<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='../../ld2webpage.xsl'?>
<LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>
  <imported>Y</imported>
  <pages>7</pages>
  <submitURL>
  </submitURL>
  <organizationName>Greater New York Hospital Association</organizationName>
  <prefix>
  </prefix>
  <firstName>
  </firstName>
  <lastName>
  </lastName>
  <registrantDifferentAddress>N</registrantDifferentAddress>
  <address1>555 WEST 57TH STREET</address1>
  <address2>
  </address2>
  <city>NEW YORK</city>
  <state>NY</state>
  <zip>10019</zip>
  <zipext>
  </zipext>
  <country>USA</country>
  <principal_city>
  </principal_city>
  <principal_state>
  </principal_state>
  <principal_zip>
  </principal_zip>
  <principal_zipext>
  </principal_zipext>
  <principal_country>
  </principal_country>
  <contactIntlPhone>
  </contactIntlPhone>
  <selfSelect>Y</selfSelect>
  <clientName>Greater New York Hospital Association</clientName>
  <clientGovtEntity>N</clientGovtEntity>
  <senateID>16830-12</senateID>
  <houseID>324950000</houseID>
  <reportYear>2016</reportYear>
  <reportType>Q1</reportType>
  <terminationDate>
  </terminationDate>
  <noLobbying>
  </noLobbying>
  <income>
  </income>
  <expenses>320000.00</expenses>
  <expensesMethod>A</expensesMethod>
  <printedName>David Rich</printedName>
  <signedDate>4/19/2016 10:12:43 AM</signedDate>
  <alis>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>HCR</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Organ donation issues, including the liver transplant allocation system and in support of new proposed UNOS system; support Ebola funding for hospital preparedness and treatment activities, including NY delegation letter to HHS and calls to HHS and meetings with Administration officials; Ebola funding language including in the Consolidated Appropriations Act of 2016 (Omnibus legislation/Senate amendment to H.R. 2029) - support; support for Zika supplemental funding; The Living Donor Protection Act of 2016 (H.R.4616/S.2584) - support; The Standard Merger and Acquisition Reviews Through Equal Rules Act (H.R. 2745) - support; proposed changes to regulation of Laboratory Developed Tests (FDA-2011-D-0360-Draft Guidance for Industry, Food and Drug Administration Staff and Clinical Laboratories: Framework for Regulatory Oversight of Laboratory Developed Tests) - oppose.</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Health &amp; Human Services - Dept of (HHS), Health Resources &amp; Services Administration (HRSA), Centers For Disease Control &amp; Prevention (CDC), Centers For Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS), Office of Management &amp; Budget (OMB), White House Office</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kenneth</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Raske</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>David</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Rich</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jonathan</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Cooper</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Susan</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Waltman</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Elisabeth</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Wynn</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Bruce</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Vladeck</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>MMM</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Graduate Medical Education (GME) issues (including Resident Physician Shortage Reduction Act (H.R.2124/S.1148) - support); provided comments to Congress in response to Energy and Commerce Committee request for input on GME; amendments to the Medicare hospital re-admissions penalty program methodology (providing SES adjustments, fixing the formula flaw), H.R.1343/S.688 - support; proposals to amend the 2 midnight policy - support; hospital issues included in President Obama's FY 16 budget - oppose; hospital issues included in H.R.2, the Medicare Access and CHIP Re-authorization Act of 2015 - support; legislation to create a comprehensive Medicare home infusion benefit (H.R.605/S.275) - support; Strengthening Medicare Advantage through Innovation and Transparency for Seniors (H.R.2570) - oppose; Medicare Inpatient Prospective Payment System FY 2016 proposed rule (CMS 1632-P) - detailed comment letter; legislation to improve the recovery audit contractor program (H.R.2156); Audit and Appeal Fairness, Integrity and Reforms in Medicare Act (AFIRM) - provided comments to the Senate Finance Committee; Ensuring Seniors Access to Local Pharmacies Act of 2015 (H.R.793/S.1190) - support; Pharmacy and Medically Underserved Areas Enhancement Act (H.R.592/S.314) - support; MAC Transparency Act (H.R.244) - support; Medication Therapy Management Act (S.776) - support; CMS-4159-F2 - comments on daily dispensing fees; Medicare Independence at Home Medical Practice Demonstration Improvement Act of 2015 (P.L.114-39) - support; provided comments on the proposed Medicare outpatient prospective payment system rule (CMS-1633-P); Medicare IME Pool Act of 2015 (H.R.3292) - oppose; Strengthening DSH and Medicare through Subsidy Recapture and Payment Reform Act (H.R.3288) - oppose; Medicare Crosswalk Hospital Code Development Act (H.R. 3291) - oppose; sign-on letter to CMS urging it to reconsider negative update for CY 2016 (CMS-1633-P) - support; proposed Medicare and Medicaid cuts as offsets to pay for budget increases, raising the debt ceiling, etc. - oppose; site neutral hospital outpatient cuts and other hospital related provisions included in the Bipartisan Budget Act of 2015 (H.R. 1314) - oppose; legislative proposals and Congressional letters to amend the Bipartisan Budget Acts site neutral hospital outpatient payment cut to grandfather sites under development as well as other legislative changes (support) - advocated for their inclusion in the Consolidated Appropriations Act of 2016 (Omnibus legislation/Senate amendment to H.R. 2029); provided comments to Congress regarding provisions in the Mental Health Reform Act of 2015 (S. 1945), that would reform how health care information for substance abuse patients is shared; met with HHS officials on Medicare and Medicaid issues of importance to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and Puerto Rican health care providers; submitted comments on Medicare and Medicaid Programs: Reform of Requirements for Long-Term Care Facilities (CMS-3260-P); Stopping Medication Abuse and Protecting Seniors Act of 2015 (S.1913) - support (with some concerns about pharmacy lock-in policy); hospital issues included in House FY 17 budget - oppose; hosptial issues included in President Obama's FY 17 budget proposal - oppose; provided comments in response to Energy and Commerce Committee request for input on hospital site-neutral issues; Medicaid provisions included in the Common Sense Savings Act of 2016 (H.R.4725) - oppose; provided comments to CMS and Congress regarding the Hospital Compare Star Ratings for hospitals - support for delay and fixing measures; The Fair Medicare Hospital Payments Act of 2016 (H.R. 4428) - oppose.</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, White House Office, Health &amp; Human Services - Dept of (HHS), Centers For Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kenneth</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Raske</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>David</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Rich</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jonathan</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Cooper</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Karen</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Heller</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Elisabeth</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Wynn</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Timothy</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Johnson</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kathleen</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Shure</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Aisling</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Zaccarelli</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Lee</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Perlman</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Laura</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Alfredo</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Shara</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Siegel</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>PHA</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Reducing the costs of pharmaceuticals, medical devices, and supplies for consumers and health care providers, including implementation of the Drug Quality and Security Act (P.L.113-54) and P.L.112-144; support medical device pricing transparency and prohibition on medical device price "gag clauses"; preserving access to group purchasing organizations (GPOs) and protecting the GPO safe harbor; educating policymakers on hospital drug shortages and significant drug price increases and support draft reform legislation; pharmaceutical labeling of generic drugs (FDA-2013-N-0500); legislation to create a comprehensive Medicare home infusion benefit (H.R.605/S.275) - support; support reforming the durable medical equipment competitive bidding program; supporting "any willing pharmacy" legislation; promoting access to biosimilars (labeling/interchangeability); 21st Century Cures Act (H.R.6) - general support for overall bill, support final pharmacy lock-in policy, oppose PPSA weakening of existing requirements, oppose Section 4004 treatment of infusion drugs furnished through durable medical equipment; Ensuring Seniors Access to Local Pharmacies Act (H.R.793/S.1190) - support; Pharmacy and Medically Underserved Areas Enhancement Act (H.R.592/S.314) - support; MAC Transparency Act (H.R.244) - support; Medication Therapy Management Empowerment Act (S.776) - support; Strengthening Medicare Advantage Through Innovation and Transparency for Seniors - oppose; FDA-2014-D-1524-0002 - comments, Administration and Capitol Hill meetings on draft guidance on repackaging of certain human drug products by pharmacies and outsourcing facilities; FDA-2014-N-1459 - comments and Capitol Hill meetings on draft MOU addressing certain distributions of compounded human drug products between states and the FDA; proposed changes to the 340B prescription drug program - oppose; 21st Century Cures Act (H.R.6) - support; proposed amendments to 340b program (not ultimately included in H.R.6) - oppose; provide comments on proposed 340b omnibus guidance (RIN 0906 AB08); Stopping Medication Abuse and Protecting Seniors Act of 2015 (S.1913)- support  (with some concerns about pharmacy lock-in policy); submitted comments on Management Standards for Hazardous Waste Pharmaceuticals (EPA-HQ-RCRA-2007-0932); meeting with DEA on Controlled Substances Act (21 USC 802); proposed changes to regulation of Laboratory Developed Tests (FDA-2011-D-0360-Draft Guidance for Industry, Food and Drug Administration Staff and Clinical Laboratories: Framework for Regulatory Oversight of Laboratory Developed Tests) - oppose.</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Centers For Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS), Food &amp; Drug Administration (FDA), Health &amp; Human Services - Dept of (HHS), Health Resources &amp; Services Administration (HRSA), Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA), Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kenneth</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Raske</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Lee</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Perlman</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Aisling</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Zaccarelli</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>David</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Rich</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jonathan</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Cooper</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Shara</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Siegel</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>Y</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>BUD</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>House and Senate Budget Resolutions, provisions relating to Medicare reductions - oppose (H.Con.Res. 27, S.Con.Res.11)</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kenneth</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Raske</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>David</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Rich</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jonathan</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Cooper</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>LBR</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>The Standard Merger and Acquisition Act of 2016 (H.R.4616/S.2584) - support.</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jonathan</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Cooper</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
  </alis>
  <updates>
    <clientAddress>
    </clientAddress>
    <clientCity>
    </clientCity>
    <clientState>
    </clientState>
    <clientZip>
    </clientZip>
    <clientZipext>
    </clientZipext>
    <clientCountry>
    </clientCountry>
    <prinClientCity>
    </prinClientCity>
    <prinClientState>
    </prinClientState>
    <prinClientZip>
    </prinClientZip>
    <prinClientZipext>
    </prinClientZipext>
    <prinClientCountry>
    </prinClientCountry>
    <generalDescription>
    </generalDescription>
    <inactive_lobbyists>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
    </inactive_lobbyists>
    <inactive_ALIs>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
    </inactive_ALIs>
    <affiliatedUrl>www.gnyhaventures.com</affiliatedUrl>
    <affiliatedOrgs>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>GNYHA Ventures, Inc.</affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>555 W. 57th St.</affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>New York</affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>NY</affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>10019</affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>USA</affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>GNYHA Services, Inc.</affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>555 W. 57th St.</affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>New York</affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>NY</affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>10019</affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>USA</affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>Innovatix, LLC</affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>555 W. 57th St.</affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>New York</affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>NY</affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>10019</affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>USA</affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
    </affiliatedOrgs>
    <inactiveOrgs>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
    </inactiveOrgs>
    <foreignEntities>
      <foreignEntity>
        <name>
        </name>
        <address>
        </address>
        <city>
        </city>
        <state>
        </state>
        <country>
        </country>
        <prinCity>
        </prinCity>
        <prinState>
        </prinState>
        <prinCountry>
        </prinCountry>
        <contribution>
        </contribution>
        <ownership_Percentage>
        </ownership_Percentage>
      </foreignEntity>
    </foreignEntities>
    <inactive_ForeignEntities>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
    </inactive_ForeignEntities>
  </updates>
</LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>