<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='../../ld2webpage.xsl'?>
<LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>
  <imported>Y</imported>
  <pages>3</pages>
  <submitURL>
  </submitURL>
  <organizationName>Common Cause</organizationName>
  <prefix>
  </prefix>
  <firstName>
  </firstName>
  <lastName>
  </lastName>
  <registrantDifferentAddress>Y</registrantDifferentAddress>
  <address1>805 15TH STREET NW</address1>
  <address2>Suite 800</address2>
  <city>WASHINGTON</city>
  <state>DC</state>
  <zip>20005</zip>
  <zipext>
  </zipext>
  <country>USA</country>
  <principal_city>
  </principal_city>
  <principal_state>
  </principal_state>
  <principal_zip>
  </principal_zip>
  <principal_zipext>
  </principal_zipext>
  <principal_country>
  </principal_country>
  <contactIntlPhone>
  </contactIntlPhone>
  <selfSelect>Y</selfSelect>
  <clientName>Common Cause</clientName>
  <clientGovtEntity>N</clientGovtEntity>
  <senateID>10150-12</senateID>
  <houseID>318820000</houseID>
  <reportYear>2016</reportYear>
  <reportType>Q1</reportType>
  <terminationDate>
  </terminationDate>
  <noLobbying>
  </noLobbying>
  <income>
  </income>
  <expenses>30000.00</expenses>
  <expensesMethod>A</expensesMethod>
  <printedName>Stephen Spaulding</printedName>
  <signedDate>4/19/2016 8:27:30 PM</signedDate>
  <alis>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>GOV</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Supported the Government By the People Act (H.R. 20), providing for a voluntary system of financing congressional elections using a mix of small private donations and federal funds and establishing a refundable tax credit to encourage grassroots campaign donations. Supported the Empowering Citizens Act (H.R. 424), providing a repair of the presidential public financing system, creating a similar public financing system for congressional races, strengthening rules prohibiting coordinated spending by outside groups and ending individual candidate-specific independent-expenditure only committees (individual candidate 'Super PACs'). Supported the Fair Elections Now Act (S. 1538) to establish a voluntary system of public financing for Senate elections. Supported the Democracy for All proposed constitutional amendment (S.J. Res 5, H.J. Res. 22) that would permit Congress and the states to set reasonable limits on the raising and spending of money to influence elections. Supported the DISCLOSE Act (H.R. 430, S. 229) to require disclosure of funds used by corporations, labor organizations, Super PACs and other entities influencing elections with independent expenditures and electioneering communications. Supported the Redistricting Reform Act of 2015 (H.R. 2173) to require states to establish independent, multi-party citizen redistricting commissions for purposes of drawing district lines. Supported the Fairness and Independence in Redistricting (FAIR) Act (S. 2483) to require independent redistricting commissions to draw district lines. Supported the EMPOWER Act (H.R. 2143, S. 1176) to establish a small donor, public matching funds system for presidential candidates to use in presidential primary and general election races. Supported the Stop Super PAC-Candidate Coordination Act (H.R. 425, S. 1838) to strengthen coordination rules between federal candidates and independent-expenditure only committees and prevent circumvention of anti-corruption contribution limits. Urged the President of the United States to sign an executive order requiring government contractors to disclose their political spending. Opposed efforts to use the budget process to insert campaign finance riders that would lift limits on spending by political parties coordinated with candidates. Opposed riders in the budget process to prohibit the Securities &amp; Exchange Commission from issuing rules requiring public companies to disclose political spending to shareholders. Opposed riders in the budget process to prohibit the Internal Revenue Service and Treasury Department from issuing new rules defining candidate-related political activity for social welfare organizations and other nonprofit organizations engaged in more than an insubstantial amount of candidate-related political activity. Opposed policy riders in the appropriations process in general. Supported the REGISTER Act (S. 1970) to establish a system for automatic voter registration in federal elections. Supported the Voting Rights Advancement Act (H.R. 2867, S. 1659), to restore the protections of the Voting Rights Act against racial discrimination in voting and to establish a new preclearance formula. Supported the Shareholder Protection Act (H.R. 446, S. 214) to require shareholder approval of corporate political expenditures. Supported the Keeping Our Campaigns Honest Act (H.R. 2125) to require the Federal Communications Commission to update its sponsorship identification rules to require disclosure of donors to political campaign broadcast advertisements. Supported the FEC Reform Act (H.R. 2931) to restructure the Federal Elections Commission and establish stronger enforcement powers of campaign finance laws. Supported the Stop Foreign Donations Affecting Our Elections Act (H.R. 4177) to require political contributions made by credit cards are from United States citizens. Supported a Senate floor amendment to require companies with revenue of $1 million or more derived from fossil fuel activities to disclose their spending on electioneering ads, if the total exceeds $10,000 yearly. Urged the Election Assistance Commission to withdraw letters to the states of Kansas, Georgia and Alabama authorizing burdensome and duplicative "proof of citizenship" requirements to the federal mail-in voter registration form. Urged the United States Senate to hold a hearing and an up-or-down floor vote for the nomination of Judge Merrick Garland to the United States Supreme Court. Supported the Federal Election Administration Act (S.2611) to develop a new federal campaign finance law enforcement agency that would have five members instead of six at the current Federal Election Commission. Supported the Political Intelligence Transparency Act of 2016 (S. 2738, H.R. 4809) to require political intelligence consultants to register under the Lobbying Disclosure Act and disclose their clients, income and activities. Supported the Senate Campaign Disclosure Parity Act (S. 366) to require Senate candidates to file their campaign finance disclosure reports electronically.  Supported the Democracy Restoration Act (H.R. 1459, S. 772) to restore voting rights in federal elections for people who are out of prison and living in their communities. Supported the Voter Registration Modernization Act (S. 1088) to require online voter registration. Supported the Same Day Registration Act (S. 1139) to require same-day voter registration in federal elections. Supported the Supreme Court Ethics Act (H.R. 1943, S. 1072) to require the Supreme Court to establish a transparent Code of Conduct governing ethics rules at the Supreme Court. Supported the Voter Empowerment Act (H.R. 12) to modernize, update and streamline our federal elections, including the registration process and combating deceptive practices. Supported the Automatic Voter Registration Act (H.R. 2694) to establish a system for states for automatic voter registration at state motor vehicle authority offices.</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, White House Office, Election Assistance Commission (EAC)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Aaron </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Scherb</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Stephen </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Spaulding</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
  </alis>
  <updates>
    <clientAddress>
    </clientAddress>
    <clientCity>
    </clientCity>
    <clientState>
    </clientState>
    <clientZip>
    </clientZip>
    <clientZipext>
    </clientZipext>
    <clientCountry>
    </clientCountry>
    <prinClientCity>
    </prinClientCity>
    <prinClientState>
    </prinClientState>
    <prinClientZip>
    </prinClientZip>
    <prinClientZipext>
    </prinClientZipext>
    <prinClientCountry>
    </prinClientCountry>
    <generalDescription>
    </generalDescription>
    <inactive_lobbyists>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
    </inactive_lobbyists>
    <inactive_ALIs>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
    </inactive_ALIs>
    <affiliatedUrl>
    </affiliatedUrl>
    <affiliatedOrgs>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
    </affiliatedOrgs>
    <inactiveOrgs>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
    </inactiveOrgs>
    <foreignEntities>
      <foreignEntity>
        <name>
        </name>
        <address>
        </address>
        <city>
        </city>
        <state>
        </state>
        <country>
        </country>
        <prinCity>
        </prinCity>
        <prinState>
        </prinState>
        <prinCountry>
        </prinCountry>
        <contribution>
        </contribution>
        <ownership_Percentage>
        </ownership_Percentage>
      </foreignEntity>
    </foreignEntities>
    <inactive_ForeignEntities>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
    </inactive_ForeignEntities>
  </updates>
</LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>