<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='../../ld2webpage.xsl'?>
<LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>
  <imported>N</imported>
  <pages>4</pages>
  <submitURL>
  </submitURL>
  <organizationName>Fighting Apartheid Confrontation Transformation Systems, Inc.</organizationName>
  <prefix>
  </prefix>
  <firstName>
  </firstName>
  <lastName>
  </lastName>
  <registrantDifferentAddress>N</registrantDifferentAddress>
  <address1>209 UNDERWOOD ST., NW</address1>
  <address2>
  </address2>
  <city>WASHINGTON</city>
  <state>DC</state>
  <zip>20012</zip>
  <zipext>
  </zipext>
  <country>USA</country>
  <principal_city>
  </principal_city>
  <principal_state>
  </principal_state>
  <principal_zip>
  </principal_zip>
  <principal_zipext>
  </principal_zipext>
  <principal_country>
  </principal_country>
  <contactIntlPhone>
  </contactIntlPhone>
  <selfSelect>Y</selfSelect>
  <clientName>Fighting Apartheid Confrontation Transformation Systems, Inc.</clientName>
  <clientGovtEntity>N</clientGovtEntity>
  <senateID>14495-12</senateID>
  <houseID>335300000</houseID>
  <reportYear>2016</reportYear>
  <reportType>Q1</reportType>
  <terminationDate>
  </terminationDate>
  <noLobbying>
  </noLobbying>
  <income>
  </income>
  <expenses>
  </expenses>
  <expensesMethod>A</expensesMethod>
  <printedName>Harold C. Hunter, Jr.</printedName>
  <signedDate>4/6/2016 9:01:07 PM</signedDate>
  <alis>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>CAW</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Congressman John Conyers, 31 Members of Congress Introduce the Emergency Financial Manager Reform Act of 2016

https://conyers.house.gov/media-center/press-releases/congressman-john-conyers-31-members-congress-introduce-emergency

FIGHTING APARTHEID CONFRONTATION TRANSFORMATION SYSTEMS, (FACTS INC. )   IS A NON-PROFIT ORGANIZATION GEARED TOWARDS UPLIFTING THE GRASSROOTS OF RACISM IN WASHINGTON, D.C.  AND AROUND THE WORLD.  
  PROUDLY  PRESENTS  

LAST LINE  OF   DEFENSE

 
RANKING  MEMBER,   ELIJAH CUMMINGS APPEARED AT A  GOVERNMENT OVERSIGHT &amp;  GOVERNMENT REFORM  COMMITTEE,  LOCATED AT THE  RAYBURN OFFICE BUILDING,   ELIJAH  CUMMINGS (D), REPRESENTATIVE OF  MARYLAND  STATED  THAT  THIS  IS,   "THE  LAST  LINE  OF  DEFENSE,"  IN TERMS  OF   INTENTIONAL  POISON  WATER  FROM  LEAD.  The  Governor of Michigan, Rick Snyder was  issued a supena not withstanding a Karegnondi  water authority   (7 - 1) City Council vote,  March  25, 2013.   The supena was issued effective  February 1, 2016  for attendance at the next hearing.
http://www.eclectablog.com/2016/01/video-flint-city-council-voted-on-joining-karegnondi-water-authority-not-to-use-the-flint-river-for-all-their-water.html
 Lets  get  the  FACTS.   FACTS,  INC.   IS   DEVELOPING  A TEN PART SERIES: 

I.    INQUIRY
II.  INVESTIGATION
III.     FACT FINDING
IV.     IDENTIFY PROBLEM
V.   ASSESS  PROBLEM  
VI.   INDEPENDENT REVIEW 
VII.   POSSSIBLE SOLUTIONS
VIII.  POSSIBLE FINANCE
IX.   REFERENCE (S) / APPENDIX
X. POLICY

THAT WILL IDENTIFY AND EXPOSE THE DEQ, EPA OFFICIALS, WITNESSES, AGENCIES, STATE STATUTES.   THE HONORABLE ELIJAH CUMMINGS   STATED   THAT  THE  STATE  OFFICIALS  HAVE  FAILED  US.   "WE  DO NOT HAVE THE RIGHT TO KEEP SILENT."    "GOVERNEMENT   BROKE  IT;   GOVERNMENT  MUST  FIX IT."    

THE   OFFICIAL  RECORD  IS  THAT THE  ULTIMATE  GOAL  REPRESENT  SUPERBOWL EFFECT  OF   CHILDREN BE SAVED.   ALL  CHILDREN ARE AFFECTED.   THE  LEAD  AND COPPER  RULES   DO NOT APPLY IN THIS  CASE.  WE  MUST   RESPECT  OUR GOVERNMENT &amp; OVERSIGHT  REFORM.   THE  CULPABILITY  IS A SENTIMENT.   JASON CHAFFETZ (R), UTAH CHAIRED  A POWERFUL HEARING THAT  WILL GO DOWN IN HISTORY --   JUST  AS  THE HONORABLE ELEANOR HOLMES NORTON  (D) NARRATED THE FACT THAT THE NATION'S CAPITOL WAS IN THE SAME NIGHTMARE AND FOUND FAULT WITH OVERHAULING THE MAJOR PIPELINES AS OPPOSED TO THE INITIAL RESIDENTIAL PIPES.   
 


 

Daniel Kildee (D)   5th  District   orchestrated that we  get the  FACTS.  There initially was a Fifty (50) million dollar General Fund  and yet is eliminated  for an emergency  that made the  decision to switch an obstruction to  justice  (Flint's unelected, statel-appointed switched flint's water without permission or approval, rather switch to the Flint   dirty River, which corroded the pipes and contaminated people's leaded water.   The people in Flint, Michigan had to drink this water for approximately two years.)  but  to whose demise?    Congressman  Kildee  stated  that  we  must  get  the  facts of the optimized control.    Congressman Kildee is the good guy in this case by voicing loud and clear that we get the FACTS.   What, where, why, who, and what was the time frame?   Congressman Kildee request   Governor Synder write a check  tomorrow  of  60 million dollars to replace the pipes in the city of Flint, Michigan and make it right for the citizens of Flint.   

The question remains  who knew  what?   When did  he or she  know  or should have known? 

The reminest of this history outcry  is  life over death.  Money over merit.  Supremacy over failure over government. 
 
 

Safe Drinking Water  Act  is   very  important  issue.   Performances   and  emergencies   are  necessary for  drinking  water.  President   Obama  declaration of of emergency in January  2016  will enhance  the   lead and copper rule.   The   advisory  council  is  merited  as  such whereas the governmental officials  have  not weighed  in compliance  of the standards   of the  lead  and  copper rule.   Kerosion treatment   was not  implemented  or   aggregated.   The goal is to protect the publicl.   The  outcry is  a sentiment that must be met.   Keith Creagh, Interim Director of Michigan Department of Environmental Quality stated that we need accountability.   Marc Edwards, Flint Water  Interagency Coordinating Commitee, have testified beyond measure that no one is listening  of  submitting data to his office.   The negligence have obstructed justice in his eyes.    Mr. Edwards  of  Virginia Technology  fulfilled the roller coaster ride to not allow agencies get away with a crime that have harmed and injured people in Flint, Michigan.   

The  citizens  of Flint  deserve  better.   In this inquiring, FACTS, INC.  will honor whistle blower Leann Walter and other citizens in Flint., Michigan.  Her  imminent harm to children as a result from the contaminated water deserve respect.  2001 - 2016.    EPA   have a responsibility in  Washington, D.C.  and  around the world.   Mission Statement:  FACTS, INC.   is a non-profit organization that is geared towards uplifting the grassroots of racism in Washington, D.C.  &amp;  around  the world.  
 

Brenda  Lawrence (D),  14th  District  Detroit, Farmington Hills, Southfield   want  answers.   The increased blood levels aspire and inspire answers.   Silence  is  death  on the watch of the Honorable Congresswoman Lawrence.  She, if no one else will get to the bottom of this situation because of her desire to represent her constituents in the great state of Michigan.     
 

Justin  Amash  asked the million dollar question;   why  and were  the  phosphates  added into the water to avoid the kerosion?   Well,  well, well, this is just  like fish  in an aquarium   with  no filter (s).   Chemicals   with no substance.   Coding  with  no balance.  PH  is   needed for  any  human  being.  Wait  a minute,   as   Congressman   Cummings  stated  this  is  not  a third  world  country.    Lets   get   the facts!

 
The Honorable Delegate Eleanor H. Norton (D)   Non-voting member in congress.    Delegate Norton stated that many abortions and  miscarriages espoused in the District of Columbia when we had the epidemic of deficient pipes and lead started at the core of the utility dispense.   In reality,  the  Nation's  Capitol  have  suffered this crissis  in the  past.  Pre-flushing is an epidemic.   Congresswoman Norton gave an astonishing knock out punch of pre-flushing is needed and must be a key  ingredient because regular pipes will be  removed from his / her home.  Residential neglect  is a norm.   People don't want to remove themselves from Flint or sell his or her homes with bad pipes.  Substance pipes or no substance pipes, that is the question?   Lets get the facts!   "December 9th is an void and null." The water was not safe then and remains to be safe now.    In privy,   the timeline remains to be seen.  
 

The  Honorable John Mica,  Republican from Florida, 7th District, Deltona Sanford, Winter Park   took some swipes at lets be honest, we  have problems all over the country.   His  key visible glass of water  display honesty and purity yet make mention of the Honorable Marion S Barry, as digesting Crack and how his contingent took over the District with the control board.   I personally remember a time in the District of Columbia in my puberty years.   I have acne and my dermatalogist  discovered that I suffered bad acne because of the tap water that I was drinking.  
 

The Honorable Gerald Connolly, (D) Virginia,  Fairfax Prince William, demands that Governor appear at the next hearing or else he should go to jail,    Congressman Connolly remained as a game breaker  stated  that Governor  Synder should be held  accountable and if he remains  quiet.    Where  is  the  culpability?  Death  is  the  answer,  I  don't   think  so.  DEQ  is  a  warning sign.   The  problems  stay at  risk.  The  kerosion control   safeguard -- life  over limb here.   
 

Paul Gosar  (R) Arizona, Lake Avasu  is the goat  (Greatest of all time) here. When did you know?  Legal questions, logic games, levy and luxury.   Chain of command.   Priority  is a scaling of dentistry  here.   Our  healty make me and other readers in this historic hearing obstruct  right over wrong, ingenius over camps.   Be  accountable!   Immediately.   The   Gosar theory is a make or brake rule.   Leading questions  allow the goat to be privy of the facts.   Standards, principles, and ethics are merited here. 
 

The enactment of laws  harness  the  ranking  member  of the Government, Oversight  committee.   Why would Governor   Synder
document   the  truth, the hold truth and nothing but the truth," as stated by  Congressman Cummings.    Why  should people in 
the Flint, Michigan pay for their  water bills when the water is contaminated.   The moral  were  reguarded  as being  neglected  by  Americans.   Busloads  of  hundreds  from Flint, Michigan harped the reaction of clean, healthy  water.  The Honoralble  Al Sharpton spearheaded through the National Action Network, support of displined soldiers, warriors.  The  President, Nia 2x  of the Greater D.C. Chapter of the National Action Network (ushered in hundred of Flint Michigan residents.)   Some of the residents had baby bottles of brown contaminated water.   

The   General Motors company moved their motor plant from the state of Michigan.     GM spokesman Tom Wickham said in an email to The Flint Journal-MLive that the company plans to wait until completion of the Karegnondi Water Authority pipeline in 2016 before returning Flint Engine Operations to city water.
http://www.mlive.com/news/flint/index.ssf/2015/10/gm.html

 

Mark Meadows, (R)  North Carolina, 11th District, Waynesville, Morgan, Henderson Water Quality is in bed with inspector general, why?   Stop blaming people echoed Mr. Meadows instead  look at  documents websitite  CTS.   Regulations  occur  enforce  Beauvis.  Mr.  Meadows  demanded a committment that Mr  Beauvis  report  
 

Matt Cartwright, (D)   Pennsylvania, 17th District   Scranton, Pottsville, Lehighton, echoed that the (7-1) vote  to uphold what Congressman Kildee.   Jerry Ambrose, Governor Synder are hiding as stated by Congressman  Cartwright.   "Collected decision" not to include the river water.  Where  is  accountability, DEQ?   Personal  knowledge  is  evident of the facts   that  Congressman  Cartwright  possess.   Congratulations.    Bingo;  thats  the facts  here   where  are  the  real witnesses   who know  the  real truth?  
 

The  lead  and copper  rule  as   stated  should be issued every   6  years.  Whereas in 2007, Congressman  Jody Hice, (R) Georgia Athens, Washington,  refuted Mr.  Beauvais  acknowledged  when  will  it  be  ready will be  in  2017.  Committment of  lead and copper rule.   Mr.  Deltorro  high  levels   is a crime  and be  silenced.  Well the truth  is  that  Congresman  Hice has a message of  discovery that EPA  dropped the ball in Flint., Michigan because we  know   EPA  find  fault  as   
 

Robin Kelly,  (D)   Ilinois, 2nd  District  Matterson Chicago  stated   a  good  fact that we  should stop  playing with the lives of our children.   I appauld her wisdom to ascertain, good fact finding information through accurated documentation.   

These  statements of facts  ensure our public health  as stated  by   Mayor Lawrence that  EPA  has a limited order to test  the water in Michigan.  We  need  to apply the law to facts.  Mayor Lawrence wants the facts.
 

Protection of fundamental health.   Checkmate --   not  updated  since   25  twenty five  years  as  a lead and copper  rule.  EPA   hope to finalize  in 2018.   Well, well well,  here we  have an irony  of  drama  for  General Motors.  Congressman Steve  Russell ,  (R) Oklahoma bring out the fact that commingly funds, utilities, etc.   burn the fact the people lose out the tax payer dollars.  Where are the facts?   Congressman Russell wants a mandate.  So does the citizens of the United States of America.   Joel Beauvis (EPA), Administration is caught with his pants down of get the rules finalized stated by Congressman Russell.   

A crime of ethic proportions state resignation, prosecution and make it right.   Replace the lead pipes.   Congress  Ted Lieu,  (D), California, 33RD District, Beverly Hills, Santa Monica, Manhattan Beach,  admitted into evidence is what we need.  Safe Drinking Water Act.  is  a dynamite eco friendly as a smoking gun.   I appreciate the honest sentiment of  Congressman Lieu.  The correctness of his line of questioning states that he did his homework of documenting the facts.   
 

Rep  Mick  Mulvaney (R), South Carolina Rock Hill, Camden,   highlighted an excellent timeline that needs to ascertain who knows what; and under what time line.   The EPA parameter monitors lead and copper at certain lenghtly timelines.   
 

Rep Bonnie Watson Coleman  (D) New  Jersey   12th  District  Trenton, Princton, Plainfield ,  Watsy Coleman hit a homerun and checkmate when she calulated as a real quality responsibilty,  March  23, 2015  that adopted  a  resolution  to  return  honest  water towards citizens.    Flint, Michigan  authorities  held  the ball for a shoe string tackle   Congreswoman made a checkmate in that stop  using Ambose as  Carugandy  water authority  as the   scapegoat. 
 
In this melodrama make one to feel presence of bipartisan to correct the wrongs, and ills of our society.  The levels  of lead water don't need to be man-made to succumb the fine lakes, rivers, and streams in the great state of Michigan water.   Kerosion control is a minted incident.   How are we going to fix it?   What can we do to make this right?   How do we betray the public trust.   Ethical behavior  of lead based levels, data, characterization.   Mr. Waling is a scapegoat,  Susan Hedman is a scapegoat.   Who  is to to blame  stated  Mr.  Mar  Edwards,   Virginia Technology.   
 

Rep  Gary Palmer, (R) Alabama 6th District,   Clanton, Columbiana,  Gardendale  stated that children are affected by the water.  All children.   Congressman Palmer highlighted state revelations that toxic material (groundwater, lead, etc.)  Groundwater is key here in that permenant damage for impact and malfeasent of justice.   The blame of Flint, Michigan drinking water contamination pertainss as a relic here.    

"Injustice anywhere is a threat to justice everywhere."   ---  DR.  MLK

Del  Stacey  Plaskett  (D) Virgin Islands;  St Thomas, St. Croix, St. John  hit the nail on the head.   Economic  eviromental hazard to challengened communities  is the norm.  The congress is the same;  the old boy network is here.  Ms. Plasket have proven that  Ben Gazi fiasco has spent  money  yet  do not allow  for water.   Michigan State  government  allow  racism  at  and all time high.   100  million dollar.   Is Mr. Early guilty or innocent?    Detroit  millions of dollars;  surpassed Mr. Early's gross negligence by receiving  money   and  a  reward  after  of  221  additional funds.   The judgement is a hire fire here  that is based on the taxpayers dollars benefit.  Sigh.   

Aided and abetting to make sure that water is safe whereas   Chair  Jason Chaffetz,   (R) Utah,  Ovsersight &amp; Government Reform Committe Chair  proved beyond a shadow of a doubt that the EPA, DEQ, HAVE FAILED IN WARNING THE CITIZENS OF FLINT, MICHIGAN AND THAT THE WATER IS UNSAFE.  TELL THE PUBLIC,  PETITION THE CONGRESS, ALERT THE PRESIDENT AGAIN, AND CONFIRM THE JUDICIAL BODY.   WE ARE WITNESSING 
CRIMINAL ACT(S)   GET THE FACTS.   WE  NEED  THE  FACTS.   WE  NEED   WHY  WE  CAN ACCESS THE DATA.  FOYER REQUEST  DON'T  TAKE  9  YEARS.  
 

Poison  without exception must be met in this Greek tragedy.     Rep   William  Lacy  Clay   D   Missouri   1st  District, St. Louis,  Ferguson  Evironmental racism are exposed in recreational areas in his District of St. Louis.  Mr.  Clay  simply emphatized  Ms. Walters children affects and defects.   How do we repair the damage of gross negligence in protecting his / her citizens in the great state of Michigan.   The fight is on for Nitwacc   Leeanne   Walters   Flint, Michigan Resident  because  of lead posining.  Do the right thing,   damage of lead need to be met with Dr.  Mona Monaham and other able Doctors who will tell the truth and not lie.   All in the sake of saving a few dollars  stated by   Congressman  Clay.   Where  is  the respect?
 

Rep. Glenn  Grothman  (R) Wisconsin, 6th District,  stated  boldly  who was affected and for what  reason.   Why?   What  is  a bad test?    2015   failed and made a cover up.   Wait a minute  a cover up  -   Mr. Edwards   ,  Virginia  Tech University,  was right. 
 
 It  is a cover up  ---   isn't  it?   Lead  and water is not
the answer.    
 

Rep   Michelle  Lujan  Grisham   (D) New Mexico, 1st   District  Albuquerque, Placitas   stated  protocol.  We  need  structure, public health, safety and what pediatriatians  have  identified based on the patient  data.  The  data  is  key and must overhual the facts  and move swiftly the Flint, Michigan drinking water contamination.    Appropriate decisions must make a careful  cause and effect drama to play out and play on the data.  Why is the governmental  data  not given key facts.  Epidemiologist can identify and sponsor health membership or bullship. Congresswoman wants the protocol to shape up and ship out or be a epidemiolist junky.   
 

Rep.  Cynthia  Lummis   (r)  Wyoming   At   Large   Cheyenne, sheridan, Rock  Springs   Agencies  must  listen to people and not companies at all times.   Ms.  Lummis   statement that racism is not the case here in Flint, Michigan.   
 

Shiela   House  Judiary Committee    
Rep   Shelia Jackson Lee
(D)  Texas    18th  District,  Houston   
"There is a Jim Jones in Michigan."  Get  the facts,  learn  your  history.   Learn  from   Congresswoman  Shelia Jackson Lee  Kerosion   Mrs. Lee  show the impact of what our future will hold  control treatment.   Aging lead feter lines is the basis for the last line of defense.   We need changes in Michigan and Congresswoman excelled commitment and totality to overhaul all of the pipes  (50 - 60  million dollars) 
 

Rep   Morgan  Griffith   (R)  Virginia  9th  District  Abingdon, Blacksburg,  Martinsville, Covington   address key issues of Moms ould be called in all of the counties that testing is needed.   Accountability is needed  regal in that decision making personality are a criminal act and need to go to jail.   "You have the right to remain silent..."    
Mr. Del toro is the lone ranger because he is not the last line of defense.  He was silenced because he told the truth.   Survey, ampling, congruency is a landmark case here.  Why,   the facts will prove that someone knew or should have known; the EPA, Mr. Miguel Del Toro, DEQ, THE GOVERNOR,   Mr. Early  -----   TO  BE  CONTINUED.    
 

FEMA aiding in toxic water crisis.


      
 
Dr. Mona Hanna-Attisha helped expose the dangers of the lead levels in the water in Flint, Michigan.
Nearly two years ago, the state decided to save money by switching Flint's water supply from Lake Huron (which they were paying the city of Detroit for), to the Flint River, a notorious tributary that runs through town known to locals for its filth.   ---   CNN
Contaminated Drinking Water in Flint, Michigan
Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) and Michigan state officials testified at a hearing on lead contaminated drinking water in Flint:  
All Speakers:  
Joel BeauvaisKeith CreaghMarc EdwardsH. "Morgan" Morgan GriffithSheila Jackson LeeDan KildeeLeeanne WaltersJustin AmashMatt CartwrightJason ChaffetzWilliam Lacy Clay Jr.Bonnie Watson ColemanGerry ConnollyElijah CummingsPaul GosarMichelle Lujan GrishamGlenn GrothmanJody B. HiceRobin KellyBrenda LawrenceTed LieuCynthia LummisMark MeadowsJohn MicaMick MulvaneyEleanor Holmes NortonGary PalmerStacey PlaskettSteve RussellTim Walberg.
 

FEBRUARY 3, 2016
Contaminated Drinking Water in Flint, Michigan
Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) and Michigan state officials testified at a hearing on lead contamination.
http://www.c-span.org/video/?404078-1/hearing-contaminated-drinking-water-flint-michigan
WRITTEN &amp; DEVELOPED BY   HAROLD  C  HUNTER, JR. 
ALL RIGHTS RESERVED   (c)  
 REGISTERED LOBBYIST,  CONGRESS,  114TH  USA   
www.haroldchunterjr.com   
</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Harold</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Hunter</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>Jr.</lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>President / CEO</coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>ENV</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Washington, D.C. - U.S. Congressman John Conyers (D-Mich.), Ranking Member of the House Judiciary Committee, together with 31 original cosponsors, introduced H.R. 4754, the Emergency Financial Manager Reform Act of 2016 to address unchecked decision-making powers that appointed emergency financial managers have in financially distressed cities.</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Harold</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Hunter</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>Jr.</lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>President   /   CEO</coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
  </alis>
  <updates>
    <clientAddress>
    </clientAddress>
    <clientCity>
    </clientCity>
    <clientState>
    </clientState>
    <clientZip>
    </clientZip>
    <clientZipext>
    </clientZipext>
    <clientCountry>
    </clientCountry>
    <prinClientCity>
    </prinClientCity>
    <prinClientState>
    </prinClientState>
    <prinClientZip>
    </prinClientZip>
    <prinClientZipext>
    </prinClientZipext>
    <prinClientCountry>
    </prinClientCountry>
    <generalDescription>
    </generalDescription>
    <inactive_lobbyists>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
    </inactive_lobbyists>
    <inactive_ALIs>
      <ali_Code>CAW</ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>ENV</ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
    </inactive_ALIs>
    <affiliatedUrl>
    </affiliatedUrl>
    <affiliatedOrgs>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
    </affiliatedOrgs>
    <inactiveOrgs>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
    </inactiveOrgs>
    <foreignEntities>
      <foreignEntity>
        <name>
        </name>
        <address>
        </address>
        <city>
        </city>
        <state>
        </state>
        <country>
        </country>
        <prinCity>
        </prinCity>
        <prinState>
        </prinState>
        <prinCountry>
        </prinCountry>
        <contribution>
        </contribution>
        <ownership_Percentage>
        </ownership_Percentage>
      </foreignEntity>
    </foreignEntities>
    <inactive_ForeignEntities>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
    </inactive_ForeignEntities>
  </updates>
</LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>