<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='../../ld2webpage.xsl'?>
<LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>
  <imported>Y</imported>
  <pages>16</pages>
  <submitURL>
  </submitURL>
  <organizationName>CMS ENERGY CORP</organizationName>
  <prefix>
  </prefix>
  <firstName>
  </firstName>
  <lastName>
  </lastName>
  <registrantDifferentAddress>N</registrantDifferentAddress>
  <address1>1730 Rhode Island Ave., NW, Suite 1007</address1>
  <address2>
  </address2>
  <city>WASHINGTON</city>
  <state>DC</state>
  <zip>20036</zip>
  <zipext>
  </zipext>
  <country>USA</country>
  <principal_city>
  </principal_city>
  <principal_state>
  </principal_state>
  <principal_zip>
  </principal_zip>
  <principal_zipext>
  </principal_zipext>
  <principal_country>
  </principal_country>
  <contactIntlPhone>
  </contactIntlPhone>
  <selfSelect>Y</selfSelect>
  <clientName>CMS ENERGY CORP</clientName>
  <clientGovtEntity>N</clientGovtEntity>
  <senateID>9578-12</senateID>
  <houseID>311300000</houseID>
  <reportYear>2016</reportYear>
  <reportType>Q1</reportType>
  <terminationDate>
  </terminationDate>
  <noLobbying>
  </noLobbying>
  <income>
  </income>
  <expenses>520000.00</expenses>
  <expensesMethod>A</expensesMethod>
  <printedName>David G. Mengebier </printedName>
  <signedDate>4/20/2016 11:34:39 AM</signedDate>
  <alis>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>CAW</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>H.R. 1327, Ozone Regulatory Delay and Extension of Assessment Length Act; H.R. 1388, Clean Air, Strong Economies Act regarding EPA ozone NAAQS; Discussion draft of Ratepayer Protection Act, regarding EPA proposed GHG emissions rule; Advocacy relating to "Waters of the U.S." Issue and related to proposed rule; S. 640, Ozone Regulatory Delay and Extension of Assessment Length Act; H.R. 897, Reducing Regulatory Burdens Act of 2015 (addresses an NPDES permitting issue related to herbicides and pesticides)H.R. 1327, Ozone Regulatory Delay and Extension of Assessment Length Act (Salmon); H.R. 1388, Clean Air, Strong Economies Act (regarding EPA ozone NAAQS); H.R. 1732, Regulatory Integrity Protection Act of 2015 (requires withdrawal of WOTUS rule and sets procedural steps for promulgation of a new rule); H.R. 2042, Ratepayer Protection Act (regarding EPA proposed GHG emissions rule); S. 640, Ozone Regulatory Delay and Extension of Assessment Length Act (Flake); S. 1140, Federal Water Quality Protection Act (requires withdrawal of WOTUS rule and sets parameters for development of a new rule); S. 1324, to require EPA to fulfill certain requirements before regulating standards of performance for new, modified, and reconstructed fossil fuel-fired EGUs (Capito); S. 1500, Sensible Environmental Protection Act of 2015 (addresses NPDES permitting issue related to herbicides and pesticides); S. 2072, EPA ozone early action compact program; H.J.Res. 71, disapproving EPA rule on greenhouse gas emissions from new, modified, and reconstructed electric utility generating units; H.J.Res. 72, disapproving EPA rule on carbon pollution emission guidelines for existing electric utility generating units; S.J.Res. 23, disapproving EPA rule on greenhouse gas emissions from new, modified, and reconstructed electric utility generating units; S.J.Res. 24, disapproving EPA rule on carbon pollution emission guidelines for existing electric utility generating units; S. 1140, Federal Water Quality Protection Act (requires withdrawal of WOTUS rule and sets parameters for development of a new rule); H.R. 3797, the SENSE Act regarding emissions limits for electric generating units using coal refuse; H.R. 4775, the Ozone Standards Implementation Act of 2016. </description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Amy</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Plaster</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kiran </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Crout </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>ENG</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>H.R. 161, the Natural Gas Pipeline Permitting Reform Act, to facilitate permitting of natural gas pipeline infrastructure; H.R. 1558, Resolving Environmental and Grid Reliability Conflicts Act of 2015; S. 848, Resolving Environmental and Grid Reliability Conflicts Act of 2015; General discussion hydro licensing reform; General discussion transmission permitting and siting issues; Promote &amp; protect the interests of natural gas utilities in any legislation considered by the House Energy &amp; Commerce Committee and the Senate Energy &amp; Natural Resources Committee regarding energy and climate legislation affecting natural gas utilities, including efficiency mandates; Draft legislation on energy efficiency and codes and standards; H.R. 1558, Resolving Environmental and Grid Reliability Conflicts Act of 2015 (Olson); H.R. 1980, E-Access Act; S. 535, the Energy Efficiency Improvement Act of 2015, relating to water heaters; S. 720, Energy Savings and Industrial Competitiveness Act of 2015 (promotes ESPCs and UESCs); S. 848, Resolving Environmental and Grid Reliability Conflicts Act of 2015 (McCaskill); S. 1044, E-Access Act; S. 15, Protecting states' rights to promote American energy security (Hatch);
S. 411, A bill to authorize the approval of natural gas pipelines and establish deadlines and expedite permits for certain natural gas gathering lines on Federal land and Indian land (Barrasso); S. 454, A bill to amend the Department of Energy High-End Computing; S. 485, A bill to prohibit the use of eminent domain in carrying out certain projects (Boozman); S. 523, A bill to coordinate the provision of energy retrofitting assistance to schools (Collins); S. 562, A bill to promote exploration for geothermal resources, and for other purposes (Heller); S. 600, A bill to require the Secretary of Energy to establish an energy efficiency retrofit pilot program (Klobuchar); S. 703, The Weatherization Enhancement and Local Energy Efficiency Investment and Accountability Act (Coons); S. 720, The Energy Savings and Industrial Competitiveness Act of 2015 (Portman); S. 784, A bill to direct the Secretary of Energy to establish microlabs to improve regional engagement with national laboratories (Heinrich); S. 822, A bill to expand geothermal production, and for other purposes (Wyden); S. 858, The Energy Savings Through Public-Private Partnerships Act of 2015 (Gardner); S. 869, The All-of-the-Above Federal Building Energy Conservation Act of 2015 (Hoeven); S. 878, A bill to establish a State residential building energy efficiency upgrades loan pilot program (Sanders); S. 886, The Smart Energy and Water Efficiency Act of 2015 (Udall); S. 888, The PREPARE Act (Schatz); S. 893, The EPIC Act of 2015 (Warner); S. 939; S. 1017, A bill to amend the Federal Power Act to improve the siting of interstate electric transmission facilities, and for other purposes (Heinrich);
S. 1026, The North American Alternative Fuels Act (Barasso); S. 1033, A bill to amend the Department of Energy Organization Act to replace the current requirement for a biennial energy policy plan with a Quadrennial Energy Review (Coons); S. 1037, A bill to expand the provisions for termination of mandatory purchase requirements under the PURPA of 1978 (Risch); S. 1038, A bill to clarify that no express or implied warranty is provided by reason of a disclosure relating to voluntary participation in the Energy Star program, and for other purposes (Risch); S. 1039, A bill to require certain agencies to conduct assessments of data centers and develop data center consolidation and optimization plans to achieve energy cost savings (Risch); S. 1044, A bill to enhance consumer access to electricity information and allow for the adoption of innovative products and services to help consumers manage their energy usage (Markey); S. 1046, A bill to accelerate the adoption of smart building technologies in the private sector and key Federal agencies (Cantwell); S. 1047, A bill to require the Secretary of Energy to review rulemaking proceedings of other Federal agencies for the potential to cause an adverse effect on the cost, time, or difficulty of complying with energy efficiency regulations, guidelines, or standards (Alexander); S. 1052, A bill to require a study on the impact of State and local performance benchmarking and disclosure policies for commercial and multifamily buildings, to provide for competitive awards to utilities, States, and units of local government, and for other purposes (Franken); S. 1054, A bill to improve the productivity and energy efficiency of the manufacturing sector by directing the Secretary of Energy, in coordination with the National Academies and other appropriate Federal agencies, to develop a national smart manufacturing plan and to provide assistance to small- and medium-sized manufacturers in implementing smart manufacturing programs, and for other purposes (Shaheen); S. 1063, The American Energy Efficiency Act (Franken); S. 1068, A bill to amend the Federal Power Act to protect the bulk-power system from cyber security threats (Risch/Heinrich); S. 1201, A bill to advance the integration of clean  distributed energy into electric grids (Shaheen); S. 1202, A bill to amend the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to assist States in adopting updated interconnection procedures and tariff schedules and standards for supplemental, backup, and standby power fees for projects for combined heat and power technology and waste heat to power technology, and for other purposes (Shaheen); S. 1207, A bill to direct the Secretary of Energy to establish a grant program under which the Secretary shall make grants to eligible partnerships to provide for the transformation of the electric grid by the year 2030 (Hirono); S. 1210, A bill to provide for the timely consideration of all licenses, permits, and approvals required under Federal law with respect to oil and gas production and distribution (Capito); S. 1213, A bill to amend the Public Utility Regulatory  Policies Act of 1978 and the Federal Power Act to facilitate the free market for distributed energy resources (King); S. 1215, A bill to amend the Methane Hydrate Research and Development Act of 2000 to provide for the development of methane hydrate as a commercially viable source of energy (Murkowski); S. 1216, A bill to amend the Natural Gas Act to modify a provision relating to civil penalties (Murkowski); S. 1217, A bill to establish an Interagency Rapid Response Team for Transmission, to establish an Office of Transmission Ombudsperson, and for other purposes (Murkowski); S. 1218, A bill to establish an interagency coordination committee or subcommittee with the leadership of the Department of Energy and the Department of the Interior, focused on the nexus between energy and water production, use, and efficiency, and for other purposes (Murkowski); S. 1219, A bill to amend the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to provide for the safe and reliable interconnection of distributed resources and to provide for the examination of the effects of net metering (Murkowski); S. 1220, A bill to improve the distribution of energy in the United States (Murkowski); S. 1221, A bill to amend the Federal Power Act to require periodic reports on electricity reliability and reliability impact statements for rules affecting the reliable operation of the bulk-power system (Murkowski); S. 1222, A bill to amend the Federal Power Act to provide for reports relating to electric capacity resources of transmission organizations and the amendment of certain tariffs to address the procurement of electric capacity resources, and for other purposes (Murkowski); S. 1223, A bill to amend the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to improve the loan guarantee program for innovative technologies, and for other purposes (Murkowski); S. 1224, A bill to reconcile differing Federal approaches to condensate (Murkowski); S. 1225, A bill to improve Federal land management, resource conservation, environmental protection, and use of Federal real property, by requiring the Secretary of the Interior to develop a multipurpose cadastre of Federal real property and identifying inaccurate, duplicate, and out-of-date Federal land inventories, and for other purposes (Murkowski); S. 1227, A bill to require the Secretary of Energy to develop an implementation strategy to promote the development of hybrid micro-grid systems for isolated communities (Murkowski); S. 1228, A bill to require approval for the construction, connection, operation, or maintenance of oil or natural gas pipelines or electric transmission facilities at the national boundary of the United States for the import or export of oil, natural gas, or electricity to or from Canada or Mexico, and for other purposes (Hoeven); S. 1230, A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish a program under which the Director of the Bureau of Land Management shall enter into memoranda of understanding with States providing for State oversight of oil and gas productions activities (Murkowski); S. 1232, A bill to amend the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to modify provisions relating to smart  grid modernization, and for other purposes (Wyden); S. 1236, A bill to amend the Federal Power Act to modify certain requirements relating to trial-type hearings with respect to certain license applications before the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, and for other purposes (Murkowski); S. 1237, A bill to amend the Natural Gas Act to limit the authority of the Secretary of Energy to approve certain proposals relating to export activities of liquefied natural gas terminals (King); S. 1241, A bill to provide for the modernization, security, and resiliency of the electric grid, to require the Secretary of Energy to carry out programs for research, development, demonstration, and information-sharing for cybersecurity for the energy sector, and for other purposes (Cantwell); S. 1242, A bill to amend the Natural Gas Act to require the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to consider regional constraints in natural gas supply and whether a proposed LNG terminal would benefit regional consumers of natural gas before approving or disapproving an application for the LNG terminal, and for other purposes (King); S. 1243, A bill to facilitate modernizing the electric grid, and for other purposes (Cantwell); S. 1256, A bill to require the Secretary of Energy to establish an energy storage research program, loan program, and technical assistance and grant program, and for other purposes (Franken); S. 1258, A bill to require the Secretary of Energy to establish a distributed energy loan program and technical assistance and grant program, and for other purposes (Franken); S. 1263, A bill to provide for the establishment of a Clean Energy Technology Manufacturing and Export Assistance Fund to assist United States businesses with exporting clean energy technology products and services (Hirono); S. 1264, A bill to amend the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to establish a renewable electricity standard, and for other purposes (Udall); S. 1270, A bill to amend the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to reauthorize hydroelectric production incentives and hydroelectric efficiency improvement incentives, and for other purposes (Gardner); S. 1272, A bill to direct the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study on the effects of forward capacity auctions and other capacity mechanisms (Markey); S. 1274, A bill to amend the National Energy Conservation Policy Act to reauthorize Federal agencies to enter into long-term contracts for the acquisition of energy (Hirono); S. 1275, A bill to establish a Financing Energy Efficient Manufacturing Program in the Department of Energy to provide financial assistance to promote energy efficiency and onsite renewable technologies in manufacturing and industrial facilities (Merkley); S. 1277, A bill to improve energy savings by the Department of Defense, and for other purposes (Hirono); S. 1282, A bill to amend the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to require the Secretary of Energy to consider the objective of improving the conversion, use, and storage of carbon dioxide produced from fossil fuels in carrying out research and development programs under that Act (Manchin); S. 1283, A bill to amend the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to repeal certain programs, to establish a coal technology program, and for other purposes (Manchin); S. 1285, A bill to authorize the Secretary of Energy to enter into contracts to provide certain price stabilization support relating to electric generation units that use coal-based generation technology (Heitkamp); S. 1293, A bill to establish the Department of Energy as the lead agency for coordinating all requirements under Federal law with respect to eligible clean coal and advanced coal technology generating projects, and for other purposes (Heitkamp); S. 1304, A bill to require the Secretary of Energy to establish a pilot competitive grant program for the development of a skilled energy workforce, and for other purposes (Cantwell); S. 1306, A bill to amend the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to use existing funding available to further projects that would improve energy efficiency and reduce emissions (Manchin); S. 1312, A bill to modernize Federal policies regarding the supply and distribution of energy in the United States, and for other purposes (Murkowski); S. 1338, A bill to amend the Federal Power Act to provide licensing procedures for certain types of projects (King); S. 1342, A bill to require the Secretary of Energy to conduct a study and issue a report that quantifies the energy savings benefits of operational efficiency programs and services for commercial, institutional, industrial, and governmental entities (Warren); S. 1346, A bill to require the Secretary of Energy to establish an e-prize competition pilot program to provide up to 4 financial awards to eligible entities that develop and verifiably demonstrate technology that reduces the cost of electricity or space heat in a high-cost region (Murkowski); S. 1398, A bill to extend, improve, and consolidate energy research and development programs, and for other purposes (Alexander); S. 1405, A bill to require a coordinated response to coal fuel supply emergencies that could impact electric power system adequacy or reliability (Franken); S. 1408, A bill to provide for a program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application in vehicle technologies at the Department of Energy (Peters); S. 1420, A bill to amend the Department of Energy Organization Act to provide for the collection of information on critical energy supplies, to establish a Working Group on Energy Markets, and for other purposes (Cantwell); S. 1422, A bill to require the Secretary of Energy to establish a comprehensive program to improve education and training for energy- and manufacturing-related jobs to increase the number of skilled workers trained to work in energy and manufacturing-related fields, and for other purposes (Heinrich); S. 1434, A bill to amend the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to establish an energy storage portfolio standard, and for other purposes (Heinrich); S. 1449, A bill to amend the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to add certain medium-duty and heavy-duty vehicles to the advanced technology vehicles manufacturing incentive program (Stabenow); H.R. 8, the North American Energy Security and Infrastructure Act of 2015; H.R. 3041, Low-Income Solar Act; S. 848, Resolving Environmental and Grid Reliability Conflicts Act of 2015; S. 15, Protecting states' rights to promote American energy security; S. 411, A bill to authorize the approval of natural gas pipelines and establish deadlines and expedite permits for certain natural gas gathering lines on Federal land and Indian land; S. 1233, A bill to amend the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to expand the electric rate-setting authority of States; S. 1236, A bill to amend the Federal Power Act to modify certain requirements relating to trial-type hearings with respect to certain license applications before the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, and for other purposes; S. 1713, Low Income Solar Act; S. 1723, Promoting Renewable Energy with Shared Solar (PRESS) Act; H.R. 2961, to establish a research, development, and technology demonstration program to improve the efficiency of gas turbines used in combined cycle and simple cycle power generation systems; H.R. 3426, the American Renewable Energy and Efficiency Act; S. 2012, the Energy Policy Modernization Act of 2015; S. 2089, the American Energy Innovation Act; S. 2012 - Energy Policy Modernization Act of 2015; H.R. 22, the Fixing Americas Surface Transportation (FAST) Act, Division F provisions regarding energy security; H.R. 1558, Resolving Environmental and Grid Reliability Conflicts Act of 2015; H.R. 2244, to establish a Strategic Transformer Reserve program; H.R. 2271, Critical Electric Infrastructure Protection Act; S. 1407, A bill to promote the development of renewable energy on public land; H.R. 2177 - Energy Savings and Industrial Competitiveness Act; S. 1029 - to prohibit DOE from prescribing a final rule amending the efficiency standards for natural gas furnaces; H.R. 1273 - Energy Savings and Building Efficiency Act; H.R. 2663, Public Land Renewable Energy Development Act of 2015, to encourage development of renewable geothermal, solar and wind energy on public land; H.R. 2984, the Fair RATES Act; H.R. 4427, to amend section 203 of the Federal Power Act.  </description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Amy </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Plaster</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kiran</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Crout </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>TAX</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Discussion draft to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify and make permanent bonus depreciation; S. 386, Mobile Workforce State Income Tax Simplification Act of 2015; Promote passage of Bonus Depreciation and return of AMT credits; H.R. 2315, Mobile Workforce State Income Tax Simplification Act of 2015; H.R. 2510, to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify and make permanent bonus depreciation; S. 660, 21st Century Worker Tax Cut Act; S. 1666, A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to increase the limitation on the election to accelerate the AMT credit in lieu of bonus depreciation for 2015 and 2016, and for other purposes; Support incentives for energy efficiency buildings (179D); Charitable Contributions Carry Forward - working to develop legislation that would extend the carry forward from 5 to 20 years; S.1660 - A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify and make permanent bonus depreciation; H.R. 879, Ax the Tax on Middle Class Americans Health Plans Act; House Amendment #2 to the Senate Amendment to H.R. 2029, Protecting Americans from Tax Hikes (PATH) Act of 2015; S. 2045, A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to repeal the excise tax on high cost employer-sponsored health coverage; S. 2075, American Worker Healthcare Tax Relief Act of 2015; S. 1946, Tax Relief Extension Act of 2015; HR 905:  LNG Excise Tax Equalization Act of 2015; H.R. 4016, Amending the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend the limitation on the carryover of excess corporate charitable contributions; H.R. 636, Americas Small Business Tax Relief Act of 2015; The Pension and Budget Integrity Act; Tax Parity: S. 1516 - Power Efficiency and Resiliency Act (POWER Act); Tax Credits: Combined Heat and Power, Fuel Cells and Microturbines Investment Tax Credit Extension Past 2016.  </description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Amy</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Plaster</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kiran </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Crout </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>CDT</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Discussion draft of reauthorization of the Commodity Exchange Act relating to derivative end-user protections; H.R. 2289, reauthorization of the Commodity Exchange Act (relating to derivative end-user protections). </description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Amy</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Plaster</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kiran </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Crout </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>TRA</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Promote &amp; protect the interests of natural gas utilities regarding pipeline safety legislation and any regulatory regime affecting natural gas utilities; Promote the development of the natural gas vehicle market by supporting various incentives; Protect the Utility Service Vehicle exemption in SAFETEA-LU; Support incentives for expansion of natural-gas as transportation fuel and fueling stations; Support incentives for natural gas vehicles; Advocate for research and development of natural gas vehicle technologies; Oppose the sale of natural gas by the Kilogram; H.R. 1963, the FLEET Act; S. 1314, Commercial UAS Modernization Act; S. 1608, Consumer Drone Safety Act; S. 1674, the DRIVE Act (Electric Vehicles); H.R. 3651, Positive Train Control Enforcement and Implementation Act of 2015; S. 808, the Surface Transportation Board Reauthorization Act; H.R. 0022, Vehicle for Senate Surface Transportation Bill; H.R. 3763, Surface Transportation Reauthorization and Reform Act of 2015; H.R. 3819, Surface Transportation Extension Act of 2015; S. 2276 SAFE Pipes Act (Pipeline Reauthorization); H.R. 4441, FAA Reauthorization; S. 2658, FAA Reauthorization Act of 2016; S. 2684, UAVs for Energy Infrastructure Act.  </description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Amy</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Plaster</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kiran </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Crout </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>HOM</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>H.R. 26, Terrorism Risk Insurance Program Reauthorization Act of 2015; H.R. 234, Cyber Intelligence Sharing and Protection Act; H.R. 1073, Critical Infrastructure Protection Act; 
H.R. 1560, Protecting Cyber Networks Act; S. 456, Cyber Threat Sharing Act of 2015;
S. 754, Cybersecurity Information Sharing Act of 2015; H.R.234:  Cyber Intelligence Sharing and Protection Act; HR. 1731:  National Cybersecurity Protection Advancement Act; HR 1560:  Protecting Cyber Networks Act; S. 754  Cybersecurity Information Sharing Act; H.R. 1073, Critical Infrastructure Protection Act (Franks); H.R. 1560, Protecting Cyber Networks Act (Nunes); H.R. 1731, National Cybersecurity Protection Advancement Act (McCaul); H.R. 1735, the FY 2016 National Defense Authorization Act (provisions regarding electromagnetic pulse); H.R. 2402, to amend the Federal Power Act to prohibit the public disclosure of protected information (Lofgren); FY 2016 Homeland Security Appropriations (provisions related to SAFETY Act clarification); H.R. 3578, the DHS Science and Technology Reform and Improvement Act of 2015 provisions regarding SAFETY Act; H.R. 3664, the Promoting Good Cyber Hygiene Act of 2015; S. 456, Cyber Threat Sharing Act of 2015; S. 754, Cybersecurity Information Sharing Act of 2015; H.R. 2029, omnibus appropriations legislation, Division N, Cybersecurity Act of 2015; S. 1846, Critical Infrastructure Protection Act of 2015; S. 1846, Critical Infrastructure Protection Act of 2015; H.R. 4350, to repeal the Cybersecurity Act of 2015; H.R.1770  - Data Security and Breach Notification Act of 2015; H.R.2205  - Data Security Act of 2015; H.R.4651 / S.2604 Digital Security Commission Act of 2016; S. 2684 - UAVs for Energy Infrastructure Act.
</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Amy </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Plaster</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kiran </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Crout </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>ENV</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Discussion draft of the Improving Coal Combustion Residuals Regulation Act of 2015, to provide for implementation of minimum federal CCR requirements through a state-based permit program; General discussion of Toxic Substances Control Act reform; S. 697, the Frank R. Lautenberg Chemical Safety for the 21st Century Act, to modernize the Toxic Substances Control Act; H.R. 1734, Improving Coal Combustion Residuals Regulation Act of 2015, to provide for implementation of minimum federal CCR requirements through a state-based permit program; H.R. 2576, TSCA Modernization Act of 2015, to modernize the Toxic Substances Control Act; Senate Improving Coal Combustion Residuals Regulation Act of 2015, to provide for implementation of minimum federal CCR requirements through a state-based permit program; S. 697, the Frank R. Lautenberg Chemical Safety for the 21st Century Act, to modernize the Toxic Substances Control Act.; H.R.1732 - Regulatory Integrity Protection Act of 2015; S.1140 - Federal Water Quality Protection Act; H.R. 2029, Consolidated Appropriations Act of 2016; S. 1140 - Federal Water Quality Protection Act - legislation pertaining to the proposed draft rule to revise the definition of Waters of the U.S. in the EPA and U.S. Army Corps of Engineers Clean Waters Act definition; H.R. 2576 - TSCA Modernization Act of 2015 - legislation related to reforming the Toxic Substance Control Act (TSCA); S. 1803 Improving Coal Combustion Residuals Regulation Act of 2015, to provide for implementation of minimum federal CCR requirements through a state-based permit program.
 
</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Amy </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Plaster</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kiran </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Crout </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>BUD</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>FY 2016 Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations, (potential appropriations issues related to Waters of the U.S., 316(b) Cooling Water Intake Structures rule, CCR regulation, and GHG NSPS); FY 2016 Energy and Water Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations, (potential appropriations issues related to DOE industry coordination on cyber and physical security, DOE/industry partnership on storm response and restoration, and grid resilience); FY 2016 Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations, (potential appropriations issues TBD; FY 2016 Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations, (potential appropriations issues related to Low Income Home Energy Assistance funding); S. Con. Res. 11 - Barrasso Amendment #347, to keep water pollution regulations focused on water quality, support for setting parameters on final "Waters of the U.S." rule; Advocated for appropriations for Low Income Home Energy Assistance Program (LIHEAP); H.R.83 - Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2015; Support lower rates on taxation of dividends; Tax reform; Tax extenders; H.R. 2028, FY 2016 Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016, Waters of the U.S. policy rider, (potential appropriations issues related to DOE-industry coordination on cyber and physical security, DOE/industry partnership on storm response and restoration, and grid resilience); H.R. 2577, FY 2016 Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations, (potential appropriations issues related to unmanned aircraft systems, coal and rail interdependencies, HUD CDBG eligibility and transportation electrification); H.R. 2685, FY 2016 Defense Appropriations, (potential appropriations issues related to renewable energy efforts and Troops to Energy Jobs); H.R. 2822, FY 2016 Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations, (potential appropriations issues related to Waters of the U.S., 316(b) Cooling Water Intake Structures rule, CCR regulation, clean air regulation, and GHG NSPS); H.R. 2995, FY 2016 Financial Services Appropriations, (potential appropriations issues related to FirstNet access and utility pole attachments); H.R. 3020, FY 2016 Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations, (potential appropriations issues related to Low Income Home Energy Assistance funding); H. Con. Res. 27, FY 2016 Budget Resolution, (budget issues generally, CBO Scoring of ESPCs and UESCs); S. 1558, FY 2016 Defense Appropriations, (potential appropriations issues related to renewable energy efforts and Troops to Energy Jobs); S. 1619, DHS Appropriations (potential appropriations issues related to Cybersecurity threat information sharing legislation and Safety Act Clarification); S. 1645, Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, (Waters of the U.S. policy rider, regulations relating to air and climate); S. 1695, FY 2016 Labor- Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations (LIHEAP);
Senate Subcommittee Draft, FY 2016 Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 (Waters of the U.S. policy rider, potential appropriations issues related to DOE-industry coordination on cyber and physical security, DOE/industry partnership on storm response and restoration, and grid resilience); S. Con. Res. 11, FY 2016 Budget Resolution, (budget issues generally, CBO Scoring of ESPCs and UESCs, Barrasso Amendment #347, to keep water pollution regulations focused on water quality, support for setting parameters on final "Waters of the U.S." rule); H.R. 719 - TSA Office of Inspection Accountability Act of 2015; the mechanism used to pass a continuing resolution to fund the government from October 1 through December 11, 2015, including LIHEAP funding at FY 2015 levels during this period; H.R. 2028, FY 2016 Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016, Waters of the U.S. policy rider, (potential appropriations issues related to DOE-industry coordination on cyber and physical security, DOE/industry partnership on storm response and restoration, and grid resilience); H.R. 2029, Consolidated Appropriations Act; H.R. 3049, FY 2016 Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies (potential appropriations issues related to bona fide hedging exemptions, financial entity definition, inter-affiliate swap transactions and physical forward contracts with volumetric optionality); H.R. 3128, Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2016 (potential appropriations issues related to Cybersecurity threat information sharing legislation and Safety Act Clarification); H.J. Res. 61, FY2016 continuing appropriations; H.J. Res. 75/H.R. 2250, FY 2016 continuing appropriations through December 16, 2015; H.J. Res. 78, FY 2016 Continuing appropriation through December 22, 2015; S. 1910, FY 2016 Financial Services Appropriations, (potential appropriations issues related to FirstNet access and utility pole attachments); S. 2129, FY 2016 bundled appropriations for Agriculture (H.R. 304), Energy and Water (H.R. 2028), Transportation Housing and Urban Development (H.R. 2577); S. 2130, FY 2016 bundled appropriations for Department of Defense (H.R. 2685), Energy and Water Development (H.R. 2028); S. 2131, FY 2016 bundled appropriations for Department of Homeland Security (S. 1619); S. 2132, FY 2016 bundled appropriations for Financial Services (H.R. 2995), Interior Environment (S. 1645) and Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education (H.R. 3020); Senate Subcommittee Draft, FY 2016 Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016, Waters of the U.S. policy rider, (potential appropriations issues related to DOE-industry coordination on cyber and physical security, DOE/industry partnership on storm response and restoration, and grid resilience).  
 

</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Amy </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Plaster</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kiran </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Crout </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>BAN</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Support revision of Volcker Rule as it relates to industrial loan banks. </description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Amy </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Plaster </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kiran </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Crout </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>UTI</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>H.R. 2358, Electricity Reliability and Forest Protection Act, facilitate vegetation management on rights-of-way across federal land to the benefit of electric reliability and forest fire risk reduction; H. Res. 127, Recognizing linemen, the profession of linemen, the contributions of these brave men and women who protect public safety, and expressing support for the designation of March 31, 2015, as National Lineman Appreciation Day; S. 2276 SAFE Pipes Act (Pipeline Reauthorization); S. 2276 SAFE Pipes Act (Pipeline Reauthorization).  </description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Amy </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Plaster</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>Executive Director, Federal Governmental Affairs </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kiran </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Crout </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>Director, Federal Governmental Affairs </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>AGR</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>H.R.2289:  Commodity End-User Relief Act (CEURA) to reauthorize the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC)</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Amy </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Plaster </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>Executive Director, Federal Governmental Affairs </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kiran </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Crout </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>Director, Federal Governmental Affairs </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>EDU</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Reauthorization Discussion Draft - Carl D. Perkins Career &amp; Technical Act. </description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Amy </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Plaster</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kiran </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Crout </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>COM</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>S. 2607, the Developing Innovation and Growing the Internet of Things (DIGIT) Act.</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Amy </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Plaster </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kiran </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Crout</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>LBR</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>H.R. 4583, To promote a 21st century energy and manufacturing workforce.</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Amy </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Plaster</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kiran </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Crout </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
  </alis>
  <updates>
    <clientAddress>
    </clientAddress>
    <clientCity>
    </clientCity>
    <clientState>
    </clientState>
    <clientZip>
    </clientZip>
    <clientZipext>
    </clientZipext>
    <clientCountry>
    </clientCountry>
    <prinClientCity>
    </prinClientCity>
    <prinClientState>
    </prinClientState>
    <prinClientZip>
    </prinClientZip>
    <prinClientZipext>
    </prinClientZipext>
    <prinClientCountry>
    </prinClientCountry>
    <generalDescription>
    </generalDescription>
    <inactive_lobbyists>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
    </inactive_lobbyists>
    <inactive_ALIs>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
    </inactive_ALIs>
    <affiliatedUrl>
    </affiliatedUrl>
    <affiliatedOrgs>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
    </affiliatedOrgs>
    <inactiveOrgs>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
    </inactiveOrgs>
    <foreignEntities>
      <foreignEntity>
        <name>
        </name>
        <address>
        </address>
        <city>
        </city>
        <state>
        </state>
        <country>
        </country>
        <prinCity>
        </prinCity>
        <prinState>
        </prinState>
        <prinCountry>
        </prinCountry>
        <contribution>
        </contribution>
        <ownership_Percentage>
        </ownership_Percentage>
      </foreignEntity>
    </foreignEntities>
    <inactive_ForeignEntities>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
    </inactive_ForeignEntities>
  </updates>
</LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>