<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='../../ld2webpage.xsl'?>
<LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>
  <imported>Y</imported>
  <pages>8</pages>
  <submitURL>
  </submitURL>
  <organizationName>National Committee to Preserve Social Security and Medicare</organizationName>
  <prefix>
  </prefix>
  <firstName>
  </firstName>
  <lastName>
  </lastName>
  <registrantDifferentAddress>N</registrantDifferentAddress>
  <address1>10 G STREET, NE, #600</address1>
  <address2>
  </address2>
  <city>WASHINGTON</city>
  <state>DC</state>
  <zip>20002</zip>
  <zipext>4215</zipext>
  <country>USA</country>
  <principal_city>
  </principal_city>
  <principal_state>
  </principal_state>
  <principal_zip>
  </principal_zip>
  <principal_zipext>
  </principal_zipext>
  <principal_country>
  </principal_country>
  <contactIntlPhone>
  </contactIntlPhone>
  <selfSelect>Y</selfSelect>
  <clientName>National Committee to Preserve Social Security and Medicare</clientName>
  <clientGovtEntity>N</clientGovtEntity>
  <senateID>27467-12</senateID>
  <houseID>303670000</houseID>
  <reportYear>2016</reportYear>
  <reportType>Q1</reportType>
  <terminationDate>
  </terminationDate>
  <noLobbying>
  </noLobbying>
  <income>
  </income>
  <expenses>200000.00</expenses>
  <expensesMethod>A</expensesMethod>
  <printedName>Max Richtman</printedName>
  <signedDate>4/13/2016 11:43:13 AM</signedDate>
  <alis>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>BUD</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>President of the U.S. Fiscal Year 2017 Budget.  (No bill.)  Proposals on Social Security, Medicare, Medicaid and Older Americans Act programs.

Congressional Fiscal Year 2017 Budget Resolution.  H. Con. Res. 125.  Proposals involving Social Security, Medicare, Medicaid and the Affordable Care Act.

Fiscal Year 2017 Outlay Levels.  (H.R. 4723, H.R. 4724 and H.R. 4725)  Proposals to reduce Fiscal Year 2017 mandatory program outlays, including plans to recover premium subsidies available under the Affordable Care Act, eliminate the Social Service Block Grant and limit the ability of state governments to use a health care provider tax to fund Medicaid.
</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, President of the U.S., Vice President of the U.S., Executive Office of the President (EOP), Office of Management &amp; Budget (OMB), Treasury - Dept of, Natl Economic Council (NEC)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Max</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Richtman</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Dan</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Adcock</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Webster</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Phillips</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Diane</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Lifsey</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Julie</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Tippens</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Lisa</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Swirsky</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>MMM</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Medicare Privatization.  (No bill.)  Proposals to transform traditional Medicare to a private insurance carrier program.

Medicare Benefit Redesign.  (No bill.)  Proposals pertaining to Parts A and B deductibles; premiums, including means-testing; a catastrophic cap on out-of-pocket spending; the eligibility age; and proposals to privatize Medicare.

Medicare Eligibility Age.  (No bill.)  Proposals to raise the eligibility age for Medicare from 65 to 67.

Medicare Drug Savings.  S. 1083, H.R. 2005, the Medicare Drug Savings Act:  proposals 
to extend the application of Medicaid drug rebates to prescription drugs paid for by Medicare and used by Medicare-Medicaid eligible beneficiaries (dual-eligibles), and by people receiving the Medicare Part D Low-Income Subsidy.

Medicare Prescription Drug Price Negotiation.  H.R. 3061, S. 31, the Medicare Prescription Drug Price Negotiation Act of 2015: proposals to authorize the Secretary of the Department of Health and Human Services to negotiate discounts, rebates, and other price concessions to lower the cost paid by Medicare to pharmaceutical manufacturers.

Medicare Prescription Drug Price Negotiation. H.R. 4207, Medicare Fair Drug Pricing Act of 2015: proposal to allow the Secretary of HHS to negotiate prices with manufacturers where little or no competition exists for drugs.

Medicare Prescription Drug Plan Option.  H.R. 3261, S. 1884, the Medicare Prescription Drug Savings and Choice Act of 2015: proposals to create one or more Medicare-administered drug plans with uniform premiums, providing seniors with the opportunity to purchase drugs directly through the Medicare program; requires the federal government to use its purchasing power to negotiate lower prices on prescription drugs for beneficiaries who enroll in the Medicare-administered plan.

Medicare Home Health Benefits.  (No bill.)  Proposals pertaining to copayments for beneficiaries receiving the Medicare home health benefit.

Medicare Observation Status.  S. 843, H.R. 1571, Improving Access to Medicare Coverage Act of 2015:  proposal to count days in the hospital in observation status toward meeting the three-day prior hospitalization requirement for skilled nursing facility (SNF) care eligibility.

Comprehensive Health Care Reform.  P.L. 111-148, Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act; P.L. 111-152, Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010:   implementation of provisions reducing Medicare Advantage plan payments; requiring higher income Medicare beneficiaries to pay an increased share of Medicare Parts B and D premium costs; expanding benefits for low-income beneficiaries under the Medicare Savings Programs and the Part D Low-Income Subsidy (LIS); expanding coverage of prevention services; testing payment and delivery system reforms; and providing expanded Medicaid coverage.

Patent Reform. S. 1137, Patent Act; H.R. 9, Innovation Act: proposal to carve brand-named pharmaceutical manufacturers out of an expedited United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) review process that allows generic companies to bypass costly litigation when challenging drug patents.  

Expanding Drug Monopolies.  H.R. 6, 21st Century Cures Act:  proposal to extend orphan drug market exclusivity for existing drugs to new indications.

Reducing Prescription Drug Costs.  S. 2023, H.R. 3513, Prescription Drug Affordability Act:  proposals to allow Medicare to negotiate drug prices, to allow Medicare and Medicaid to receive additional rebates from brand and generic drugs, and to allow for the re-importation of drugs from Canada.

Chronic Care Coordination.  (No bill.)  Proposals to facilitate the delivery of high-quality care for people with Medicare living with multiple chronic conditions.

Medicare Vision, Dental and Hearing Coverage.  H.R. 3308, Seniors Have Eyes, Ears and Teeth Act:  proposal to provide Medicare coverage for vision, hearing and dental services.

Medicare Hearing Coverage.  H.R. 1653, the Medicare Hearing Aid Coverage Act of 2015: proposal to provide Medicare coverage for the cost of hearing aids and examinations.

Medicare Dental Coverage.  S. 570, H.R. 1055, the Comprehensive Dental Reform Act: proposal to extend comprehensive dental coverage to all Medicare, Medicaid, and VA beneficiaries.

Medicare Part B Premium and Deductible Increase.  S. 2148, Protecting Medicare Beneficiaries Act of 2015; H.R. 3696, Medicare Premium Fairness Act of 2015 and P.L. 114-74:  proposals to prevent steep increases in Medicare Part B premiums and deductibles in 2016.

Medicare Care Planning.  S. 1549, the Care Planning Act of 2015: proposals to create a Medicare benefit for care planning, the coordination of services, to fill gaps in quality measurement in the advanced illness field, and to include advanced care planning information in the Medicare &amp; You handbook.

Medicare Private Plan Notification Improvements.  (No bill.)  Proposals to improve the annual notification Medicare private plans promulgate to Parts C and D enrollees pertaining to plan changes that will raise enrollee costs or limit access to products and services.  

Medicare Part B Payment Reforms.  (No bill.)  Proposals to change the way Medicare pays doctors for administering drugs to eliminate incentives to prescribe drugs based on their expense instead of clinical need.

Medicare Advantage Payment Reforms.  (No bill.)  Proposals to eliminate discrepancies in how much Medicare pays for services for similarly situated individuals in traditional Medicare and in Medicare Advantage plans.
</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Health &amp; Human Services - Dept of (HHS), Centers For Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS), Administration on Aging, Executive Office of the President (EOP)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Max</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Richtman</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Dan</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Adcock</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Webster</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Phillips</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Diane</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Lifsey</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Julie</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Tippens</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Lisa</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Swirsky</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>RET</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Department of Labor (DOL) Retirement Advisor Fiduciary Rule. (No bill.)  Proposed DOL rule to protect Americans from conflicts of interest when brokers and other financial advisors give retirement advice.

The Older Americans Act.  S. 192, Older Americans Act Reauthorization Act of 2015:    provisions related to the reauthorization of the Older Americans Act.

Cost of Living Adjustment Relief.  S. 2251 and H.R. 4144, Seniors and Veterans Emergency (SAVE) Benefits Act:  proposal to require the Secretary of the Treasury to make a one-time emergency payment to Social Security beneficiaries, veterans and others.

Social Security Commission.  H.R. 1578, Social Security Commission Act of 2015:   proposals to require a commission to make recommendations for achieving solvency of the Social Security trust funds for 75 years.

Social Security Expansion. H.R. 1391, S. 1904, Social Security 2100 Act:  proposals to improve benefits and to strengthen Social Securitys financing by eliminating the payroll tax cap and implementing a gradual increase in workers and employers contributions to Social Security.

Social Security Expansion Support:  H. Res. 393: proposals to express support for protecting and expanding Social Security benefits while securing the programs long term future.

Supplemental Security Income (SSI).  S. 1387, H.R. 2442, Supplemental Security Income Restoration Act of 2015:  proposals to update provisions in the SSI program to reflect inflation since 1972 and to increase the asset limit to $10,000 for an individual and $15,000 for a couple.

Supplemental Security Income and Social Security Benefits.  H.R. 2511, School Attendance Improves Lives (SAIL) Act:  proposals to require SSI beneficiaries between the ages of 16-17 to attend school full-time in order to qualify for benefits.

Supplemental Security Income and Social Security Benefits.  H.R. 2504, Control Unlawful Fugitive Felons (CUFF) Act: proposal to authorize the Social Security Administration to suspend Social Security or SSI benefits to individuals with outstanding arrest warrants or who have violated the terms of their parole.

Social Security Benefit Statement.  (No bill.)  Efforts to have the Social Security Administration resume annual distribution of benefit statements to eligible individuals.

Eliminating Government Pension Offset and Windfall Elimination Provision.  S. 1651, H.R. 973, Social Security Fairness Act:  proposal to repeal the Government Pension Offset and Windfall Elimination Provision.

Modifying Windfall Elimination Provision.  H.R. 711, Equal Treatment of Public Servants Act:  proposal to replace the current Windfall Elimination Provision with a new Social Security formula.

Protecting Seniors from Garnishment.  (No bill.)  Proposals to protect Social Security beneficiaries from having their Social Security benefits garnished to recover unpaid student loans.

Caregiver Social Security Credits.  S. 2721, H.R. 3377, Social Security Caregiver Credit Act of 2015:  proposal to provide wage credits for individuals who reduce their participation in the workforce or leave the workforce to provide care to specified family members and relatives.

Gun Control Initiatives.  (No bill.)  Proposals to require the Social Security Administration to identify Social Security beneficiaries whose medical or psychological conditions render them unfit to own firearms.

Protecting Social Security Benefits from Administrative Offset.  S. 2387, Protection of Social Security Benefits Restoration Act: : proposal to restore the protections of previous law preventing the government from taking away earned benefits to pay Federal debts.</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Social Security Administration (SSA), Administration on Aging, Executive Office of the President (EOP), Justice - Dept of (DOJ), Labor - Dept of (DOL)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Max</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Richtman</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Dan</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Adcock</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Webster</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Phillips</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Diane</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Lifsey</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Julie</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Tippens</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Lisa</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Swirsky</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>TRD</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Trans-Pacific Partnership (TPP) Agreement.  (No bill.)  Proposals affecting prescription drug, biologic drug and medical device costs in public programs such as Medicare and Medicaid.</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Executive Office of the President (EOP)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Max</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Richtman</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Dan</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Adcock</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Webster</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Phillips</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Diane</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Lifsey</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Julie</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Tippens</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Lisa</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Swirsky</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>HCR</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Family Caregiver Assistance.  S. 1719, H.R. 3099, Recognize, Assist, Include, Support, and Engage (RAISE) Family Caregivers Act of 2015: proposal directing the Department of Health and Human Services to develop, maintain, and periodically update a National Family Caregiving Strategy.

Family Caregiver Assistance. H.R. 3913, Lifespan Respite Care Reauthorization Act: proposal to reauthorize the program that provides grants to states to develop or enhance existing respite care programs for family caregivers caring for individuals with special needs of all ages.</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Health &amp; Human Services - Dept of (HHS)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Max</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Richtman</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Dan</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Adcock</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Webster</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Phillips</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Diane</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Lifsey</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Julie</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Tippens</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Lisa</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Swirsky</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>POS</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Postal Reform.  S. 2051, the Improving Postal Operations, Services and Transparency Act of 2015:  proposal that would increase postal rates for nonprofit advocacy organizations by making the temporary exigent rate surcharge, scheduled to end in April 2016, permanent.</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Max</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Richtman</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Dan</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Adcock</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Webster</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Phillips</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Diane</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Lifsey</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Julie</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Tippens</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Lisa</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Swirsky</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
  </alis>
  <updates>
    <clientAddress>
    </clientAddress>
    <clientCity>
    </clientCity>
    <clientState>
    </clientState>
    <clientZip>
    </clientZip>
    <clientZipext>
    </clientZipext>
    <clientCountry>
    </clientCountry>
    <prinClientCity>
    </prinClientCity>
    <prinClientState>
    </prinClientState>
    <prinClientZip>
    </prinClientZip>
    <prinClientZipext>
    </prinClientZipext>
    <prinClientCountry>
    </prinClientCountry>
    <generalDescription>
    </generalDescription>
    <inactive_lobbyists>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>Julie</firstName>
        <lastName>Tippens</lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
    </inactive_lobbyists>
    <inactive_ALIs>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
    </inactive_ALIs>
    <affiliatedUrl>
    </affiliatedUrl>
    <affiliatedOrgs>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
    </affiliatedOrgs>
    <inactiveOrgs>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
    </inactiveOrgs>
    <foreignEntities>
      <foreignEntity>
        <name>
        </name>
        <address>
        </address>
        <city>
        </city>
        <state>
        </state>
        <country>
        </country>
        <prinCity>
        </prinCity>
        <prinState>
        </prinState>
        <prinCountry>
        </prinCountry>
        <contribution>
        </contribution>
        <ownership_Percentage>
        </ownership_Percentage>
      </foreignEntity>
    </foreignEntities>
    <inactive_ForeignEntities>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
    </inactive_ForeignEntities>
  </updates>
</LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>