<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='../../ld2webpage.xsl'?>
<LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>
  <imported>Y</imported>
  <pages>5</pages>
  <submitURL>
  </submitURL>
  <organizationName>National Association of Federal Credit Unions</organizationName>
  <prefix>
  </prefix>
  <firstName>
  </firstName>
  <lastName>
  </lastName>
  <registrantDifferentAddress>N</registrantDifferentAddress>
  <address1>3138 NORTH 10TH STREET</address1>
  <address2>
  </address2>
  <city>ARLINGTON</city>
  <state>VA</state>
  <zip>22201</zip>
  <zipext>
  </zipext>
  <country>USA</country>
  <principal_city>
  </principal_city>
  <principal_state>
  </principal_state>
  <principal_zip>
  </principal_zip>
  <principal_zipext>
  </principal_zipext>
  <principal_country>
  </principal_country>
  <contactIntlPhone>
  </contactIntlPhone>
  <selfSelect>Y</selfSelect>
  <clientName>National Association of Federal Credit Unions</clientName>
  <clientGovtEntity>N</clientGovtEntity>
  <senateID>26763-12</senateID>
  <houseID>302630000</houseID>
  <reportYear>2016</reportYear>
  <reportType>Q1</reportType>
  <terminationDate>
  </terminationDate>
  <noLobbying>
  </noLobbying>
  <income>
  </income>
  <expenses>420000.00</expenses>
  <expensesMethod>A</expensesMethod>
  <printedName>Carrie Hunt </printedName>
  <signedDate>4/19/2016 5:07:08 PM</signedDate>
  <alis>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>BAN</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Consumer Financial Protection Bureaus (CFPB) Notice and Request for Comment on Web-Based Quantitative Testing Point of Sale/ATM (POS/ATM) Overdraft Disclosure Forms; Comments responding to request for information on the FHFAs proposed collection of information relating to the NSEMB; Comments on Regulatory Impact Assessment and Initial Regulatory Flexibility Analysis, RIN 1506-AB25; Concerns with CFPB future payday lending rulemakings; payday lending as related to the CFPBs Outline of Proposals Under Consideration; H.R. 3192: Homebuyers Assistance Act; H.R. 2769: Risk-Based Capital Study Act; National Credit Union Administrations (NCUA) risk-based capital proposal; H.R. 2205: Data Security Act of 2015/ Subjects retailers to robust federal safekeeping standard; EMV chip technology is what makes the new cards more secure -  PIN is a distraction from the real issue that is data security; party responsible for breached data should be liable for costs associated with breach; NCUA budget transparency; H.R. 1176: NCUA Budget Transparency Act/ GAO Study of NCUA budgeting practices; H.R. 1188: Credit Union Small Business Jobs Creation Act/ raising MBL cap; H.R. 1195: Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection Advisory Boards Act; H.R. 1210: Portfolio Lending and Mortgage Access Act; H.R. 2473: Preserving Capital Access and Mortgage Liquidity Act of 2015; H.R. 2896: the TAILOR Act of 2015; S. 754: Cyber Security Information Sharing Act; NAFCUs Five Point Plan for Regulatory Relief (capital reforms for credit unions; field of membership improvements for credit unions; reduced consumer financial protection bureaus on credit unions; operational improvements for credit unions; 21st century data security standards); Regulatory relief for credit unions; S. 961: Data Security Act of 2015/ Subjects retailers to robust federal safekeeping standard; NCUAs efforts to allow credit unions to better serve rural areas; H.R. 1259: Helping Expand Lending Practices in Rural Communities Act; H.R. 1261: Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection Accountability Act/ Subjects CFPB to Congressional appropriations process; S. 774: Financial Institutions Examination Fairness and Reform Act; S. 871: HELP Rural Communities Act of 2015/ CFPB Rural Definition; H.R. 685: Mortgage Choice Act of 2015/ Points and Fees; H.R. 1408: Mortgage Servicing Asset Capital Requirements Act; H.R. 1422: Credit Union Residential Loan Parity Act/ MBL 1-4 exemption; H.R. 1529: Community Institution Mortgage Relief Act of 2015; H.R. 1941: Financial Institutions Examination Fairness and Reform Act; Regulatory Burdens; Qualified Mortgage Rule; S. 1484: Financial Regulatory Improvement Act; S. 2028: A bill to amend the Federal Credit Union Act, to advance the ability of credit unions to promote small business growth and economic development opportunities, and for other purposes; H.R. 3738: the Office of Financial Research Accountability Act of 2015; H.R. 3557: the FSOC Transparency and Accountability Act; H.R. 1660: the Federal Savings Association Charter Flexibility Act; Improve the federal charter of credit unions through the FCU Act; H.R. 989: Capital Access for Small Businesses and Jobs Act/ Supplemental Capital; H.R. 1133: To exclude extensions of credit made to veterans from the definition of a member business loan under the Federal Credit Union Act; NCUA proposed rulemaking on a federal insured credit unions member business lending; NCUAs exam scheduling policy; NAFCUs Top Ten Regulations for Eliminate of Amend (improve process for credit unions seeking changes to their field of membership; provide more meaningful exemptions for small institutions; expand credit union investment authority; allowing more transfers per month from savings accounts per Federal Reserve Regulation D; flexibility for credit unions making member business loans; NCUAs member business lending rule: update requirement to disclose account numbers to protect privacy of members; update advertising requirements for loan products and share accounts; seek improvements to the NCUA Central Liquidity Facility; obtain flexibility for federal credit unions to determine their choice of law; update simplify and make improvements to regulations governing check processing funds); S. 423: Privacy Notice Modernization Act of 2015; H.R. 22: the Surface Transportation Reauthorization and Reform Act of 2015; NCUAs proposed Field of Membership Amendments; H.R. 2995: Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act; Require the CFPB to conduct a fair, comprehensive study before adopting a rule that would restrict arbitration and open the door to abusive class actions; NCUA third party vendor authority; CFPB request for approval under the Paperwork Reduction Act to conduct a national web-based survey relative to overdraft protection services; CFPB consumer complaint narrative database; CFPB and the student loan servicing market; CFPB integration of the Truth in Lending Act (TILA) - Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act (RESPA) disclosures, consider good faith efforts to comply with TRID; financial regulators must level the playing field and promulgate rules that require non-traditional market lenders to meet basic consumer protection requirements such as those of TILA, underwriting standards for loans, and applicable state usury  laws; FSOC should facilitate  regulatory coordination among its member regulators; preserve the credit union tax exemption; regulatory relief including CFPB using their exemption authority more; Housing Finance Reform - it is vital that credit unions continue to have unfettered access to the secondary mortgage market and any reforms should have emphasis on fair pricing that reflects loan quality rather than quantity; Department of Labors proposed changes to the Fair Labor Standards Act for certain full-time salaried works to be eligible for overtime protections; Federal Communication Commission clarification for free end user calls made by financial institutions; Federal Communication Commission clarification regarding clarifications to the interpretations of the Telephone Consumer Protection Act; H.R. 1155: the Searching for and Cutting Regulations that are unnecessarily Burdensome (SCRUB) Act; prepaid cards - CFPB efforts to ensure that consumers using prepaid products are sufficiently informed and protected - they should find appropriate balance between adequate consumer protection and allowing consumers access to products they demand; compliance burdens related to CFPB amendments to Regulation C, HMDA; Small Business Administration SBA 7(a) business loan program; H.R. 2499: Veterans Entrepreneurship Act of 2015; FY 2016 Financial Services and General Government Appropriations bill; H.R. 427: Regulations for the Executive in Need of Scrutiny Act of 2015; Agency use of regulatory guidance; Protect responsible overdraft services; Changes to requirements under the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act; H.R. 957: Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection Inspector General Reform Act; Reform of Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac; Credit risk-guarantee fees; Military Lending Act; H.R. 1735: National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016; Cost-benefit analysis at federal regulatory agencies; Regulatory coordination; Regulations related to remittance transfers; Legal opinion letters at the CFPB; H.R. 9: Innovation Act; H.R. 185: Regulatory Accountability Act of 2015; H.R. 527: Small Business Regulatory Flexibility Improvements Act of 2015; H.R. 650: Preserving Access to Manufactured Housing Act; H.R. 766: Financial Institution Customer Protection Act/ Ending Operation Choke Point; H.R. 1262: Consumer Right to Financial Privacy Act of 2015; H.R. 1263: Consumer Financial Protection Safety and Soundness Improvement Act/ Changes veto authority of the Financial Stability Oversight Council; H.R. 1265: Bureau Advisory Commission Transparency Act/ Making credit union advisory council meetings public; H.R. 1266: Financial Product Safety Commission Act/ Replacing CFPB Director with Commission; H.R. 1309: Systemic Risk Designation Improvement Act of 2015; S. 881: Comprehensive Regulatory Review Act of 2015; S. 924: To require public hearings on NCUA's budget; S. 1137: PATENT Act; S. 1440: Credit Union Residential Loan Parity Act/ MBL 1-4 exemption; Ensure an Effective Payments system; Fairness under FCC ruling on autodialing and FCC oversight; modernize online lending laws and regulations; give NCUA greater flexibility with credit union lending including the ability to establish longer maturities for certain loans; preventing g-fees charged by Fannie and Freddie from being used as funding offset; NCUA 18-month Exam Cycle; Military Lending Act Database; Credit Losses Accounting Standard; FASB Accounting Standards; CFPBs expansion of data collection under Reg C, Privacy protections for data collected by CFPB; NIST notice and request for information on views on the Framework for Improving Critical Infrastructure Cybersecurity; Comments on Notice of proposed rulemaking regarding field of membership and chartering;  CBSA population limit, combined statistical area, well defined local communities, rural population limits, multiple common bond charters, underserved areas, TIP charters; CFPB information collection on compliance costs and other effects of regulation; Duty to serve underserved markets; interchange rates as related to the Durbin Amendment to Dodd-Frank; Federal Reserves EGRPRA review process; FHFAs principal reduction consideration; FFIEC Cybersecurity Assessment Tool; Department of Labor Overtime Rule; Department of Labor Fiduciary Rule.</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>Natl Credit Union Administration (NCUA), Small Business Administration (SBA), Defense - Dept of (DOD), Homeland Security - Dept of (DHS), Federal Reserve System, Treasury - Dept of, Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC), Securities &amp; Exchange Commission (SEC), Housing &amp; Urban Development - Dept of (HUD), Office of the Comptroller of the Currency (OCC), Government Accountability Office (GAO), White House Office, Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA), Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB), Federal Trade Commission (FTC), Financial Crimes Enforcement Network (FinCEN), Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC), Justice - Dept of (DOJ), U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, U.S. SENATE, Natl Institute of Standards &amp; Technology (NIST), Office of Management &amp; Budget (OMB), Federal Communications Commission (FCC), Labor - Dept of (DOL)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Dan </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Berger</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Carrie</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Hunt</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Brad</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Thaler</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Chad</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Adams</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Dan</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>O'Brien </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Alicia</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Nealon</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Meghan</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Brady</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kavitha</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Subramanian</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Alexander </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Monterrubio</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Matthew</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Schwartz</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Michael</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Emancipator</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Quincy</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Enoch</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>FIN</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Consumer Financial Protection Bureaus (CFPB) Notice and Request for Comment on Web-Based Quantitative Testing Point of Sale/ATM (POS/ATM) Overdraft Disclosure Forms; Comments responding to request for information on the FHFAs proposed collection of information relating to the NSEMB; Comments on Regulatory Impact Assessment and Initial Regulatory Flexibility Analysis, RIN 1506-AB25; Concerns with CFPB future payday lending rulemakings; payday lending as related to the CFPBs Outline of Proposals Under Consideration; H.R. 3192: Homebuyers Assistance Act; H.R. 2769: Risk-Based Capital Study Act; National Credit Union Administrations (NCUA) risk-based capital proposal; H.R. 2205: Data Security Act of 2015/ Subjects retailers to robust federal safekeeping standard; EMV chip technology is what makes the new cards more secure -  PIN is a distraction from the real issue that is data security; party responsible for breached data should be liable for costs associated with breach; NCUA budget transparency; H.R. 1176: NCUA Budget Transparency Act/ GAO Study of NCUA budgeting practices; H.R. 1188: Credit Union Small Business Jobs Creation Act/ raising MBL cap; H.R. 1195: Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection Advisory Boards Act; H.R. 1210: Portfolio Lending and Mortgage Access Act; H.R. 2473: Preserving Capital Access and Mortgage Liquidity Act of 2015; H.R. 2896: the TAILOR Act of 2015; S. 754: Cyber Security Information Sharing Act; NAFCUs Five Point Plan for Regulatory Relief (capital reforms for credit unions; field of membership improvements for credit unions; reduced consumer financial protection bureaus on credit unions; operational improvements for credit unions; 21st century data security standards); Regulatory relief for credit unions; S. 961: Data Security Act of 2015/ Subjects retailers to robust federal safekeeping standard; NCUAs efforts to allow credit unions to better serve rural areas; H.R. 1259: Helping Expand Lending Practices in Rural Communities Act; H.R. 1261: Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection Accountability Act/ Subjects CFPB to Congressional appropriations process; S. 774: Financial Institutions Examination Fairness and Reform Act; S. 871: HELP Rural Communities Act of 2015/ CFPB Rural Definition; H.R. 685: Mortgage Choice Act of 2015/ Points and Fees; H.R. 1408: Mortgage Servicing Asset Capital Requirements Act; H.R. 1422: Credit Union Residential Loan Parity Act/ MBL 1-4 exemption; H.R. 1529: Community Institution Mortgage Relief Act of 2015; H.R. 1941: Financial Institutions Examination Fairness and Reform Act; Regulatory Burdens; Qualified Mortgage Rule; S. 1484: Financial Regulatory Improvement Act; S. 2028: A bill to amend the Federal Credit Union Act, to advance the ability of credit unions to promote small business growth and economic development opportunities, and for other purposes; H.R. 3738: the Office of Financial Research Accountability Act of 2015; H.R. 3557: the FSOC Transparency and Accountability Act; H.R. 1660: the Federal Savings Association Charter Flexibility Act; Improve the federal charter of credit unions through the FCU Act; H.R. 989: Capital Access for Small Businesses and Jobs Act/ Supplemental Capital; H.R. 1133: To exclude extensions of credit made to veterans from the definition of a member business loan under the Federal Credit Union Act; NCUA proposed rulemaking on a federal insured credit unions member business lending; NCUAs exam scheduling policy; NAFCUs Top Ten Regulations for Eliminate of Amend (improve process for credit unions seeking changes to their field of membership; provide more meaningful exemptions for small institutions; expand credit union investment authority; allowing more transfers per month from savings accounts per Federal Reserve Regulation D; flexibility for credit unions making member business loans; NCUAs member business lending rule: update requirement to disclose account numbers to protect privacy of members; update advertising requirements for loan products and share accounts; seek improvements to the NCUA Central Liquidity Facility; obtain flexibility for federal credit unions to determine their choice of law; update simplify and make improvements to regulations governing check processing funds); S. 423: Privacy Notice Modernization Act of 2015; H.R. 22: the Surface Transportation Reauthorization and Reform Act of 2015; NCUAs proposed Field of Membership Amendments; H.R. 2995: Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act; Require the CFPB to conduct a fair, comprehensive study before adopting a rule that would restrict arbitration and open the door to abusive class actions; NCUA third party vendor authority; CFPB request for approval under the Paperwork Reduction Act to conduct a national web-based survey relative to overdraft protection services; CFPB consumer complaint narrative database; CFPB and the student loan servicing market; CFPB integration of the Truth in Lending Act (TILA) - Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act (RESPA) disclosures, consider good faith efforts to comply with TRID; financial regulators must level the playing field and promulgate rules that require non-traditional market lenders to meet basic consumer protection requirements such as those of TILA, underwriting standards for loans, and applicable state usury  laws; FSOC should facilitate  regulatory coordination among its member regulators; preserve the credit union tax exemption; regulatory relief including CFPB using their exemption authority more; Housing Finance Reform - it is vital that credit unions continue to have unfettered access to the secondary mortgage market and any reforms should have emphasis on fair pricing that reflects loan quality rather than quantity; Department of Labors proposed changes to the Fair Labor Standards Act for certain full-time salaried works to be eligible for overtime protections; Federal Communication Commission clarification for free end user calls made by financial institutions; Federal Communication Commission clarification regarding clarifications to the interpretations of the Telephone Consumer Protection Act; H.R. 1155: the Searching for and Cutting Regulations that are unnecessarily Burdensome (SCRUB) Act; prepaid cards - CFPB efforts to ensure that consumers using prepaid products are sufficiently informed and protected - they should find appropriate balance between adequate consumer protection and allowing consumers access to products they demand; compliance burdens related to CFPB amendments to Regulation C, HMDA; Small Business Administration SBA 7(a) business loan program; H.R. 2499: Veterans Entrepreneurship Act of 2015; FY 2016 Financial Services and General Government Appropriations bill; H.R. 427: Regulations for the Executive in Need of Scrutiny Act of 2015; Agency use of regulatory guidance; Protect responsible overdraft services; Changes to requirements under the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act; H.R. 957: Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection Inspector General Reform Act; Reform of Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac; Credit risk-guarantee fees; Military Lending Act; H.R. 1735: National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016; Cost-benefit analysis at federal regulatory agencies; Regulatory coordination; Regulations related to remittance transfers; Legal opinion letters at the CFPB; H.R. 9: Innovation Act; H.R. 185: Regulatory Accountability Act of 2015; H.R. 527: Small Business Regulatory Flexibility Improvements Act of 2015; H.R. 650: Preserving Access to Manufactured Housing Act; H.R. 766: Financial Institution Customer Protection Act/ Ending Operation Choke Point; H.R. 1262: Consumer Right to Financial Privacy Act of 2015; H.R. 1263: Consumer Financial Protection Safety and Soundness Improvement Act/ Changes veto authority of the Financial Stability Oversight Council; H.R. 1265: Bureau Advisory Commission Transparency Act/ Making credit union advisory council meetings public; H.R. 1266: Financial Product Safety Commission Act/ Replacing CFPB Director with Commission; H.R. 1309: Systemic Risk Designation Improvement Act of 2015; S. 881: Comprehensive Regulatory Review Act of 2015; S. 924: To require public hearings on NCUA's budget; S. 1137: PATENT Act; S. 1440: Credit Union Residential Loan Parity Act/ MBL 1-4 exemption; Ensure an Effective Payments system; Fairness under FCC ruling on autodialing and FCC oversight; modernize online lending laws and regulations; give NCUA greater flexibility with credit union lending including the ability to establish longer maturities for certain loans; preventing g-fees charged by Fannie and Freddie from being used as funding offset; NCUA 18-month Exam Cycle; Military Lending Act Database; Credit Losses Accounting Standard; FASB Accounting Standards; CFPBs expansion of data collection under Reg C, Privacy protections for data collected by CFPB; NIST notice and request for information on views on the Framework for Improving Critical Infrastructure Cybersecurity; Comments on Notice of proposed rulemaking regarding field of membership and chartering;  CBSA population limit, combined statistical area, well defined local communities, rural population limits, multiple common bond charters, underserved areas, TIP charters; CFPB information collection on compliance costs and other effects of regulation; Duty to serve underserved markets; interchange rates as related to the Durbin Amendment to Dodd-Frank; Federal Reserves EGRPRA review process; FHFAs principal reduction consideration; FFIEC Cybersecurity Assessment Tool; Department of Labor Overtime Rule; Department of Labor Fiduciary Rule.</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>Natl Credit Union Administration (NCUA), Small Business Administration (SBA), Defense - Dept of (DOD), Homeland Security - Dept of (DHS), Federal Reserve System, Treasury - Dept of, Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC), Securities &amp; Exchange Commission (SEC), Housing &amp; Urban Development - Dept of (HUD), Office of the Comptroller of the Currency (OCC), Government Accountability Office (GAO), White House Office, Federal Trade Commission (FTC), Financial Crimes Enforcement Network (FinCEN), Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC), Justice - Dept of (DOJ), U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, U.S. SENATE, Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA), Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB), Natl Institute of Standards &amp; Technology (NIST), Office of Management &amp; Budget (OMB), Federal Communications Commission (FCC), Labor - Dept of (DOL)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Dan</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Berger</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Quincy</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Enoch</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Carrie</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Hunt</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Brad</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Thaler</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Chad</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Adams</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Dan</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>O'Brien</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Alicia</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Nealon</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Meghan</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Brady</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kavitha</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Subramanian</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Alexander</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Monterrubio</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Matthew</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Schwartz</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Michael </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Emancipator</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>TAX</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>credit union tax exemption; retention of the credit union tax exemption in any reform efforts</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>Internal Revenue Service (IRS), Natl Credit Union Administration (NCUA), Treasury - Dept of, White House Office, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, U.S. SENATE, Federal Trade Commission (FTC), Federal Reserve System</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Dan </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Berger</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Quincy</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Enoch</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Carrie</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Hunt</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Brad</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Thaler</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Chad</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Adams</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Dan</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>O'Brien</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Alicia </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Nealon</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Meghan</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Brady</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kavitha</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Subramanian</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Alexander</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Monterrubio</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Matthew</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Schwartz</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Michael</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Emancipator</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
  </alis>
  <updates>
    <clientAddress>
    </clientAddress>
    <clientCity>
    </clientCity>
    <clientState>
    </clientState>
    <clientZip>
    </clientZip>
    <clientZipext>
    </clientZipext>
    <clientCountry>
    </clientCountry>
    <prinClientCity>
    </prinClientCity>
    <prinClientState>
    </prinClientState>
    <prinClientZip>
    </prinClientZip>
    <prinClientZipext>
    </prinClientZipext>
    <prinClientCountry>
    </prinClientCountry>
    <generalDescription>
    </generalDescription>
    <inactive_lobbyists>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>Quincy</firstName>
        <lastName>Enoch</lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>Alicia</firstName>
        <lastName>Nealon</lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
    </inactive_lobbyists>
    <inactive_ALIs>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
    </inactive_ALIs>
    <affiliatedUrl>https://www.nafcu.org/Tertiary.aspx?id=17818</affiliatedUrl>
    <affiliatedOrgs>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>NAFCU Board of Directors</affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>3138 North 10th Street</affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>Arlington</affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>VA</affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>22201</affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>USA</affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
    </affiliatedOrgs>
    <inactiveOrgs>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
    </inactiveOrgs>
    <foreignEntities>
      <foreignEntity>
        <name>
        </name>
        <address>
        </address>
        <city>
        </city>
        <state>
        </state>
        <country>
        </country>
        <prinCity>
        </prinCity>
        <prinState>
        </prinState>
        <prinCountry>
        </prinCountry>
        <contribution>
        </contribution>
        <ownership_Percentage>
        </ownership_Percentage>
      </foreignEntity>
    </foreignEntities>
    <inactive_ForeignEntities>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
    </inactive_ForeignEntities>
  </updates>
</LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>