<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='../../ld2webpage.xsl'?>
<LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>
  <imported>N</imported>
  <pages>7</pages>
  <submitURL>
  </submitURL>
  <organizationName>MARSHFIELD CLINIC HEALTH SYSTEM</organizationName>
  <prefix>
  </prefix>
  <firstName>
  </firstName>
  <lastName>
  </lastName>
  <registrantDifferentAddress>N</registrantDifferentAddress>
  <address1>1000 NORTH OAK AVENUE</address1>
  <address2>
  </address2>
  <city>MARSHFIELD</city>
  <state>WI</state>
  <zip>54449</zip>
  <zipext>5777</zipext>
  <country>USA</country>
  <principal_city>
  </principal_city>
  <principal_state>
  </principal_state>
  <principal_zip>
  </principal_zip>
  <principal_zipext>
  </principal_zipext>
  <principal_country>
  </principal_country>
  <contactIntlPhone>
  </contactIntlPhone>
  <selfSelect>Y</selfSelect>
  <clientName>MARSHFIELD CLINIC HEALTH SYSTEM</clientName>
  <clientGovtEntity>N</clientGovtEntity>
  <senateID>57830-12</senateID>
  <houseID>352550000</houseID>
  <reportYear>2016</reportYear>
  <reportType>Q1</reportType>
  <terminationDate>
  </terminationDate>
  <noLobbying>
  </noLobbying>
  <income>
  </income>
  <expenses>160000.00</expenses>
  <expensesMethod>A</expensesMethod>
  <printedName>Brent V. Miller</printedName>
  <signedDate>4/15/2016 12:10:32 PM</signedDate>
  <alis>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>BUD</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Personalized (Precision) Medicine  

Personalized medicine, the tailoring of medical treatments to patient characteristics, relies upon the ability to classify individuals into subpopulations that differ in disease susceptibility and treatment responses. It allows clinicians to target preventive or therapeutic interventions on those who will benefit, and thereby to spare the expense and side effects of treatment for those who will not, thus making medicine more efficient. If the multiple population groups in the United States and elsewhere in the world are to benefit fully and fairly from such research, a national resource operated as a trust for the public good must be established to conduct a large population-based cohort study that includes full representation of minority populations. The Federal government should make critical investments in the enabling tools and resources essential to moving beyond genomic discoveries to personalized medicine services of patient and public benefit.

National Farm Safety

Support for occupational safety and health funding for Fiscal Year 2015.  The National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health (NIOSH) is the primary federal agency responsible for conducting research and making recommendations for the prevention of work-related illness and injury. NIOSH provides leadership to avert workplace illness, injury, disability, and death and supports programs to improve the health and safety of workers. NIOSH funds the National Childrens Center for Rural and Agricultural Health and Safety. Marshfield Clinic urges support for this important program.


</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Natl Institutes of Health (NIH)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Brent</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Miller</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>MMM</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>MMM (Medicare and Medicaid)
Many aspects of the Affordable Care Act promote changes that are consistent with the mission of the Marshfield Clinic:
Extends health insurance to the uninsured
Calls for Value Based Purchasing for all providers 
Calls for the establishment of Accountable Care Organizations

The following are key elements of the health policy agenda of the Marshfield Clinic Health System: 

Medicare Access and CHIP Reauthorization Act 
With passage of the Medicare Access and CHIP Reauthorization Act of 2015 (MACRA), Congress eliminated the constant threat of inappropriate cuts to Medicare physician fees. Going forward Medicare physician payments will transition to an incentive-based system based on value and accountability.  Starting in 2019, Medicare physician payment will be based on the Merit-Based Incentive Payment System (MIPS). Physicians who perform well on quality, value and IT metrics will be rewarded with higher pay rates and those who perform poorly will face penalties. Participants in Alternative Payment Systems such as accountable care organizations that assume financial risk will receive 5% bonuses between 2019 and 2025. Because the language of the statute is not specific, the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS) must develop specific metrics that will be used to determine the bonus payments and penalties that will start in 2019 in public rulemaking well before 2019.   We have concerns about the regulatory process that will be used to determine which alternative delivery systems warrant bonus payments, as well as the metrics that will determine bonuses and penalties for those remaining in a fee-for-service payment system. 
MCHS also supported MACRA provisions that extended funding for the Childrens Health Insurance Program and provided $7.2 billion to community health centers over the next 2 years, postponed cuts in payments to hospitals that treat large numbers of low-income patients; and extended provisions that funded geographic adjustment of the physician work, therapy services and payments for rural hospitals.
Graduate Medical Education - 
Teaching hospitals in rural locations provide an environment for residents to learn and faculty to serve as educators, providers and researchers. These roles advance the broad mission of preparing each generation of physicians, provide critical patient care and specialized services, often to the disadvantaged, facilitate the discovery of new therapies and treatments, and enable residents to acclimate to the rural setting. As new payment and delivery models emphasize primary care to improve patient outcomes and reduce costs, and as more care shifts to outpatient settings, teaching faculty and residency programs must increase access to ambulatory residency rotations to serve Americans who live in areas with an under-supply of primary care physicians. The purpose and value of residency training in clinical settings and the financial support needed to sustain physician education will only increase as the U.S. population lives longer with more complex health conditions.  To ensure GME can meet the future needs of the newly insured and aging population, Congress must commit to the consistent GME funding and lift Medicares limit on funded residency positions. We support the Teaching Health Center funding in MACRA for Community Health Centers but request you extend funds beyond 2017.

The Medicare Advantage Benchmark Cap - ACA SEC. 3201. (b) (4) By authorizing Quality Incentive Payments for MA plans with star ratings of 4 stars and above, Congress made a significant policy change towards value-based purchasing in the MA program.  If a plan is eligible for a Quality Incentive Payment, it receives it in the form of a 5 percent increase to its benchmark. However, Congress also authorized a new methodology for calculating benchmarks, and mandated that benchmarks under the new methodology cannot be greater than what they would have been under the old benchmark methodology.  This is the benchmark cap.  The benchmark cap reduces or even eliminates Quality Incentive Payments. The policy issue is that the cap weakens the incentive for plans to attain higher star ratings and undermines the shift towards paying for performance in the MA program.  We do not think that Congress intended to take away with one provision (the cap) the significant policy change towards paying for value that it enacted in the ACA. This change will have a significant negative impact on Medicare Advantage beneficiaries. Medicare Advantage benchmark cap legislation was introduced in December. H.R. 4275, the Medicare Advantage Quality Payment Relief Act of 2015, would remove the quality incentive payments from the calculation of the benchmark cap. Reps. Mike Kelly (R-PA), Ron Kind (D-WI), Brett Guthrie (R-KY) and Mike Doyle (D-PA) are the initial co-sponsors. 


Geographic Adjustment of Physician Payments - Recent findings by the Institute of Medicine and the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission have demonstrated significant shortcomings in the data utilized to geographically adjust physician payments.  The IOM and MedPAC studies have confirmed that the data sources currently relied upon for geographic adjustment bear no correlation to physician earnings.   CMS officials have admitted that the proxies utilized for the purpose of geographic adjustment have never been validated, and there never has been a new data source utilized in the twenty years since the fee schedule was implemented.  MedPAC data show that the geographic adjustment reference occupations predict earnings of rural physicians to be 25-30% less than physicians in metropolitan areas. MedPAC data show that earnings of primary care physicians in rural areas are, in fact, 13% higher than physicians in metropolitan areas.  Since there is no statistical basis of support for disparities in payment we strongly recommend that Congress require CMS to correct this inequity immediately.  Having a source of credible data and a sustainable payment mechanism is critical to maintaining access to primary care services in rural areas for patients who reside in those areas. 

Transparency     Marshfield Clinic supported provisions included in MACRA that would provide for greater access to Medicare claims data by modernizing and reforming the Qualified Entity (QE) program, which permits organizations to access and analyze Medicare data.

Telemedicine in Medicare 

Changes to Medicare law and regulation are needed to improve equity in access for Medicare beneficiaries to services delivered via TeleHealth. Medicare beneficiaries should be allowed to receive services in telemedicine sites located in urban areas.  The necessary changes would remove restrictions on originating sites by removing the rural requirement and the list of originating sites and allowing any certified Medicare facility to provide the services; current requirements that physician must bill for services from the originating site should be removed; restrictions on eligible practitioners should be removed to allow all Medicare approved practitioners to provide telemedicine services; and there should be no restrictions on which Medicare services may be provided through telemedicine.  
Recommendations: 
1.Amend the Medicare requirement for non-MSA geographic location of the patient to allow all Medicare certified organizations as originating sites regardless of rural or metropolitan statistical area designation.  

2.Alternative - amend the Medicare requirement for non-MSA geographic location of the patient to allow accountable care organizations to be exempt from the MSA requirement.  

Oral Health Coverage for the Medically Compromised and at Risk Populations  There is sufficient data that demonstrates oral health impacts the systemic health of the patient and in doing can reduce the cost of care.  Linkages that encourage patient compliance, patient education, provider education, and bi-directional referral and surveillance should be incented and compensated.   Shared savings demonstrations should be developed for health systems and co-pay incentives developed for patients engaging in and complying with such inter-disciplinary care.
</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Centers For Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS), Health &amp; Human Services - Dept of (HHS), Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (MedPAC)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Brent</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Miller</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>HCR</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>National Farm Safety

Support for occupational safety and health funding for Fiscal Year 2015.  The National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health (NIOSH) is the primary federal agency responsible for conducting research and making recommendations for the prevention of work-related illness and injury. NIOSH provides leadership to avert workplace illness, injury, disability, and death and supports programs to improve the health and safety of workers. NIOSH funds the National Childrens Center for Rural and Agricultural Health and Safety. Marshfield Clinic urges support for this important program.
Personalized (Precision) Medicine  

Personalized medicine, the tailoring of medical treatments to patient characteristics, relies upon the ability to classify individuals into subpopulations that differ in disease susceptibility and treatment responses. It allows clinicians to target preventive or therapeutic interventions on those who will benefit, and thereby to spare the expense and side effects of treatment for those who will not, thus making medicine more efficient. If the multiple population groups in the United States and elsewhere in the world are to benefit fully and fairly from such research, a national resource operated as a trust for the public good must be established to conduct a large population-based cohort study that includes full representation of minority populations. The Federal government should make critical investments in the enabling tools and resources essential to moving beyond genomic discoveries to personalized medicine services of patient and public benefit.
</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Natl Institutes of Health (NIH)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Brent</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Miller</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>VET</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>VA Choice program 

We have asked for assistance to resolve administrative problems with Health Net Federal Services in the VA Choice program. 
</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Veterans Affairs - Dept of (VA)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Brent</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Miller</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>MED</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Protecting Access to Medicare Act of 2014 (PAMA)
PAMA includes reforms to the Clinical Lab Fee Schedule (CLFS).  This proposed rule for PAMA.  MCHS requested a delay in this proposed rule, changes to expand the definition of applicable lab to represent the true market of all laboratories; requested greater transparency of calculations; more time to allow for gathering data and implementation. 
</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Centers For Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Brent</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Miller</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
  </alis>
  <updates>
    <clientAddress>
    </clientAddress>
    <clientCity>
    </clientCity>
    <clientState>
    </clientState>
    <clientZip>
    </clientZip>
    <clientZipext>
    </clientZipext>
    <clientCountry>
    </clientCountry>
    <prinClientCity>
    </prinClientCity>
    <prinClientState>
    </prinClientState>
    <prinClientZip>
    </prinClientZip>
    <prinClientZipext>
    </prinClientZipext>
    <prinClientCountry>
    </prinClientCountry>
    <generalDescription>
    </generalDescription>
    <inactive_lobbyists>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
    </inactive_lobbyists>
    <inactive_ALIs>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
    </inactive_ALIs>
    <affiliatedUrl>
    </affiliatedUrl>
    <affiliatedOrgs>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
    </affiliatedOrgs>
    <inactiveOrgs>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
    </inactiveOrgs>
    <foreignEntities>
      <foreignEntity>
        <name>
        </name>
        <address>
        </address>
        <city>
        </city>
        <state>
        </state>
        <country>
        </country>
        <prinCity>
        </prinCity>
        <prinState>
        </prinState>
        <prinCountry>
        </prinCountry>
        <contribution>
        </contribution>
        <ownership_Percentage>
        </ownership_Percentage>
      </foreignEntity>
    </foreignEntities>
    <inactive_ForeignEntities>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
    </inactive_ForeignEntities>
  </updates>
</LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>