<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='../../ld2webpage.xsl'?>
<LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>
  <imported>Y</imported>
  <pages>5</pages>
  <submitURL>
  </submitURL>
  <organizationName>NATIONAL AFFORDABLE HOUSING MANAGEMENT ASSOCIATION (NAHMA)</organizationName>
  <prefix>
  </prefix>
  <firstName>
  </firstName>
  <lastName>
  </lastName>
  <registrantDifferentAddress>N</registrantDifferentAddress>
  <address1>400 NORTH COLUMBUS STREET, #203</address1>
  <address2>
  </address2>
  <city>ALEXANDRIA</city>
  <state>VA</state>
  <zip>22314</zip>
  <zipext>
  </zipext>
  <country>USA</country>
  <principal_city>
  </principal_city>
  <principal_state>
  </principal_state>
  <principal_zip>
  </principal_zip>
  <principal_zipext>
  </principal_zipext>
  <principal_country>
  </principal_country>
  <contactIntlPhone>
  </contactIntlPhone>
  <selfSelect>Y</selfSelect>
  <clientName>NATIONAL AFFORDABLE HOUSING MANAGEMENT ASSOCIATION (NAHMA)</clientName>
  <clientGovtEntity>N</clientGovtEntity>
  <senateID>46324-12</senateID>
  <houseID>341440000</houseID>
  <reportYear>2016</reportYear>
  <reportType>Q1</reportType>
  <terminationDate>
  </terminationDate>
  <noLobbying>
  </noLobbying>
  <income>
  </income>
  <expenses>130000.00</expenses>
  <expensesMethod>A</expensesMethod>
  <printedName>KRISTINA C. COOK</printedName>
  <signedDate>4/15/2016 1:01:36 PM</signedDate>
  <alis>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>HOU</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Public Law (P.L.) 114-94 (H.R. 22): Fixing Americas Surface Transportation (FAST) Act. Housing provisions included in House Amendment 827. 

P.L. 114-74 (H.R. 1314): the Bipartisan Budget Act of 2015. A two-year budget deal that suspended the federal borrowing cap until March 16, 2017; all provisions. 

P.L. 114-96 (H.R. 2250): Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2015. This bill provided an additional temporary extension for FY 2016 funding at the same funding level as FY 2015 with an expiration date of December 16, 2015; all provisions 

P.L. 114-113 (H.R. 2029): Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016. Omnibus bill providing appropriations for the remainder of FY 2016; provisions under Division L, Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016: Title II - Department of Housing and Urban Development, Division A, Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016: Title III - Rural Development Programs, and Division Q, Protecting Americans from Tax Hikes Act, 2016: Part IV - Incentives for Real Estate Investment, Section 131 Extension of minimum low-income housing tax credit rate for non-Federally subsidized buildings. 

P.L. 114-53 (H.R. 719): Continuing appropriations Act, 2016. This bill is a temporary continuing resolution (CR) which funded the federal government for fiscal year (FY) 2016 at the same funding as FY 2015 until December 11, 2015; provisions related to (Sec. 117): Provides USDA with funding flexibility to pay ongoing debt service for multi-family direct loan program rental assistance contracts under sections 514 and 515 of the Housing Act of 1949. Permits the renewal during the duration of the CR of rental assistance contracts entered into or renewed in 2015 that exhausted funds within the 12-month contract period. 

P.L. 113-235 (H.R. 83): the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2014; all provisions relating to funding for federal affordable housing programs in FY 2015. 

H.R. 4888: The Ending Homelessness Act of 2016. This bill seeks to provide resources to end homelessness in America through $13.27 billion in emergency funding over the next five years. H.R. 4888 would also implement strategies for outreach and case management, as well as technical assistance to help states and local jurisdictions better align their healthcare and housing; all provisions.

H.R. 4753: The Wounded Warrior Housing Reform Act of 2016. This bill would exclude Service-connected disability compensation, and pensions paid to a veteran age 65 or older from consideration as income for affordable housing programs; all provisions. 

H.R. 3700: Housing Opportunity through Modernization Act of 2015. This bill incorporates different housing reform bills introduced in the 114th Congress: The Preservation Enhancement and Savings Opportunity Act of 2015 (H.R. 2482), The Private Investment in Housing Act (H.R. 2997). It includes a drafted bill from the 113th Congress which has not been formally introduced, the Affordable Housing and Self-Sufficiency Improvement Act of 2012 (AHSSIA); all provisions 

H.R. 3697: The Section 3 Modernization and Improvement Act of 2015. This bill aims to increase enforcement and Congressional oversight of Section 3 properties; all provisions 

H.R. 2482: Preservation Enhancement and Savings Opportunity Act of 2015. This bill amends and eliminates certain owner limitations under the Low-Income Housing Preservation and Resident Homeownership Act of 1990 (LIHPRHA). 

H.R. 2997: Private Investment in Housing Act, 2015. This bill would allow HUD to establish a demonstration program under which, in FY 2016 through FY 2019, HUD may execute budget-neutral, performance-based agreements (for up to 12 years each) that result in a reduction in energy or water costs; all provisions 

H.R. 1047: Housing Assistance Efficiency Act of 2015. This bill would amend the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act to allow a private nonprofit organization to administer permanent housing rental assistance provided through the Continuum of Care Program; all provisions 

H.R. 233: The Tenant Income Verification Relief Act of 2015. This bill would allow income reviews for fixed-income families to be completed every three years rather than the current annual inspection used to determine assisted housing program eligibility; all provisions 

S. 2012: Energy Policy Modernization Act of 2015. This bill would create a demonstration program under which the Secretary of HUD may enter into agreements with multifamily property owners that result in a reduction in energy or water costs; all provisions 

S. 1412: Housing for Homeless Students Act of 2015. A bill to qualify homeless youth and veterans who are full-time students for purposes of the low income housing tax credit; all provisions 

S.1139: Improving the Low Income Housing Tax Credit Rate Act of 2015. This bill would make permanent a 9 percent minimum rate for new housing projects and a 4 percent rate for acquiring existing housing for rehabilitation; all provisions 

S.1909: Local Zoning Decisions Protection Act, 2015. A bill which would prevent any federal funding for implementing HUDs final rule Affirmatively Furthering Fair Housing; all provisions 

H.R. 1142: To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make permanent and expand the temporary minimum credit rate for the low-income housing tax credit. This bill would make permanent a 9 percent minimum rate for new housing projects and 4 percent rate for acquiring existing housing for rehabilitation; all provisions 

H.R. 1995: the Local Zoning and Property Rights Protection Act of 2015. This bill would prohibit HUD from implementing its proposed rule entitled Affirmatively Furthering Fair Housing; all provisions 

HUD Notice: Announcement of Tenant Protection Voucher Funding Awards for Fiscal Year 2015 for the Housing Choice Voucher Program [Docket No. FR-5937-FA-01] March 29, 2016; all provisions 

HUD FY 2016 Median Family Income estimates and FY 2016 Income Limits March 28, 2016. 

HUD Notice PIH 2016-04: Implementation of the Federal Fiscal Year (FFY) 2016 Funding Provisions for the Housing Choice Voucher Program March 10, 2016; all provisions

HUD Notice PIH 2016-02 (HA): Enhanced Voucher Requirements for Over-housed Families March 4, 2016; all provisions

HUD Notice: Family Self Sufficiency Program in Multifamily March 15, 2016; all provisions

HUD Proposed Rule Section 542(c) Housing Finance Agencies Risk-Sharing Program: Revisions to Regulations [Docket No FR-5881-P-01] March 8, 2016; all provisions relating to affordable, multifamily housing property mortgages.

HUD Final Rule: "Streamlining Administrative Regulations for the Public Housing, Housing Choice Voucher, Multifamily Housing, and Community Planning and Development Programs" [Docket No. FR 5743-F-03] March 1, 2016; all provisions and previously proposed rule

HUD Section 8 Renewal Policy Guide, Chapter 9: Rent Comparability Studies revision draft February 23, 2016; all provisions

Department of Justice, Office for Victims of Crime report: Federal Strategic Action Plan on Services for Victims of Human Trafficking in the United States 2013-2017; provisions relating to housing assistance for human trafficking victims; advised members of NAHMA to participate in a conference call between HUD and the Department of Health and Human Services on the intersection of human trafficking and the need for housing and social services for survivors - February 24, 2016. 
HUD Memorandum New UPCS Inspector Protocol Conferencing Bed Bug Infestation February 1, 2016; all provisions

HUD Memorandum Renewal of Expiring Project Assistance Contracts (PACs) Under the Section 202 Program of Supportive Housing for the Elderly and for Persons with Disabilities for Fiscal Year (FY 2016) January 5, 2016; all provisions

HUD Notice H 2016-01: Passbook Savings Rate Effective February 1, 2016 January 19, 2016; all provisions relating to the passbook savings rate, which is used to determine annual income from net family assets.

HUD Notice of Funding Availability (NOFA): Supportive Services Demonstration for Elderly Households in HUD-Assisted Multifamily Housing demonstration project January 20, 2016; all provisions relating to eligible owners of HUD-assisted senior housing developments to access funding that will cover the cost of a full-time enhanced service coordinator and a part-time wellness nurse

HUD Notice PIH 2016-01: Family Unification Program and Family Self Sufficiency Demonstration January 15, 2016; all provisions relating to Public Housing Agencies (PHAs) opportunity to participate in a demonstration testing the effectiveness of combining housing choice vouchers for eligible youth with assistance under the Family Self Sufficiency program.
 
HUD National Disaster Resilience Competition (NDRC); all provisions relating to housing and infrastructure projects in states and communities that were impacted by major disasters between 2011 and 2013.

Security and Exchange Commission Notice [Release No. 34-76148; File No. SR-FINRA-2015-036]: "Self-Regulatory Organizations; Financial Industry Regulatory Authority, Inc.; Notice of Filing of a Proposed Rule Change To Amend FINRA Rule 4210 (Margin Requirements) To Establish Margin Requirements for the TBA Market" October 14, 2015; all provisions relating to the coverage of multifamily agency forward-settling transactions in the multifamily financing market. 

Federal Housing Finance Agency Notice for Proposed Rulemaking: Enterprise Duty To Serve Underserved Markets, December 18, 2015 - 12 CFR Part 1282 [RIN 2590-AA27]; all provisions 

HUD Notice of Final Fiscal Year (FY) 2016 Fair Market Rents (FMRs) [Docket No. FR-5885-N-02]: "Final Fair Market Rents for the Housing Choice Voucher Program and Moderate Rehabilitation Single Room Occupancy Program and Other Programs Fiscal Year 2016" December 11, 2015; all provisions 

HUD Proposed Rule [Docket No. FR-5248-P-01] RIN 2529-AA94: "Quid Pro Quo and Hostile Environment Harassment and Liability for Discriminatory Housing Practices Under the Fair Housing Act" October 21, 2015; all provisions 

HUD Notice H 2015-10: "Guidance for Public Housing Agencies (PHAs) and Owners of Federally-Assisted Housing on Excluding the Use of Arrest Records in Housing Decisions" November 2, 2015; all provisions 

HUD Notice PIH 2015-19: "Guidance for Public Housing Agencies (PHAs) and Owners of Federally-Assisted Housing on Excluding the Use of Arrest Records in Housing Decisions" November 2, 2015; all provisions 

HUD Guide: Rental Assistance Demonstration (RAD), Quick Reference Guide to Multifamily Housing Requirements, October 2015; all provisions 

HUD Notice [Docket No. FR-5883-N-01]: "Notice of Certain Operating Cost Adjustment Factors for 2016" October 13, 2015; all provisions impacting project based assistance contracts for eligible multifamily housing projects. 

President Obama Executive Order 13690: The Federal Flood Risk Management Standard for federal agencies; all provisions which impact multifamily housing properties financed through the Federal Housing Administration (FHA) 

HUD Advanced Notice of Proposed Rulemaking [Docket No. FR-5855-A-01]: Establishing a More Effective Fair Market Rent (FMR) System; Using Small Area Fair Market Rents (SAFMRs) in Housing Choice Voucher Program Instead of the Current 50th Percentile FMRs; all provisions 

HUD Final Notice [Docket No. FR-5728-N-02]: Federal Housing Administration (FHA): Small Building Risk Sharing Initiative; all provisions 

HUD Final Rule: Affirmatively Furthering Fair Housing [Docket No. FR-5173-F-04] RIN 2501-AD33; all provisions 

HUD Transmittal issued 8/7/15: Section 8 Renewal Policy Guidebook; all sections 

HUD Initiative "Transforming Multifamily for the 21st Century"; all provisions. 

HUD Draft FHA Multifamily Accelerated Processing (MAP) Guide; all provisions relating to federally assisted multifamily housing in chapters 1.5, 3, 3.6.C, 3.7.V, 3.8, 5, 5.2, 5.3, 5.10.L.5, 7.1, 7.8, 14.7, 18.3. 

HUD Memorandum: "Age Restrictions in FHA Insured Housing"; all provisions. 

HUD Notice PIH 2012-32 (HA), REV-2, Rental Assistance Demonstration - Final Implementation, Revision 2 June 15, 2015; all provisions. 

HUD Proposed Rule, "Supportive Housing and Services for the Elderly and Persons With Disabilities: Implementing Statutory Reforms-Reopening of Public Comment" [Docket No. FR-5576-N-02], Dec 11, 2014; all provisions. 

HUD Memorandum, "Occupancy Protections for HUD-Assisted Households in Properties with Low-Income Housing Tax Credits" January 12, 2015; all provisions. 

HUD Notice, "Enforcement of Davis-Bacon Act wage requirements for projects participating in the second component of the Rental Assistance Demonstration program" December 23, 2015; all provisions. 

HUD Notice, "Violence Against Women Reauthorization Act of 2013: Implementation in HUD Housing Programs" [Docket No. FR-5720-P-02] March 25, 2015; all provisions of this HUD regulation, with emphasis on language concerning emergency housing transfers for victims of domestic violence claiming protection under VAWA. 

Final ruling and opinion in the Supreme Court case Texas Department of Housing and Community Affairs v. The Inclusive Communities Project, Inc. 

Policies relating to affordable housing development in housing finance reform efforts in Congress. 

All policies relating to the expansion of the Low-Income Housing Tax Credit (LIHTC) 

All policies relating to HUD inspection protocol UPCS-V

All policies relating to Housing Assistance Payments (HAP) Contracts 

All policies relating to Project Rental Assistance Contracts (PRACs) and strategies to preserve properties in this portfolio. 

All policies relating to funding and administration of the Housing Trust Fund. 

All policies and funding grants relating to the managing of lead-based paint at multifamily properties. 

All policies relating to the release and implementation of the Affirmatively Furthering Fair Housing rule from HUD. 

All policies relating to Performance-Based Contract Administration. 

All policies relating to the resumption of Management and Occupancy Reviews (MORs). 

Policies relating to student occupancy requirements in properties assisted through HUD or the Low-Income Housing Tax Credit. 

Policies relating to Fair Value Accounting in federal estimates of housing programs. 

Department of Agriculture, Rural Housing Service Notice: Notice of Solicitation of Applications for the Section 533 Housing Preservation Grants for Fiscal Year 2016; all provisions 

Rural Development unnumbered Letter dated March 18, 2016: Rental Assistance Obligation Tool; all provisions.

Rural Development Administrative Notice dated February 5, 2016: Fiscal Year 2016 Site Manager and Maintenance Person of the Year Recognition Program; all provisions 

Rural Housing Service Notice: Notice of Solicitation of Applications for the Section 533 Housing Preservation Grants for Fiscal Year 2016 December 29, 2015; all provisions.

Policies relating to USDA-RHS' Section 521 Rental Assistance; non-payment of rental assistance contracts in FY 2015 and initial months of FY 2016.

Policies relating to the preservation of properties financed with mortgages from the Section 515 program; advocated for non-burdensome actions that will allow properties to either be acquired by new ownership or to refinance so that they may continue to receive Section 521 Rental Assistance

Policies relating to management fee adjustments in Rural Development from 2010 to 2016; provisions relating of implementation of Operating Cost Adjustment Factors (OCAF) method. 

Offered recommendations in response to USDA-RHS' informal request for ideas to implement a performance-based management fee for apartments that receive Rural Rental Assistance. 

Advocated for policies to address ongoing occupancy issues, including prolonged vacancies, in properties that participate in USDA-RHS's Multifamily Housing programs. 

Advocated for policies to address improper payments in USDA-RHS's Section 521 Rural Rental Assistance program. 

All policies related to USDA Rural Development's Improper Payments Information Act (IPIA) audit for the Rental Assistance Program, Multi-Family Integrated System and its findings reviews, and rural housing preservation. 
</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Agriculture - Dept of  (USDA), Housing &amp; Urban Development - Dept of (HUD), Internal Revenue Service (IRS), Treasury - Dept of, Executive Office of the President (EOP), White House Office, Office of Management &amp; Budget (OMB)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kris</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Cook</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Scott</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>McMillen</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Larry</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Keys</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>Jr.</lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>Y</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>BUD</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Budget of the United States Government, Fiscal Year 2017, February 9, 2016. Contains the Budget Request of the President to the United States Congress, including information on the Presidents priorities for fiscal year 2017; provisions under Department of Housing and Urban Development section of appendix, including: Tenant-Based Rental Assistance, Project-Based Rental Assistance, Section 202 Housing for the Elderly, Section 811 Housing for Persons with Disabilities, Community Development Fund, and Home Investment Partnerships Program; provisions under Department of Agriculture section of appendix , including: Section 521 Rental Assistance, Section 515, Section 538 Loan Level, and the Multifamily Revitalization program with emphasis on Rural Housing Vouchers. 
House of Representatives budget for fiscal year 2017: A Balanced Budget for a Stronger America, March 15, 2016; provisions relating to the Community Development Block Grant and targeted funding levels for FY 2017. 

P.L. 114-74 (H.R. 1314): the Bipartisan Budget Act of 2015. A two-year budget deal that suspended the federal borrowing cap until March 16, 2017; all provisions.

P.L. 114-96 (H.R. 2250): Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2015. This bill provided an additional temporary extension for fiscal year (FY) 2016 funding at the same funding level as FY 2015 with an expiration date of December 16, 2015; all provisions 

P.L. 114-113 (H.R. 2029): Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016. Omnibus bill providing appropriations for the remainder of FY 2016; provisions under Division L, Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016: Title II - Department of Housing and Urban Development, Division A, Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016: Title III - Rural Development Programs, and Division Q, Protecting Americans from Tax Hikes Act, 2016: Part IV - Incentives for Real Estate Investment, Section 131 Extension of minimum low-income housing tax credit rate for non-Federally subsidized buildings.

P.L. 114-53 (H.R. 719): Continuing appropriations Act, 2016. This bill is a temporary continuing resolution (CR) which funded the federal government for fiscal year (FY) 2016 at the same funding as FY 2015 until December 11, 2015; provisions related to (Sec. 117): Provides USDA with funding flexibility to pay ongoing debt service for multi-family direct loan program rental assistance contracts under sections 514 and 515 of the Housing Act of 1949. Permits the renewal during the duration of the CR of rental assistance contracts entered into or renewed in 2015 that exhausted funds within the 12-month contract period.

Advocated for comprehensive budget agreement to lift current spending caps mandated by the Budget Control Act, 2011.

Public Law (PL) No: 114-53 (H.R. 719): Continuing appropriations Act, 2016. This bill is a temporary continuing resolution (CR) which will fund the federal government for fiscal year (FY) 2016 at the same funding as FY 2015 until December 11, 2015; provisions related to (Sec. 117): Provides USDA with funding flexibility to pay ongoing debt service for multi-family direct loan program rental assistance contracts under sections 514 and 515 of the Housing Act of 1949. Permits the renewal during the duration of the CR of rental assistance contracts entered into or renewed in 2015 that exhausted funds within the 12-month contract period.

Budget of the United States Government, Fiscal Year 2016; all provisions relating to the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) -Rural Housing Service (RHS) funding and administration of affordable multifamily housing and rental assistance programs and Treasury-Internal Revenue Service (IRS) proposals related to the Low Income Housing Tax Credit(LIHTC)&amp; bond-financed multifamily housing programs.

S.Con.Res.11, "An original concurrent resolution setting forth the congressional budget for the United States Government for fiscal year 2016 and setting forth the appropriate budgetary levels for fiscal years 2017 through 2025", March 20, 2015; all provisions relating to the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) -Rural Housing Service (RHS) funding and administration of affordable multifamily housing and rental assistance programs and Treasury-Internal Revenue Service (IRS) proposals related to the Low Income Housing Tax Credit(LIHTC)&amp; bond-financed multifamily housing programs.

H.Con.Res.27, "Establishing the budget for the United States Government for fiscal year 2016 and setting forth appropriate budgetary levels for fiscal years 2017 through 2025", March 20, 2015; all provisions relating to the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) -Rural Housing Service (RHS) funding and administration of affordable multifamily housing and rental assistance programs and Treasury-Internal Revenue Service (IRS) proposals related to the Low Income Housing Tax Credit(LIHTC)&amp; bond-financed multifamily housing programs.

H.R. 2577: Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016; all provisions related to the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) 
Senate Subcommittee Draft: Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016; all provisions related to the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) 

H.R. 3049: Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 (House). TITLE III-all provisions concerning Rural Housing Service affordable multifamily housing &amp; rental assistance programs 

S. 1800: Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 (Senate). TITLE III-all provisions concerning Rural Housing Service affordable multifamily housing &amp; rental assistance programs
</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Housing &amp; Urban Development - Dept of (HUD), Agriculture - Dept of  (USDA), Internal Revenue Service (IRS), Treasury - Dept of</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kris</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Cook</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Scott</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>McMillen</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Larry</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Keys</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>Jr.</lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>TAX</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Internal Revenue Service Final and Temporary Regulations: Utility Allowance Submetering March 3, 2016 - 26 CFR Part 1 [TD 9755] RIN 1545-BI91; all provisions relating to policies that amend the utility allowance regulations for the Low-Income Housing Tax Credit (LIHTC).

Internal Revenue Service Final and Temporary Regulations: Amendments to the Low-Income Housing Credit Compliance-Monitoring Regulations February 25, 2016 - 26 CFR Part 1 [TD 9753] RIN 1545-BL84; all provisions relating to the minimum number of units for which an agency must conduct physical inspections and low-income certifications. 

Office of Senator Maria Cantwell Addressing the Challenges of Affordable Housing and Homelessness: the Housing Tax Credit - a report detailing LIHTC usage and access for low-income families in the state of Washington and nationally. 

P.L. 114-113 (H.R. 2029): Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016. Omnibus bill providing appropriations for the remainder of FY 2016; provisions under Division L, Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016: Title II - Department of Housing and Urban Development, Division A, Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016: Title III - Rural Development Programs, and Division Q, Protecting Americans from Tax Hikes Act, 2016: Part IV - Incentives for Real Estate Investment, Section 131 Extension of minimum low-income housing tax credit rate for non-Federally subsidized buildings. 

Internal Revenue Service Memo [UIL 42.07.04]: Low-income Housing Credit (LIHC) - Noncompliance Resulting from Conflicting Program Requirements; all provisions

Revenue Ruling 2015-15 Appropriate Percentages Under Section 42(b)(1) for July 2015; all provisions  

S. 1139: Improving the Low-Income Housing Tax Credit Rate Act. A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make permanent the minimum low-income housing tax credit rate for unsubsidized buildings and to provide a minimum 4 percent credit rate for existing buildings; all provisions. 

H.R.1142: To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make permanent and expand the temporary minimum credit rate for the low-income housing tax credit program; all provisions. 

S.2260: Expiring Provisions Improvement, Reform, and Efficiency (EXPIRE) Act of 2014. TITLE I, Subtitle B, Sec. 112-Extension and modification of temporary minimum low-income housing tax credit rate for non-federally subsidized buildings; all provisions. 

H.R. 5771: Tax Increase Prevention Act of 2014. Division A Title 1 Sec. 112. Extension of temporary minimum low-income housing tax credit rate for non-federally subsidized buildings; all provisions. 

HUD Memorandum, "Occupancy Protections for HUD-Assisted Households in Properties with Low-Income Housing Tax Credits" January 12, 2015; all provisions 

Department of Treasury Notice 2015-27, "Public Comment Invited on Recommendations for 2015-2016 Priority Guidance Plan" 

Submitted recommendations for tax reform in the United States to the Senate Finance Committee; provisions related to the low-income housing tax credit.
</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Internal Revenue Service (IRS), Treasury - Dept of, Agriculture - Dept of  (USDA), Housing &amp; Urban Development - Dept of (HUD)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kris</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Cook</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Scott</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>McMillen</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Larry</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Keys</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>Jr.</lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
  </alis>
  <updates>
    <clientAddress>
    </clientAddress>
    <clientCity>
    </clientCity>
    <clientState>
    </clientState>
    <clientZip>
    </clientZip>
    <clientZipext>
    </clientZipext>
    <clientCountry>
    </clientCountry>
    <prinClientCity>
    </prinClientCity>
    <prinClientState>
    </prinClientState>
    <prinClientZip>
    </prinClientZip>
    <prinClientZipext>
    </prinClientZipext>
    <prinClientCountry>
    </prinClientCountry>
    <generalDescription>
    </generalDescription>
    <inactive_lobbyists>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
    </inactive_lobbyists>
    <inactive_ALIs>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
    </inactive_ALIs>
    <affiliatedUrl>
    </affiliatedUrl>
    <affiliatedOrgs>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>Southeastern Affordable Housing Management Association (SAHMA) </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>5570-J Tulane Dr. SW</affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>Atlanta</affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>GA</affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>30336</affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>USA</affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
    </affiliatedOrgs>
    <inactiveOrgs>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
    </inactiveOrgs>
    <foreignEntities>
      <foreignEntity>
        <name>
        </name>
        <address>
        </address>
        <city>
        </city>
        <state>
        </state>
        <country>
        </country>
        <prinCity>
        </prinCity>
        <prinState>
        </prinState>
        <prinCountry>
        </prinCountry>
        <contribution>
        </contribution>
        <ownership_Percentage>
        </ownership_Percentage>
      </foreignEntity>
    </foreignEntities>
    <inactive_ForeignEntities>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
    </inactive_ForeignEntities>
  </updates>
</LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>