<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='../../ld2webpage.xsl'?>
<LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>
  <imported>Y</imported>
  <pages>6</pages>
  <submitURL>
  </submitURL>
  <organizationName>National Rifle Association of America</organizationName>
  <prefix>
  </prefix>
  <firstName>
  </firstName>
  <lastName>
  </lastName>
  <registrantDifferentAddress>N</registrantDifferentAddress>
  <address1>11250 WAPLES MILL ROAD</address1>
  <address2>
  </address2>
  <city>FAIRFAX</city>
  <state>VA</state>
  <zip>22030</zip>
  <zipext>
  </zipext>
  <country>USA</country>
  <principal_city>
  </principal_city>
  <principal_state>
  </principal_state>
  <principal_zip>
  </principal_zip>
  <principal_zipext>
  </principal_zipext>
  <principal_country>
  </principal_country>
  <contactIntlPhone>
  </contactIntlPhone>
  <selfSelect>Y</selfSelect>
  <clientName>National Rifle Association of America</clientName>
  <clientGovtEntity>N</clientGovtEntity>
  <senateID>28470-12</senateID>
  <houseID>310760000</houseID>
  <reportYear>2016</reportYear>
  <reportType>Q1</reportType>
  <terminationDate>
  </terminationDate>
  <noLobbying>
  </noLobbying>
  <income>
  </income>
  <expenses>635000.00</expenses>
  <expensesMethod>A</expensesMethod>
  <printedName>Mary Rose Adkins</printedName>
  <signedDate>4/18/2016 11:38:26 AM</signedDate>
  <alis>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>CIV</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>H.R. 766; Financial Institution Customer Protection Act of 2015 - Prohibits a federal banking agency from formally or informally suggesting, requesting, or ordering a depository institution to terminate either a specific customer account, or group of customer accounts, or otherwise restrict or discourage it from entering into or maintaining a banking relationship with a specific customer or group of customers, unless: (1) the agency has a material reason to do so, and (2) the reason is not based solely on reputation risk.

H.R. 1076 &amp; S. 551; Denying Firearms and Explosives to Dangerous Terrorist Act of 2015 - Amends the federal criminal code to grant the Attorney General the authority to deny the transfer of firearms or the issuance of a federal firearms and explosives license to any individual if the Attorney General: (1) determines that such individual has been engaged in or has provided material support or resources for terrorist activities, and (2) has reasonable belief that such individual may use a firearm or explosive in connection with terrorism.  Allows any individual whose firearm or explosives license application has been denied to bring legal action challenging the denial.

H.R. 1217; Public Safety and Second Amendment Rights Protection Act of 2015 - Amends the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act to reauthorize for FY2016-FY2019 the grant program for improvements to the criminal history record system.

H.R. 1413 &amp; S. 477; Firearms Manufacturers and Dealers Protection Act of 2015 - Funds appropriated or otherwise made available, including amounts derived from any fee or other source, are denied to the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Department of Justice, or any other federal agency to carry out Operation Choke Point or any other program designed to discourage the provision or continuation of credit or the processing of payments by financial institutions for dealers and manufacturers of firearms and ammuntion.

H.R. 1488; Protecting Gun Owners in Bankruptcy Act of 2015 - Amends federal bankruptcy law to permit an individual debtor to exempt from the property of the estate in bankruptcy the debtor's aggregate interest, not to exceed $3,000, in a single firearm or firearms.

H.R. 1701 &amp; S.874; Second Amendment Enforcement Act of 2015 - To restore Second Amendment rights in the District of Columbia.

H.R. 2001; Veterans 2nd Amendment Protection Act - To amend title 38, United States Code, to clarify the conditions under which certain persons may be treated as adjudicated mentally incompetent for certain purposes.

H.R. 2259; Protect Our Military Families' 2nd Amendment Rights Act - To amend chapter 44 of title 18, United States Code, to provide that a member of the armed forces and the spouse of that member shall have the same rights regarding the receipt of firearms at the location of any duty station of the member.

H.R. 2578; Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 - Making appropriations for the Departments of Commerce and Justice, Science, and Related Agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2016, and for other purposes.

H.R. 3126; To prohibit the Commissioner of Social Security from furnishing the name of any individual in a report to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System unless a Federal court has determined the individual to be mentally defective.

H.R. 3138; Military Recruiter Right to Carry Act of 2015 - To recognize the right of members of the Armed Forces assigned to duty at Armed Forces recruitment offices to carry a personal or service-issue firearm at the office.

H.R. 3139 &amp; S. 1821; SEMPER FI Act - To improve security at Armed Forces recruitment centers.

H.R. 3146; Military Base Self-Defense Act - To safeguard military and civilian personnel on military bases by repealing bans on military personnel carrying firearms, and for other purposes.

H.R. 3227; Protecting America's Warriors Act - To protect the Second Amendment rights of members of the Armed Forces and civilian employees of the Department of Defense trained in the use of firearms to carry officially-issued or personally-owned firearms on military installations in the United States.

H.R. 3239; Armed Forces Career Center Protection Act - To provide enhanced security at Armed Forces recruitment centers through the installation of reinforced bullet-proof glass and entry doors.

H.R. 3485; 50l(c)(4) Reform Act of 2015 - To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to prohibit 50l(c)(4) entities from participating in, or intervening in (including the publishing or distributing of statements), any political campaign.

H.R. 3516; Social Security Beneficiary 2nd Amendment Rights Protection Act - To amend the Social Security Act relating to the use of determination made by the Commissioner.

H.R. 3722; Mental Health and Safe Communities Act of 2015, To strengthen our mental health system and improve public safety.

H.R. 4026; TSA Act, To provide that a concealed handgun license shall be treated as a verifying identity document for purposes of aircraft passenger security screening, and to prohibit the Federal Government from collecting or storing information about an individual relating to a concealed handgun license.

H.R. 4319; Second Amendment Defense Act of 2016 - This bill prohibits a federal government officer or employee from taking an action that limits an individual's conduct related to firearms or ammunition that is more restrictive than limitations in effect as of January 3, 2016.

H.R. 4320; NICS Denial Notification Act of 2016 - To provide for the reporting to State and local law enforcement authorities of cases in which the national instant criminal background check system indicates that a firearm has been sought to be acquired by a prohibited person, so that authorities may pursue criminal charges under State law, and to ensure that the Department of Justice reports to Congress on charges brought and prosecutions secured against prohibited persons who attempt to acquire a firearms.

H.R. 4321; Separation of Powers Restoration and Second Amendment Protection Act - To provide that any executive action that infringes on the powers and duties of Congress under section 8 of article I of the Constitution of the United States or on the Second Amendment to the Constitution of the United States has no force or effect, and to prohibit the use of funds for certain purposes.

H.R. 4348; DC Personal Protection Reciprocity Act - To require reciprocity between the District of Columbia and other States and jurisdictions with respect to the ability of individuals to carry certain concealed firearms, and for other purposes.

H.R. 4379; Defending Gun Rights Against Executive Overreach Act - To prohibit the use of Federal funds to further restrict conduct in relation to firearms.

H.R. 4781; FDIC Accountability Act of 2016 - To amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to make certain functions of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation subject to appropriations.

H.Amdt. 947 to H.R. 2406; Amendment sought to prohibit an individual who is prohibited from possessing a firearm by the Gun Control Act from using a public target range.

S. 1123; USA FREEDOM Act of 2015 - To reform the authorities of the Federal Government to require the production of certain business records, conduct electronic surveillance, use pen registers and trap and trace devices, and use other forms of information gathering for foreign intelligence, counterterrorism, and criminal purposes, and for other purposes.

S. 1815; A bill to require a process by which members of the Armed Forces may carry a concealed personal firearm on a military installation.

S. 1819; Semper Fi Act, To improve security at Armed Forces recruitment centers.

S. 1821; Armed Forces Self-Defense Act - To permit service members to carry firearms on military installations, including reserve centers and recruitment offices.

S. 1823; A bill to safeguard military personnel on Armed Forces military installations by repealing bans on military personnel carrying firearms, and for other purposes.

S. 1835; Military Facilities Force Protection Act of 2015 - To enhance military facilities force protection.

S. 1839; Servicemembers Self-Defense Act of 2015 - To amend title 10 and 18, to permit members of the Armed Forces to possess firearms on military installations in accordance with applicable State law, and for other purposes.

S. 1988; Enhancing Security for Military Personnel Act of 2015 - To enhance the security of military personnel at United States military installations and operating locations.

S. 1992; Protect Our Military Families' 2nd Amendment Rights Act - To amend chapter 44 of title 18, United States Code, to provide that a member of the Armed Forces and the spouse of that member shall have the same rights regarding the receipt of firearms at the location of any duty station of the member.

S. 2209; Lawful Purpose and Self Defense Act, To revise various laws that interfere with the right of the people to obtain and use firearms for all lawful purposes.

S. 2359; Defend Our Capital Act of 2015, To restore Second Amendment rights in the District of Columbia.

S. 2434; Separation of Powers Restoration and Second Amendment Protection Act, To provide that any executive action that infringes on theh powers and duties of Congress under section 8 of article I of the Constitution of the United States or on the Second Amendment to the Constitution of the United States has no force or effect, and to prohibit the use of funds for certain purposes.

S. 2495; Social Security Beneficiary 2nd Amendment Rights Protection Act - This bill amends titles II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) and XVI (Supplemental Security Income) (SSI) Social Security Act to prohibit any determination by the Commissioner of Social Security with respect to an individual, including one that OASDI and SSI benefits to which that individual is entitled shall be paid to a representative payee, from being considered to be a determination that the individual has been adjudicated as a mental defective to make it unlawful for the individual to engage in the shipment or transport of firearms or ammunition or receive any firearm or ammunition which has been shipped or transported in interstate or foreign commerce.

S.Amdt. 2915 to S.Amdt. 2874, To restore Second Amendment rights in the District of Columbia.

</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Bureau of Alcohol Tobacco Firearms &amp; Explosives</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Todd</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Adkins</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>James</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Atkinson</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Brian</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Calabrese</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Benjamin</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Cassidy</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Chris W.</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Cox</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>James </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Holland</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Wayne</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>LaPierre</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jason</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Lawrence</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>David</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Lehman</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jason</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Ouimet</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Brandi</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Pensoneau</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jack</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Thompson</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Christopher</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Zealand</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>FIR</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>H.R. 752 &amp; S. 407; Large Capacity Ammunition Feeding Device Act - To prohibit the transfer or possession of large capacity ammunition feeding devices, and for other purposes.

H.R. 1365; Ammunition and Firearms Protection Act - To prevent the reclassification of certain ammunition as armor piercing ammunition.

H.R. 2613 &amp; S. 1474; Handgun Trigger Safety Act of 2015 - To provide for the development and use of technology for personalized handguns, to require that all handguns manufactured or sold in, or imported into the United States incorporate such technology, and for other purposes.

H.R. 2699 &amp; S. 1735; Undetectable Firearms Modernization Act of 2015 - To modernize the Undetectable Firearms Act of 1988.

H.R. 3802; Alternative Ammunition Manufacturing Act, To amend title 18, United States Code to provide for the disposition, within 60 days, of an application to exempt a projectile from classification as armor piercing ammunition.

S. 2444; Alternative Ammunition Manufacturing Act - To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide for the disposition, within 60 days, of an application to exempt a projectile from classification as armor piercing ammunition.
</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Todd</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Adkins</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>James</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Atkinson</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Brian</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Calabrese</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Benjamin</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Cassidy</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Chris W. </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Cox</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>James</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Holland</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Wayne</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>LaPierre</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jason</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Lawrence</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>David</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Lehman</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jason</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Ouimet</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Brandi</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Pensoneau</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jack</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Thompson</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Christopher</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Zealand</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>LAW</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>H.R. 86; Safe Students Act - Amends the federal criminal code to repeal provisions making it unlawful to possess or discharge a firearm in a school zone.

H.R. 131 &amp; S. 1308; Interstate Transportation of Firearms or Ammunition - To amend chapter 44 of title 18, United States Code, to more comprehensively address the interstate transportation of firearms or ammunition.

H.R. 402; National Right-to-Carry Reciprocity Act of 2015 - Amends the federal criminal code to authorize a person who is carrying a valid, government-issued identification document containing that person's photograph and a valid permit to carry a concealed firearm in one state, and who is not prohibited from possessing, transporting, shipping, or receiving a firearm under federal law, to possess or carry a concealed handgun (other than a machine gun or destructive device) in another state in accordance with the restrictions of that state.

H.R. 578 &amp; S. 263; Recreational Lands Self-Defense Act of 2015 - Prohibits the Secretary of the Army from promulgating or enforcing any regulation that prohibits an individual from possessing a firearm at a water resources development project administered by the Chief of Engineers if: (1) the individual is not otherwise prohibited by law from possessing the firearm, and (2) the possession of the firearm is in compliance with the law of the state in which the project is located.

H.R. 923 &amp; S. 498; Constitutional Concealed Carry Reciprocity Act of 2015 - Amends the federal criminal code to authroize a person who is not prohibited from possessing, transporting, shipping, or receiving a firearm under federal law, who is entitled and not prohibited from carry a concealed firearm in his or her state of residence or who is carrying a valid state license or permit to carry a concealed weapon, and who is carrying a government-issued photographic identification document to carry a concealed handgun (which has been shipped or transported in interstate or foreign commerce, other than a machine gun or destructive device) in any state in accordance with the restrictions of that state.

H.R. 986; Concealed Carry Reciprocity Act of 2015 - To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide a means by which nonresidents of a State whose residents may carry concealed firearms may also do so in the State.

H.R. 1114 &amp; S. 173; To modify the definition of "antique firearm" - Modifies the definition of "antique firearm" under the federal criminal code and the Internal Revenue Code to cover any firearm manufactured in or before the calendar year that is 100 years before the year in which a determination is made as to whether the firearm is an antique firearm (currently, any firearm manufactured in or before 1898).

H.R. 1316 &amp; S. 670; Veterans' Heritage Firearms Act of 2015 - Provides a 90-day amnesty period during which veterans and their family members can register in the National Firearms Registration and Transfer Record any firearm acquired before October 31, 1968, by a veteran while a member of the Armed Forces stationed outside the continental United States.

H.R. 1358; Armor-Piercing Bullets Act of 2015 - To enact into law a framework for deciding whether certain projectiles are armour piercing ammuniton.

H.R. 1739; FIREARM Act - To prohibit the Federal Government from requiring race or ethnicity to be disclosed in connection with the transfer of a firearm.

H.R. 1745; Support Assault Firearms Elimination and Reduction for our Streets Act - To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a credit against tax for surrendering to authorities certain assault weapons.

H.R. 1858; Crime Gun Tracing Act - To promote the tracing of firearms used in crimes, and for other purposes.

H.R. 2137 &amp; S. 1162; Federal Law Enforcement Self-Defense and Protection Act of 2015 - To ensure Federal law enforcement officers remain able to ensure their own safety, and the safety of their families, during a covered furlough.

H.R. 2216; Protecting Domestic Violence and Stalking Victims Act - To amend title 18, United States Code, to protect more victims of domestic violence by preventing their abusers from possessing or receiving firearms, and for other purposes.

H.R. 2246 &amp; S. 1351; Firearms Interstate Commerce Reform Act - To amend chapter 44 of title 18, United States Code, to update certain procedures applicable to commerce in firearms and remove certain Federal restrictions on interstate firearms transactions.

H.R. 2283; Stope Online Ammunition Sales Act of 2015 - To require face to face purchases of ammunition, to require licensing of ammunition dealers, and to require reporting regarding bulk purchases of ammunition.

H.R. 2380; Gun Show Loophole Closing Act of 2015 - To require criminal background checks on all firearms transactions occurring at gun shows.

H.R. 2546; Firearm Risk Protection Act of 2015 - To prohibit the sale of a firearm to, and the purchase of a firearm by, a person who is not covered by appropriate liability insurance coverage.

H.R. 2612 &amp; S. 1473; To authorize the appropriation of funds to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention for conducting or supporting research on firearms safety or gun violence prevention.

H.R. 2710; Lawful Purpose and Self Defense Act - To revise various laws that interfere with the right of the people to obtain and use firearms for all lawful purposes.

H.R. 2732; Handgun Purchaser Licensing Act - To provide for a grant program for handgun licensing programs, and for other purposes.

H.R. 2753; Fairness in Firearm Testing Act - To require the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives to make video recordings of the examination and testing of firearms and ammunition, and for other purposes.

H.R. 2767; Airport Security Act of 2015 - To prohibit certain individuals from possessing a firearm in an airport, and for other purposes.

H.R. 2871; Keeping Guns From Criminals Act - To provide an incentive for firearm owners to sell their firearms safely and responsibly.

H.R. 3051; Background Check Completion Act - To eliminate the requirement that a firearms dealer transfer a firearm if the national instant criminal background check system has been unable to complete a background check of the prospective transferee within 3 business days.

H.R. 3125; Accidental Firearms Transfers Reporting Act of 2015 - To require the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation to report to the Congress semiannually on the number of firearms transfers resulting from the failure to complete a background check within 3 business days, and the procedures followed after it is discovered that a firearm transfer has been made to a transferee who is ineligible to receive a firearm.

H.R. 3375; To amend chapter 44 of title 18, United States Code, to extend the period during which a firearms licensee is required to wait for a response from the national instant criminal background check system before being allowed to transfer a firearm to a prospective transferee.

H.R. 3395; Trafficking Reduction and Criminal Enforcement (TRACE) Act - To prevent the illegal sale of firearms, and for other purposes.

H.R. 3411; Fix Gun Checks Act of 2015 - To ensure that all individuals who should be prohibited from buying a firearm are listed in the national instant criminal background check system and require a background check for every firearm sale.

H.R. 3455; Gun Trafficking Prevention Act of 2015 - To prevent gun trafficking.

H.R. 3569; Good Neighbor Gun Dealer Act - To require the Attorney General to establish a "Good Neighbor" code of conduct for federally licensed firearms dealers, and for other purposes.

H.R. 3713; Sentencing Reform Act of 2015, To reform sentencing laws, and for other purposes.

H.R. 3813; Domestic Violence Gun Homicide Prevention Act of 2015, To establish a grant program to encourage States to adopt certain policies and procedures relating to the transfer and possession of firearms.

H.R. 3853; Gun Dealer Accountability Act, To provide the Attorney General with greater discretion in issuing Federal firearms licenses, and to authorize temporarily greater scrutiny of Federal firearms licensees who have transferred a firearm unlawfully or had 10 or more crime guns traced back to them in the preceding 2 years.

H.R. 3888; Blair Holt's Firearm Licensing and Record of Sale Act of 2015, To provide for the implementation of a system of licensing for purchasers of certain firearms and for a record of sale system for those firearms, and for other purposes.

H.R. 3926; Gun Violence Research Act, To amend the Public Health Service Act to provde for better understanding of the epidemic of gun violence, and for other purposes.

H.R. 4069; No Guns for Terrorists Act of 2015, To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit the sale of firearms to individuals suspected of terrorism, and for other purposes.

H.R 4135; Visa Waiver Program Firearms Clarification Act of 2015, To clarify the definition of nonimmigrant for purposes of chapter 44 of title 18, United States Code.

H.R. 4145; To require the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study of, and report to the Congress on, secure gun storage or safety devices.

H.R. 4214; Gun Violence Prevention and Safe Communities Act of 2015, To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to increase the excise tax and special occupational tax in respect of firarms and to increase the transfer tax on any other weapon, and for other purposes.

H.R. 4237; Protect America Act of 2015, To increase public safety by permitting the Attorney General to deny the transfer of firearms or the issuance of explosives licenses to known or suspected terrorists, and for other purposes.

H.R. 4269; Assasult Weapons Bank of 2015, To regulate assault weapons, to ensure that the right to keep and bear arms is not unlimited, and for other purposes.

H.R. 4278; Safer Neighborhoods Gun Buyback Act of 2015, To authorize the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance to make grants to States, units lof local government, and gun dealers to conduct gun buyback programs, and for other purposes.

H.R. 4315; Mental Health Access and Gun Violence Prevention Act of 2016 - This bill authorizes FY2017 appropriations for the Department of Justice, the Department of Health and Human Services, and the Social Security Administration to: (1)increase access to mental health care treatment and services, and (2)promote reporting of mental health information to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System.

H.R. 4316; Gun Violence Reduction Resources Act of 2016 - This bill authorizes the Department of Justice to hire 200 additional agents and investigators for the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives.

H.R. 4399; Equal Access to Justice for Victims of Gun Violence Act - This bill amends the Protection of Lawful Commerce in Arms Act to repeal provisions that prohibit state or federal civil actions or administrative proceedings from being brought against firearm or ammunition manufacturers, sellers, importers, dealers, or trade associations for criminal or unlawful misuse of a firearm by the person bringing the action or a third party.
The bill prohibits the Firearms Trace System database maintained by the National Trace Center of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives from being immune from legal process.  In state or federal civil actions or administrative proceedings, the contents of the database: (1)shall be subject to discovery and admissible as evidence; and (2)may be used, relied on, or disclosed in any manner,  Testimony or other evidence may also be permitted based on that data.

H.R. 4550; PASS Act - To permit qualified law enforcement officers, qualified retired law enforcement officers, and persons not prohibited by State law from carrying a concealed firearm to carry a firearm, and to discharge a firearm in defense of self or others, in a school zone.

H.R. 4703; Family Firearm Protection Act - This bill prohibits a federal government officer or employee from taking an action that limits a firearm transfer between family members, including by way of inheritance, that is more restrictive than limitations in effect as of January 3, 2016.

H.R. 4748; Imported Assault Weapons Ban of 2016 - To ban the importation of semiautomatic assault weapons, and for other purposes.

H. Amdt. 927 to H.R. 766; Amendment clarified that the bill does not prevent federal banking regulators from requesting or requiring a financial institution to terminate a relationship with a customer because (1)the customer poses a threat to national security, (2)is engaged in terrorist financing, (3)is doing business with Iran, North Korea, Syria, or another State Sponsor of Terrorism, or (4)is doing business with an entity in any of those countries.

H. Amdt. 928 to H.R. 766; Page 3, strike lines 4 through 9 and insert the following: (1)NOTICE REQUIRED.- Except as provided under paragraph (2), if an appropriate Federal banking agency orders a depository institution to terminate a specific customer account or group of customer accounts, the depository institution shall inform the customer or customers of the justification for the customer's account termination described under subsection (b).

H.Amdt. 946 to H.R. 2406 - Amendment to delete Title XII which has been enacted into law already; remove outdated year references in short titles, make expenditures under the Federal Land Transaction Facilitation Act subject to appropriation; and add the text of HR 3279, as passed by the House, as a new title XVII.

H.Amdt. 957 to 2406 - Amendment to allow a person who is not prohibited from possessing, transporting, shipping, or receiving a firearm or ammunition to transport a firearm or ammunition for any lawful purpose from any place where the person may lawfully possess, carry, or transport the firearm or ammunition to any other such place if, during the transportation, the firearm is unloaded.


H.Res.289; Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that gun violence is a public health issue and Congres should enact by the end of the 114th Congress comprehensive Federal legislation that protects the Second Amendment and keeps communities safe and healthy, including expanding enforceable background checks for all commercial gun sales, improving the mental health system in the United States, and making gun trafficking and straw purchasing a Federal crime.

H.Res.467; Establishing the Select Committee on Gun Violence Prevention.

S. 1385; Firearm Act of 2015, To prohibit the Federal Government from requiring race or ethnicity to be disclosed in connection with the transfer of a firearm.

S. 1529; A bill to promote the tracing of firearms used in crimes, and for other purposes, To promote the tracing of firearms used in crimes, and for other purposes.

S. 1738; Safer Communities Act of 2015 - To protect individuals by strengthening the Nation's mental health infrastructure, improving the understanding of violence, strengthening firearm prohibitions and protections for at-risk individuals, and improving and expanding the reporting of mental health records to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System.

S. 1751; Handgun Purchaser Licensing Act - To provide for a grant program for handgun licensing programs, and for other purposes.

S. 1760; Hadiya Pendleton and Nyasia Preyear-Yard Gun Trafficking and Crime Prevention Act of 2015 - To prevent gun trafficking.

S. 1834; Lori Jackson Domestic Violence Survivor Protection Act - To amend title 18, United States Code, to protect more victims of domestic violence by preventing their abusers from possessing or receiving firearms, and for other purposes.

S. 1977; Gun Violence Intervention Act of 2015 - To provide family members and close associates of an individual who they fear is a danger to himself, herself, or others new tools to prevent gun violence.

S. 2002; Mental Health and Safe Communities Act of 2015 - To strengthen our mental health system and improve public safety.

S. 2016; Responsible Transfer of Firearms Act - To amend chapter 44 of title 18, United States Code, to promote the responsible transfer of firearms.

S. 2192; NICS Reporting Improvement Act, To ensure that States submit all records of individuals who should be prohibited from buying a firearm to the national instant criminal background check system.

S. 2198; Domestic Violence Gun Homicide Prevention Act of 2015, To establish a grant program to encourage States to adopt certain policies and procedures relating to the transfer and possession of firearms.

S. 2213; Background Check Completion Act of 2015, To oprohibit firearms dealers from selling a firearm prior to the completion of a background check.

S. 2236; Hearing Protection Act of 2015, To provide that silencers be treated the same as long guns.

S. 2323; Visa Waiver Program Firearms Clarification Act of 2015, To clarify the definition of nonimmigrant for purposes of chapter 44 of title 18, United States Code.

S. 2330; SAFE Check Act, To allow the Attorney General additional time to process background checks for alien firearm purchases, and for other purposes.

S. 2377; Defeat ISIS and Protect and Secure the United States Act of 2015, To defeat the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria (ISIS) and protect and secure the United States, and for other purposes.

S. 2469; A bill to repeal the Protection of Lawful Commerce in Arms Act - This bill amends the Protection of Lawful Commerce in Arms Act to repeal provisions that prohibit state or federal civil actions or administrative proceedings from being brought against firearm or ammunition manufacturers, sellers, importers, dealers, or trade associations for criminal or unlawful misuse of a firearm by the person bringing the action or a third party.

S. 2544; Stop Illegal Trafficking in Firearms Act of 2016 - To increase public safety by punishing and deterring firearms trafficking. 

S.Amdt.2908 to S.Amdt.2874; To prohibit Second Amendment rights, ensure that all individuals who should be prohibited from buying a firearm are listed in the National Instant Criminal Background Check System, and provide a responsible and consistent background check process.

S.Amdt.2910 to S.Amdt.2874; To increase public safety by permitting the Attorney General to deny the transfer of firearms or the issuance of firearms and explosives licenses to known or suspected dangerous terrorists.

S.Amdt.2912 to S.Amdt.2874; Relating to the Protect America Act of 2015.

S.Amdt.2914 to S.Amdt.2874; To address gun violence, improve the availabilty of recores to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System, address mental illness in the criminal justice system, and end straw purchases and trafficking of illegal firearms, and for other purposes.</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Bureau of Alcohol Tobacco Firearms &amp; Explosives</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Todd</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Adkins</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>James</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Atkinson</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Brian</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Calabrese</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Benjamin</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Cassidy</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Chris W. </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Cox</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>James</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Holland</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Wayne</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>LaPierre</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jason</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Lawrence</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>David</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Lehman</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jason</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Ouimet</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Brandi</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Pensoneau</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jack</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Thompson</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Christopher</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Zealand</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>NAT</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>H.R. 167; Wildfire Disaster Funding Act - Amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to require specified adjustments to discretionary spending limits in FY2015-FY2022 to accommodate appropriations for wildfire suppression operations in the Wildland Fire Management accounts at the Department of Agriculture (USDA) or the Department of the Interior.

H.R. 327; Polar Bear Conservation and Fairness Act of 2015 - To amend the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to allow importation of polar bear trophies taken in sport hunts in Canada before the date the polar bear was determined to be a threatened species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973.

H.R. 461; Wild Game Donation Act of 2015 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) increase the tax deduction for charitable contributions of qualified wild game meat by the processing fees paid with respect to such contributions, and (2) exclude from the gross income of meat processors processing fees paid by a charitable organization for the processing of donated wild game meat.

H.R. 528; Recreational Fishing and Hunting Heritage and Opportunities Act - To direct Federal public land management officials to exercise their authority under existing law to facilitate use of and access to Federal public lands for fishing, sport hunting, and recreational shooting, and for other purposes.

H.R. 697 &amp; S. 1769; African Elephant Conservation and Legal Ivory Possession Act of 2015 - To amend the African Elephant Conservation Act of 1988 to conserve elephants while appropriately regulating ivory in the United States.

H.R. 1735; National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016 - To authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2016 for military activities of the Department of Defense and for military construction, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes.

H.R. 2028; Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 - Making appropriations for energy and water development and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2016, and for other purposes.

H.R. 2399; Wildlife and Hunting Heritage Conservation Council Advistory Committee Act - To establish the Wildlife and Hunting Heritage Conservation Council Advisory Committee to advise the Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture on wildlife and habitat conservation, hunting, recreational shooting, and for other purposes.

H.R. 3173; Sportsmen's Conservation and Outdoor Recreation Enhancement Act - To promote conservation for the purpose of enhancing hunting, fishing and other outdoor recreational opportunities.

H.R. 3526; CECIL Act - To amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to extend the import-and-export- related provision of that Act to species proposed for listing as threatened or endangered under that Act.

H.Amdt.584; At the end of the bill (before the short title), insert the following: LIMITATION ON USE OF FUNDS WITH RESPECT TO IVORY SEC. _ . None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to implement or enforce section 120 of this Act.

H.Amdt.948 to H.R. 2406 - Amendment sought to strike Title III, the exemption to import polar bear trophies taken in sport.

H.Amdt.954 to 2406 - amendment to prohibit USDA and NFS from issuing restrictions and regulation on hunting and recreational fishing in the Mark Twain National Forest.

H.Amdt.956 to H.R. 2406 - Amendment to require the Forest Administrator to amend the travel plan for the Kisatchie National in Louisiana to allow Utility Terrain Vehicle (UTV) access on roads nominated by the Secretary of Louisiana Wildlife and Fisheries, except when such designation would pose an unacceptable safety risk.  If a road is denied, the amendment would require the Forest Administrator to publish a notice in the Federal Register with a justification for the closure.

H.Amdt.958 to H.R. 2406 - Amendment to add the text of H.R. 373, the Good Samaritan Search and Recovery Act, to the end of the bill.  Adding such text would expedite access to federal lands for volunteer search and rescue groups to assist in recovering the remains of a deceased individual believed to be located on federal lands.

H.Amdt.959 to H.R. 2406 - Amendment to provide for reissuing the 2011 U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service decision to delist the gray wolf in the Western Great Lakes and Wyoming from the Endangered Species Act.

H.Amdt.960 to H.R. 2406 - Amendment to prohibit the Fish and Wildlife Service from issuing a final rule that preempts state management authority which is protected by law in Alaska and withdrawals a final rule issued by the National Park Service of the same issue.

H.Res.619; Providing for consideration of the Bill (H.R. 2406) to protect and enhance opportunities for recreational hunting, fishing and shooting, and for other purposes.

S. 225; Hunting, Fishing and Recreational Shooting Protection Act - Exempts components of firearms and ammunition and sport fishing equipment and its components (such as lead sinkers) from regulations on chemical substances under the Toxic Substances Control Act.

S. 405, S.556, &amp; S.659, S. ; Bipartisan Sportsmen's Act of 2015 - To protect and enhance opportunities for recreational hunting, fishing, and shooting, and for other purposes.

S. 721 &amp; S. 992; Target Practice and Marksmanship Training Support Act - To amend the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act to facilitate the establishment of additional or expanded public target ranges in certain States.

</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Bureau of Land Management (BLM), U.S. Fish &amp; Wildlife Service (USFWS), U.S. Forest Service</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Todd</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Adkins</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>James</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Atkinson</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Brian</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Calabrese</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Benjamin</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Cassidy</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Chris W.</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Cox</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>James</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Holland</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Wayne</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>LaPierre</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jason</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Lawrence</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>David</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Lehman</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jason</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Ouimet</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Brandi</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Pensoneau</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Susan</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Recce</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jack</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Thompson</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Christopher</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Zealand</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
  </alis>
  <updates>
    <clientAddress>
    </clientAddress>
    <clientCity>
    </clientCity>
    <clientState>
    </clientState>
    <clientZip>
    </clientZip>
    <clientZipext>
    </clientZipext>
    <clientCountry>
    </clientCountry>
    <prinClientCity>
    </prinClientCity>
    <prinClientState>
    </prinClientState>
    <prinClientZip>
    </prinClientZip>
    <prinClientZipext>
    </prinClientZipext>
    <prinClientCountry>
    </prinClientCountry>
    <generalDescription>
    </generalDescription>
    <inactive_lobbyists>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>Rebecca </firstName>
        <lastName>Louviere</lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
    </inactive_lobbyists>
    <inactive_ALIs>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
    </inactive_ALIs>
    <affiliatedUrl>
    </affiliatedUrl>
    <affiliatedOrgs>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
    </affiliatedOrgs>
    <inactiveOrgs>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
    </inactiveOrgs>
    <foreignEntities>
      <foreignEntity>
        <name>
        </name>
        <address>
        </address>
        <city>
        </city>
        <state>
        </state>
        <country>
        </country>
        <prinCity>
        </prinCity>
        <prinState>
        </prinState>
        <prinCountry>
        </prinCountry>
        <contribution>
        </contribution>
        <ownership_Percentage>
        </ownership_Percentage>
      </foreignEntity>
    </foreignEntities>
    <inactive_ForeignEntities>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
    </inactive_ForeignEntities>
  </updates>
</LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>