<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='../../ld2webpage.xsl'?>
<LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>
  <imported>Y</imported>
  <pages>3</pages>
  <submitURL>
  </submitURL>
  <organizationName>Air Transport Association of America, Inc.(d/b/a Airlines for America)</organizationName>
  <prefix>
  </prefix>
  <firstName>
  </firstName>
  <lastName>
  </lastName>
  <registrantDifferentAddress>Y</registrantDifferentAddress>
  <address1>1275 PENNSYLVANIA AVENUE, NW</address1>
  <address2>
  </address2>
  <city>WASHINGTON</city>
  <state>DC</state>
  <zip>20004</zip>
  <zipext>2450</zipext>
  <country>USA</country>
  <principal_city>
  </principal_city>
  <principal_state>
  </principal_state>
  <principal_zip>
  </principal_zip>
  <principal_zipext>
  </principal_zipext>
  <principal_country>
  </principal_country>
  <contactIntlPhone>
  </contactIntlPhone>
  <selfSelect>Y</selfSelect>
  <clientName>Air Transport Association of America, Inc.(d/b/a Airlines for America)</clientName>
  <clientGovtEntity>N</clientGovtEntity>
  <senateID>614-12</senateID>
  <houseID>321610000</houseID>
  <reportYear>2016</reportYear>
  <reportType>Q1</reportType>
  <terminationDate>
  </terminationDate>
  <noLobbying>
  </noLobbying>
  <income>
  </income>
  <expenses>1610000.00</expenses>
  <expensesMethod>C</expensesMethod>
  <printedName>JAMES L. CASEY</printedName>
  <signedDate>4/18/2016 4:42:03 PM</signedDate>
  <alis>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>AVI</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Congressional Legislation: 
H.R. 1061/S. 571, Pilots Bill of Rights 2 [appeal of adverse Federal Aviation Administration certificate actions]; H.R. 911, Saracini Aviation Safety Act of 2015 [installation of commercial aircraft cockpit barriers]; H.R. 772, Safe Aviation &amp; Flight Enhancement Act of 2015 [installation aboard commercial aircraft of deployable aircraft recorder systems]; H.R. 753, Safe Aviation &amp; Flight Emergency Tracking Act of 2015 [requiring continuous tracking of commercial aircraft]; H.R. 79, No Missing Planes Act [requiring a study of improving communications between commercial aircraft and air traffic control]; H.R. 1074/S. 712, Passenger Fee Restructuring Act of 2015 [revisions to airline passenger security fee requirements]; H.R. 998, Preclearance Authorization Act of 2015 [requirements for future establishment by Customs and Border Protection of overseas airline passenger preclearance facilities and associated security requirements]; H.R. 399/S. 208, Secure Our Borders First Act of 2015 [establishment at U.S. airports of international passenger biometric exit program]; H.R. 229, Biometric Exit Improvement Act of 2015 [establishment at U.S. airports of international passenger biometric exit program]; H.R. 82, Putting Security First in Preclearance Act [establishing of criteria for new Customs and Border Protection preclearance facilities at foreign airports]; H.R. 158, Visa Waiver Program Improvement Act of 2015 [requiring reports by the Department of Homeland Security to Congress about the Electronic System for Travel Authorization]; H.R. 1560, Protecting Cyber Networks Act [encouraging the private sector and the federal government to share information about cyber threats]; H.R. 234, Cyber Intelligence Sharing &amp; Protection Act ; S. 754, Cybersecurity Information Sharing Act of 2015 [encouraging the private sector and the federal government to share information about cyber threats]; H.R. 2577, Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 [appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security, the Federal Aviation Administration and the Office of the Secretary of Transportation]; TSA PreCheck Expansion Act [expansion of the Transportation Security Administration's PreCheck airline-passenger screening system]; H.R. 2770, Keeping Our Travelers Safe and Secure Act [requiring procedures to validate security-related technology at commercial airports]; H.R. 2767, Airport Security Act of 2015 [limiting possession of firearms at commercial airports]; H.R. 2750, Improved Security Vetting for Aviation Workers Act of 2015 [requiring additional security vetting of aviation workers at airports]; H.R. 2127, Securing Expedited Screening Act [limiting categories of persons entitled to expedited airport screening]; H.R. 1731, National Cybersecurity Protection Advancement Act of 2015 [encouraging the private sector and the federal government to share information about cyber threats]; H.R. 877, United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement Authorization Act [establishment of a new agency withing the Department of Homeland Security, United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement]; H.R. 719, TSA Office of Inspection Accountability Act of 2015 [revision of criteria for criminal investigator positions at the Transportation Security Administration]; Gerardo Hernandez Airport Security Act of 2015 [improving procedures to respond to active-shooter situations at commercial airports]; H.R. 710, Essential Transportation Worker Identification Credential Assessment Act [requiring Department of Homeland Security assessment of effectiveness of transportation-worker security card program]; H.R. 81, FAMS Augmentation Act of 2015 [increasing number of Federal Air Marshals and revising security measures for international flights]; H.R. 115, Freedom of Travel Act of 2015 [limiting Transportation Security Administration screening to aviation]; H.R. 1735/S.1376, National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016 [research and development for aviation-compatible biofuels]; H.R. 2530, Friendly Airports for Mothers Act of 2015 [requiring lactation areas at large and medium hub commercial airports]; H.R. 2006, Aerotropolis Act of 2015 [specifying eligibility of intermodal transportation facilities for federal grants]; H.R. 1835, Air Traffic Controller Reform and Employee Stock Ownership Act of 2015 [transfer of air traffic management to a corporation and establishing an employee stock-ownership plan associated with that transfer]; S. 1619/H.R. 3128, Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2016 [appropriations for Customs and Border Protection, and the Transportation Security Administration]; S. 1612, Safe Skies Act of 2015 [applying Federal Aviation Administration's flight duty and rest requirements to all-cargo operations]; S. 1594, Arm All Pilots Act of 2015 [improving Federal Air Marshal training facilities and specifying the circumstances for FAM carriage of firearms aboard aircraft]; H.R. 22, DRIVE Act [Highway Bill];H.R. 3102, Airport Access Control Security Improvement Act of 2015 [directs the Transportation Security Administration to establish a risk-based, intelligence-driven model for the screening of airport employees based on level of employment-related access to Secure Identification Display Areas, Airport Operations Areas, or secure areas at U.S. airports]; H.R. 3144, Partners for Aviation Security Act [requires Transportation Security Administration consultation with the Aviation Security Advisory Committee regarding modifications to list of items that passengers are prohibited from carrying aboard aircraft and requires TSA to report to Congress about the Transportation Security Oversight Board]; H.R. 3584, Transportation Security Administration Reform and Improvement Act of 2015 [requires aviation and surface security changes at TSA]; H.R. 3586, Border and Maritime Coordination Improvement Act [requires border and maritime security improvements]; H.R. 3614, Airport and Airway Extension Act of 2015 [extension of airport and airways improvement program through March 31, 2016]; H.R. 3334, Families Flying Together Act of 2015 [requires the Department of Transportation to issue regulations to ensure that families are able to sit together on flights];H.R. 3379, Airplane Kids In Transit Safety Act of 2015 (or the Airplane KITS Act of 2015)[directs the Federal Aviation Administration to initiate a rulemaking proceeding to ensure that aircraft medical kits contain appropriate medication and equipment to meet the emergency medical needs of children, including an epinephrine auto-injector]; H.R. 3149, Baggage Fee Fairness Act of 2015 [limits the amount of a fee that an airline can charge for checked baggge]; H.R. 2776, Carry-On Freedom Act of 2015 [directs the Department of Transportation to issue regulations to prohibit an airline that charges passengers a fee for checked baggage from using a size standard for carry-on baggage that reduces the size standard used by the carrier on June 8, 2015]; S. 1972, Airline Access to Emergency Epinephrine Act of 2015 [directs the Federal Aviation Administration to require airlines to carry on each aircraft at least two packs of epinephrine auto-injectors for use as the initial treatment for anaphylaxis and to train crewmembers to recognize the symptoms of an acute allergic reaction and administer auto-injectable epinephrine]. H.R. 2029, Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016; H.R. 460/S. 623, Human Trafficking Detection Act of 2015 [training Department of Homeland Security personnel to deter, detect, disrupt and prevent human trafficking]; H.R. 644, Trade Facilitation and Trade Enforcement Act of 2015 [international trade enforcement and trade facilitation]; H.R. 4295, To require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to increase the rest periods of flight attendants to the same rest periods of pilots [rest periods for airline flight attendants]; H.R. 4203, Comfortable and Fair Flight Act [prohibition against certain airline fees]; H.R. 4171, Silent Skies Act of 2015 [prohibition of the operation of certain aircraft not complying with stage 4 noise levels]; H.R. 3965, FAA Community Accountability Act of 2015 [establishing and revising flight paths and procedures]; S. 2406, A bill to require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to review certain decisions to grant categorical exclusions for Next Generation flight procedures and to consult with the airports at which such procedures will be implemented; S. 2361, Airport Security Enhancement and Oversight Act [U.S. commercial airport security measures]; H.R. 4721, Airport and Airway Extension Act of 2016 [extending authorizations for the airport improvement program and the funding and expenditure authority of the Airport and Airway Trust Fund];H.R. 4369/S. 2442, To authorize the use of passenger facility charges at an airport previously associated with the airport at which the charges are collected [as indicated in the bill's title]; H.R. 4314, Counterterrorism Screening and Assistance Act of 2016 [requiring the Secretary of State, in consultation with other federal entities, to develop a plan to combat international travel by terrorists and foreign fighters, accelerate the transfer of border security systems to foreign governments and establishing minimum international border security standards]; H.R. 4698, Securing Aviation from Foreign Entry Points and Guarding Airports Through Enhanced Security Act of 2016 [requiring the Transportation Security Administration to conduct security risk assessments of all last-point-of-departure foreign airports with nonstop flights to the United States, and to submit to Congress and the Government Accountability Office a plan to enhance security collaboration concerning flights between the United States and foreign countries]; H.R. 4549/S. 2549, Treating Small Airports with Fairness Act of 2016 [requiring the Transportation Security Administration to conduct and provide staff and equipment for security screening at any airport that lost commercial air service on or after January 1, 2013, if the airport operator submits: (1) a request for the TSA to conduct such screening, and (2) written confirmation of a commitment from an air carrier that the carrier intends to resume service at the airport within one year]; H.R. 4408, National Strategy to Combat Terrorist Travel Act of 2016 [requiring the President to transmit to Congress a national strategy to combat terrorist travel]; H.R. 4407, Counterterrorism Advisory Board Act of 2016 [establishing in the Department of Homeland Security a board to coordinate and integrate DHS's intelligence, activities and policy related to its counterterrorism responsibilities]; S. 2658, Federal Aviation Administration Reauthorization Act of 2016 [extending authorizations for the airport improvement program and the funding and expenditure authority of the Airport and Airway Trust Fund, and creating or revising FAA and Department of Transportation civil aviation programs];S. 2656, FAIR Fees Act [prohibiting air carriers from imposing fees that are "not reasonable and proportional" to the costs incurred by the air carriers]; S. 2642, Stop Trafficking on Planes (STOP) Act of 2016 [requiring passenger air carrier to provide their flight attendants and pilots with training to combat human trafficking in the course of carrying out their duties]; S. 2547, Real Transparency in Airfares Act of 2016 [increasing the maximum penalty for unfair and deceptive practices relating to advertising the costs of air transportation]; S. 2536, A bill to require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to issue a notice of proposed rulemaking regarding the inclusion in aircraft medical kits of medications and equipment to meet the emergency medical needs of children [as indicated in the bill's title]; and S. 2528, Lithium Battery Safety Act of 2016 [repealing the prohibition in federal law against new Department of Transportation regulations for the transportation by aircraft of lithium metal cells or batteries or lithium ion cells or batteries that are more stringent than the requirements of the International Civil Aviation Organization Technical Instructions for the Safe Transport of Dangerous Goods by Air].



Regulatory Issues: 

Air Cargo Security Issues; Air Traffic Control Reform, including current improvements and proposed legislative changes; Aircraft Noise and Emissions Issues; Airport Security Issues; Aircraft Tracking Issues, particularly international proposals concerning tracking; Alternative Aviation Fuels; Customs and Border Protection (CBP) Issues, including CBP airport staffing levels and foreign-airport preclearance implementation issues, CBP Implementation of Biometric Entry and Exit Systems, and CBP Fes;  Department of Transportation (DOT) Full Fare Advertising Rule; DOT Implementation of Passenger Protection Regulations I and II;  DOT Proposed Passenger Protection Regulation III;  DOT Tarmac Delay Rule Implementation Issues; Employee Occupational Safety and Health Issues. Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) Air Crew Training Rule, FAA Flight and Duty Time Regulations, FAA NextGen Initiative, FAA Pilot Qualifications Rule, and Unmanned Aerial Systems Airspace Use Issues; FAA/USTRANSCOM Non-Premium War-Risk Insurance Program; FY 2016 DOT/FAA and DHS budget proposals, including proposals to increase the customs use and immigration user fees; Implementation of a National Airline Policy; International Air Service Rights Issues (U.S. Government Bilateral Negotiations); Lithium Battery Carriage Aboard Aircraft (FAA and Pipeline Hazardous Materials Administration); Passenger Facility Charge Tax Issues; Railway Labor Act Application and Interpretation Issues; Transportation Security Administration (TSA) Aviation Security Taxes and Fees, TSA Civil Aviation Security Issues, including expansion of trusted traveler/risk-based screening programs, airport exit-lane staffing and secondary cockpit barriers and TSA Managed Inclusion Passenger Security Program;and Various Federal Income and Excise Tax Matters; Excise Tax on the Cost of Employer-Sponsored Health Care; Visa Waiver Program;  Crude Oil Export Ban; Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service (APHIS) - Agriculture Quarantine Inspection (AQI) Program; and Frequency Spectrum Allocation; and negotiations and implementation of the expansion and shifting of times of flight slots at Haneda Airport, Tokyo, Japan.

</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Commerce - Dept of  (DOC), Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), Executive Office of the President (EOP), Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), Homeland Security - Dept of  (DHS), Internal Revenue Service (IRS), Natl Mediation Board, Natl Transportation Safety Board (NTSB), Occupational Safety &amp; Health Review Commission, Office of Management &amp; Budget (OMB), State - Dept of (DOS), Transportation - Dept of (DOT), Transportation Security Administration (TSA), U.S. Customs &amp; Border Protection, Defense - Dept of (DOD)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Nicholas</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Calio</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Christine</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Burgeson</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Sean</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Kennedy</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Sharon</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Pinkerton</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Shelley</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Rubino</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Josh</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Saltzman</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jarrod</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Thompson</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>Air Canada, which is an associate member of Airlines for America, is interested in the issues listed under Specific Lobbying Issues to the extent that they affect its operations to and from the United States.</foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
  </alis>
  <updates>
    <clientAddress>
    </clientAddress>
    <clientCity>
    </clientCity>
    <clientState>
    </clientState>
    <clientZip>
    </clientZip>
    <clientZipext>
    </clientZipext>
    <clientCountry>
    </clientCountry>
    <prinClientCity>
    </prinClientCity>
    <prinClientState>
    </prinClientState>
    <prinClientZip>
    </prinClientZip>
    <prinClientZipext>
    </prinClientZipext>
    <prinClientCountry>
    </prinClientCountry>
    <generalDescription>
    </generalDescription>
    <inactive_lobbyists>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
    </inactive_lobbyists>
    <inactive_ALIs>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
    </inactive_ALIs>
    <affiliatedUrl>
    </affiliatedUrl>
    <affiliatedOrgs>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
    </affiliatedOrgs>
    <inactiveOrgs>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
    </inactiveOrgs>
    <foreignEntities>
      <foreignEntity>
        <name>
        </name>
        <address>
        </address>
        <city>
        </city>
        <state>
        </state>
        <country>
        </country>
        <prinCity>
        </prinCity>
        <prinState>
        </prinState>
        <prinCountry>
        </prinCountry>
        <contribution>
        </contribution>
        <ownership_Percentage>
        </ownership_Percentage>
      </foreignEntity>
    </foreignEntities>
    <inactive_ForeignEntities>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
    </inactive_ForeignEntities>
  </updates>
</LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>