<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='../../ld2webpage.xsl'?>
<LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>
  <imported>Y</imported>
  <pages>3</pages>
  <submitURL>
  </submitURL>
  <organizationName>The Mitchell Firm, Inc.</organizationName>
  <prefix>
  </prefix>
  <firstName>
  </firstName>
  <lastName>
  </lastName>
  <registrantDifferentAddress>N</registrantDifferentAddress>
  <address1>42020 Village Center Plaza</address1>
  <address2>Suite 120-200</address2>
  <city>Stone Ridge</city>
  <state>VA</state>
  <zip>20105</zip>
  <zipext>
  </zipext>
  <country>USA</country>
  <principal_city>Chantilly</principal_city>
  <principal_state>VA</principal_state>
  <principal_zip>20152</principal_zip>
  <principal_zipext>
  </principal_zipext>
  <principal_country>USA</principal_country>
  <contactIntlPhone>
  </contactIntlPhone>
  <selfSelect>N</selfSelect>
  <clientName>Moshe Margareten</clientName>
  <clientGovtEntity>N</clientGovtEntity>
  <senateID>91650-152</senateID>
  <houseID>368070008</houseID>
  <reportYear>2016</reportYear>
  <reportType>Q1</reportType>
  <terminationDate>
  </terminationDate>
  <noLobbying>
  </noLobbying>
  <income>30000.00</income>
  <expenses>
  </expenses>
  <expensesMethod>
  </expensesMethod>
  <printedName>Greg Mitchell</printedName>
  <signedDate>4/20/2016 4:15:13 PM</signedDate>
  <alis>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>LAW</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Made contacts in support of H.R. 759, the Corrections and Recidivism Reduction Act, a bill to reform the federal prison system, strengthen public safety, enhance prison security, provide inmates the help they need, and protect civil liberties. Specifically, made contacts in support of recidivism reduction programs, productive activities and real jobs; and earned time credits for federal prisoners. Supported time credits of up to 30 days for each period of 30 days of programming that they successfully complete for prisoners who are a low risk of recidivism.

HR 759 does the following:

Strengthens Public Safety:
The Corrections and Recidivism Reduction Act implements a post-sentencing dynamic risk assessment system to determine an inmates risk of committing more crimes upon release from prison. Under the legislation, the Bureau of Prisons (BOP) would utilize effective recidivism reduction programs and provide incentives for inmates to participate in those programs. Ultimately, inmates could earn credits toward an alternative custody arrangement - such as a halfway house or home confinement - at the end of their prison sentence.
Renders criminals convicted of certain serious offenses ineligible for the alternative custody program, including dangerous sexual offenders, murderers, and others.

Enhances Prison Security:
The bill authorizes the Director of BOP to issue pepper spray to those employed in a prison above the medium security level.
The bill requires the Director of BOP to provide a secure storage area outside the secure perimeter for employees to store firearms or to allow for vehicle lock boxes for firearms.
The bill requires the Director of BOP to provide de-escalation training as part of the regular training requirements of correctional officers.

Provide Inmates the Help They Need:
The bill requires BOP to initiate pilot programs for youth mentorship and the training and therapy of rescue dogs.
It requires BOP to submit a report and evaluation of the current pilot program to treat heroin and opioid abuse through medication assisted treatment.
The bill extends the compassionate elderly release provision from the Second Chance Act that allows the prisoner to request for his or her compassionate release if he or she meets the requirements set out in the law.
The bill codifies BOPs rules on using restraints on pregnant inmates, which generally prohibit the use of restraints on pregnant inmates except those who are an immediate and credible flight risk or threat of harm to herself, the baby, or others.

Protects Civil Liberties:
The bill prevents BOP from monitoring the contents of electronic communications to or from a prisoner in a federal prison facility and his attorney or other legal representative. The bill contains an exception when BOP obtains a court order to monitor electronic communications for the purpose of entering it into evidence, or use or disclose, the contents of the communications.

Also made contacts in support of S. 2123, the Sentencing Reform and Corrections Act of 2015, a bill to reform sentencing laws and correctional institutions, and for other purposes.

Specifically supported the following sections of this bill:

Section 202. Recidivism Reduction Programming and Productive Activities. This section requires BOP to make statistically validated recidivism reduction programming available to all eligible prisoners within six years. As an incentive for successfully completing recidivism reduction program, eligible inmates may receive time credit of up to five days for each period of 30 days of programming that they successfully complete. Inmates classified as low risk may receive an additional credit of up to five days for each period of 30 days of program completion. Inmates serving sentences for a second or subsequent federal offense and those with 13 or more criminal history points under the sentencing guidelines are ineligible for time credits. Inmates serving sentences for certain offenses are excluded, including crimes of terrorism and violence. 

Section 203. Post-Sentencing Risk and Needs Assessment System. The Attorney General is required to develop a risk and needs assessment system that will determine the recidivism risk of all federal inmates and classify inmates as having a high, moderate, or low risk of recidivism. The assessment system must also identify each inmates programmatic needs and identify appropriate programming. The system must measure indicators of progress such that each inmate (other than those already classified as low risk) has a meaningful opportunity to progress to a lower risk level during the time of the inmates incarceration through changes in dynamic risk factors, and that each inmate on prerelease custody (other than those already classified as low risk) has a meaningful opportunity to progress to a lower risk classification through changes in dynamic risk factors. 

Section 204. Prerelease Custody. This section allows prisoners to serve an amount of time equal to the credit they have earned for recidivism reduction programming in prerelease custody, provided that the prisoners most recent risk assessment determined that the prisoner was low or moderate risk and, if moderate risk, that the prisoners risk of recidivism has significantly declined. It provides that a prisoner permitted to spend a portion of the prisoners sentence in prerelease custody as a result of completing recidivism reduction programming may spend such time in a residential reentry center, on home confinement, or on community supervision. Inmates placed in home confinement shall be subject to monitoring and be required to remain in their residence, with exceptions for employment and other specified activities. BOP may revoke a prisoners prerelease custody and require the prisoner to serve the remainder of the prisoners term of incarceration in prison if the prisoner violates the conditions.  

But made contacts to support the following revision:
The removal of the exclusion for a federal fraud offense for which the prisoner received a sentence of imprisonment of more than 15 years.</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Greg</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Mitchell</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>Chief of Staff, Congressman James E. Rogan (CA)</coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
  </alis>
  <updates>
    <clientAddress>
    </clientAddress>
    <clientCity>
    </clientCity>
    <clientState>
    </clientState>
    <clientZip>
    </clientZip>
    <clientZipext>
    </clientZipext>
    <clientCountry>
    </clientCountry>
    <prinClientCity>
    </prinClientCity>
    <prinClientState>
    </prinClientState>
    <prinClientZip>
    </prinClientZip>
    <prinClientZipext>
    </prinClientZipext>
    <prinClientCountry>
    </prinClientCountry>
    <generalDescription>
    </generalDescription>
    <inactive_lobbyists>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
    </inactive_lobbyists>
    <inactive_ALIs>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
    </inactive_ALIs>
    <affiliatedUrl>
    </affiliatedUrl>
    <affiliatedOrgs>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
    </affiliatedOrgs>
    <inactiveOrgs>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
    </inactiveOrgs>
    <foreignEntities>
      <foreignEntity>
        <name>
        </name>
        <address>
        </address>
        <city>
        </city>
        <state>
        </state>
        <country>
        </country>
        <prinCity>
        </prinCity>
        <prinState>
        </prinState>
        <prinCountry>
        </prinCountry>
        <contribution>
        </contribution>
        <ownership_Percentage>
        </ownership_Percentage>
      </foreignEntity>
    </foreignEntities>
    <inactive_ForeignEntities>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
    </inactive_ForeignEntities>
  </updates>
</LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>