<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='../../ld2webpage.xsl'?>
<LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>
  <imported>Y</imported>
  <pages>3</pages>
  <submitURL>
  </submitURL>
  <organizationName>The Raben Group</organizationName>
  <prefix>
  </prefix>
  <firstName>
  </firstName>
  <lastName>
  </lastName>
  <registrantDifferentAddress>N</registrantDifferentAddress>
  <address1>1341 G street NW Flr 5</address1>
  <address2>
  </address2>
  <city>WASHINGTON</city>
  <state>DC</state>
  <zip>20005</zip>
  <zipext>
  </zipext>
  <country>USA</country>
  <principal_city>
  </principal_city>
  <principal_state>
  </principal_state>
  <principal_zip>
  </principal_zip>
  <principal_zipext>
  </principal_zipext>
  <principal_country>
  </principal_country>
  <contactIntlPhone>
  </contactIntlPhone>
  <selfSelect>N</selfSelect>
  <clientName>Breast Cancer Fund</clientName>
  <clientGovtEntity>N</clientGovtEntity>
  <senateID>61458-1406</senateID>
  <houseID>353940050</houseID>
  <reportYear>2016</reportYear>
  <reportType>Q1</reportType>
  <terminationDate>
  </terminationDate>
  <noLobbying>
  </noLobbying>
  <income>10000.00</income>
  <expenses>
  </expenses>
  <expensesMethod>
  </expensesMethod>
  <printedName>Robert Raben</printedName>
  <signedDate>4/20/2016 11:30:53 PM</signedDate>
  <alis>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>HCR</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>LEGISLATION IN THE 114TH CONGRESS​

S.1014, Personal Care Products Safety Act
The Breast Cancer Fund continues to meet with staff from Senator Feinsteins office  and other HELP committee offices to encourage legislative action on the issue of safety of Personal Care Products. The Breast Cancer Fund supports action that would remove toxins and regulate Personal Care Products and Cosmetics.

H.R.2576, TSCA Modernization Act of 2015
The Breast Cancer Fund supports this bill and has been meeting with House and Senate offices to persuade members to take up the bill in the Senate. 

S. 697, Frank R. Lautenberg Chemical Safety for the 21st Century Act
The Breast Cancer Fund opposes this legislation without amendments, as it would do little to strengthen the current TSCA law, but continues to work with members of the Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works to improve and strengthen the bill. 

S. 725, Alan Reinstein and Trevor Schaefer Toxic Chemical Protection Act
The Breast Cancer Fund supports this legislation because it would mandate the testing of chemicals for their health risks, including potentially hazardous, cancer-causing chemicals currently being used in a variety of consumer products.

S. 821, BPA in Food Packaging Right to Know Act
The Breast Cancer Fund continues to meet with staff from Senate offices to encourage legislative action on the issue of bisphenol-A, which has been linked to increased rates of cancer, as well as other significant health problems. The Breast Cancer Fund support action that would ban bisphenol-A from the linings of canned food, foods marketed to children, and food storage containers.

HOUSE AND SENATE APPROPRIATIONS

The Breast Cancer Fund contacted House and Senate offices about increasing federal funding for the following:

Centers for Disease Control and Prevention Programs, National Environmental Public Health Tracking Network 
Centers for Disease Control and Prevention Programs, Environmental Health Labs Biomonitoring Program 
National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences (NIEHS)
The Breast Cancer Fund contacted Senate offices about preserving the current Design for the Environment program in the EPA.

FUTURE LEGISLATIVE PROPOSALS:

The Breast Cancer Fund visits Senate offices to support an amendment to the Senate NDAA that directs the Secretary of Defense, in carrying out research, development, test, and evaluation activities with respect to breast cancer, to implement the recommendations of the Interagency Breast Cancer and Environmental Research Coordinating Committee to prioritize prevention and increase the study of chemical and physical factors in breast cancer (IBCERCC).

The Breast Cancer Fund supports this legislation to reform the FDAs regulation of cosmetic and personal care product ingredients based on mounting evidence that several ingredients of common cosmetic products have been linked to negative environmental health impacts, including breast cancer.

The Breast Cancer Fund supports ongoing efforts to reintroduce legislation that would compel manufacturers to provide complete and accurate product labeling of chemicals used in consumer products. Such labeling is a critical step in removing carcinogenic, and otherwise hazardous, materials from consumer products.

The Breast Cancer Fund supports ongoing efforts to reintroduce legislation in the House that would mandate the testing of chemicals for their health risks- including potentially hazardous, cancer-causing chemicals currently being used in a variety of consumer products.

The Breast Cancer Fund continues to talk with staff from Senate offices about the introduction of legislation in the Senate to reform the FDAs regulation of cosmetics and personal care product ingredients to prevent the use of chemicals found to have negative health and environmental impacts.

REGULATION AND LEGISLATIVE INTENT:

FDA Advocacy
In addition to meeting with Congressional staff on the matter of bisphenol-A (BPA), the Breast Cancer Fund has also met with members of the FDA management team concerning the FDAs ongoing cosmetics regulation negotiations and the FDAs transparency policies more generally.

P.L. 110-314 - The Consumer Product Safety Commission Improvement Act
The Breast Cancer Fund lobbied in support of the provision that bans the use of phthalates in the manufacture of childrens toys. We are now monitoring implementation of this law; working on preserving the law's phthalates provision through the legislative and regulatory process; and urging expeditious research and regulatory action as required by the legislation.


Lobbying:  U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, U.S. SENATE, Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC), National Institutes of Health (NIH), Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), Executive Office of the President (EOP), Office of Management &amp; Budget (OMB), Health &amp; Human Services - Department of (HHS), Office of Science &amp; Technology Policy (OSTP), Health &amp; Human Services - Dept of (HHS), Food &amp; Drug Administration (FDA)
</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC), Natl Institutes of Health (NIH), Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), Executive Office of the President (EOP), Office of Management &amp; Budget (OMB), Health &amp; Human Services - Dept of (HHS), Office of Science &amp; Technology Policy (OSTP), Food &amp; Drug Administration (FDA)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Daniel </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Penchina</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Katharine</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Huffman</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
  </alis>
  <updates>
    <clientAddress>
    </clientAddress>
    <clientCity>
    </clientCity>
    <clientState>
    </clientState>
    <clientZip>
    </clientZip>
    <clientZipext>
    </clientZipext>
    <clientCountry>
    </clientCountry>
    <prinClientCity>
    </prinClientCity>
    <prinClientState>
    </prinClientState>
    <prinClientZip>
    </prinClientZip>
    <prinClientZipext>
    </prinClientZipext>
    <prinClientCountry>
    </prinClientCountry>
    <generalDescription>
    </generalDescription>
    <inactive_lobbyists>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
    </inactive_lobbyists>
    <inactive_ALIs>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
    </inactive_ALIs>
    <affiliatedUrl>
    </affiliatedUrl>
    <affiliatedOrgs>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
    </affiliatedOrgs>
    <inactiveOrgs>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
    </inactiveOrgs>
    <foreignEntities>
      <foreignEntity>
        <name>
        </name>
        <address>
        </address>
        <city>
        </city>
        <state>
        </state>
        <country>
        </country>
        <prinCity>
        </prinCity>
        <prinState>
        </prinState>
        <prinCountry>
        </prinCountry>
        <contribution>
        </contribution>
        <ownership_Percentage>
        </ownership_Percentage>
      </foreignEntity>
    </foreignEntities>
    <inactive_ForeignEntities>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
    </inactive_ForeignEntities>
  </updates>
</LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>