<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='../../ld2webpage.xsl'?>
<LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>
  <imported>Y</imported>
  <pages>3</pages>
  <submitURL>
  </submitURL>
  <organizationName>National Small Business Association</organizationName>
  <prefix>
  </prefix>
  <firstName>
  </firstName>
  <lastName>
  </lastName>
  <registrantDifferentAddress>Y</registrantDifferentAddress>
  <address1>1156 15TH STREET, NW</address1>
  <address2>Suite 502 </address2>
  <city>WASHINGTON</city>
  <state>DC</state>
  <zip>20005</zip>
  <zipext>
  </zipext>
  <country>USA</country>
  <principal_city>
  </principal_city>
  <principal_state>
  </principal_state>
  <principal_zip>
  </principal_zip>
  <principal_zipext>
  </principal_zipext>
  <principal_country>
  </principal_country>
  <contactIntlPhone>
  </contactIntlPhone>
  <selfSelect>Y</selfSelect>
  <clientName>National Small Business Association</clientName>
  <clientGovtEntity>N</clientGovtEntity>
  <senateID>28550-12</senateID>
  <houseID>306970000</houseID>
  <reportYear>2016</reportYear>
  <reportType>Q1</reportType>
  <terminationDate>
  </terminationDate>
  <noLobbying>
  </noLobbying>
  <income>
  </income>
  <expenses>37000.00</expenses>
  <expensesMethod>A</expensesMethod>
  <printedName>Todd McCracken </printedName>
  <signedDate>4/27/2016 2:02:44 PM</signedDate>
  <alis>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>SMB</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>H.R. 8 - North American Energy Security and Infrastructure Act of 2015 Legislation seeks to promote energy efficiency inside the federal government and improve the security of energy-related infrastructure primarily by expanding the Department of Energys authorities. NSBA supports 
H.R. 9 - Innovation Act Reforms the patent system and introduces measures that would make it more difficult for small businesses to defend their patents. NSBA opposes
H.R. 25 - The Fair Tax Act To promote freedom, fairness, and economic opportunity by repealing the income tax and other taxes, abolishing the Internal Revenue Service, and enacting a national sales tax to be administered primarily by the states. NSBA supports 
H.R. 644 - the Trade Facilitation and Trade Enforcement Act The legislation authorizes the U.S. Customs and Border Protection and improves the flow of legitimate trade by modernizing the automated import and export system. NSBA supports
H.R. 703 - Renewable Fuel Standard Elimination Act Would remove the renewable fuel standard. NSBA is monitoring
H.R. 1105 - Death Tax Repeal Act of 2015 Bill would repeal the estate and generation-skipping transfer taxes, as well as cut the top gift tax rate. NSBA supports 
H.R. 1155 - Searching for and Cutting Regulations that are Unnecessarily Burdensome (SCRUB) Act of 2015 This bill would create a special commission to review and repeal regulatory requirements which could be removed without significant impact to the regulations overall effectiveness. NSBA supports
H.R. 1732 - Regulatory Protection Act of 2015 The legislation would require the EPA to rewrite the waters of the U.S. rule. NSBA supports
H.R. 2045 - TROL Act Allows the FTC to go after patent trolls which often target small business patent holders. NSBA supports
H.R. 2187 - The Fair Investment Opportunities for Professional Experts Act 
Requires the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to rewrite the accredited investor definition and would codify the current financial thresholds so that they may not be raised by the SEC except by statute. NSBA supports
H.R. 2775 - the Remote Transactions Parity Act of 2015 The bill allows states that meet simplification requirements to require remote sellers to collect taxes due on items purchased by consumers in those states. NSBA is monitoring
H.R. 2911 - Small Business Healthcare Relief Act This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to allow an employer with fewer than 50 employees that does not offer group health insurance coverage to establish a health reimbursement arrangement. NSBA supports 
H.R. 3326 - Defend Trade Secrets Act of 2015 Creates a right of action in federal court for trade secrets violations and creates mechanisms to prevent the release of trade secret information. NSBA supports
H.R. 3784 - The SEC Small Business Advocate Act of 2016 This bill would establish an Office of the Small Business Advocate within SEC to advocate on behalf of small businesses and to be a resource for small businesses. NSBA supports
H.R. 4168 - Small Business Capital Formation Enhancement Act Will require the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to respond to recommendations made during the annual Government-Business Forum on Small Business Capital Formation. NSBA supports
H.R. 4341 - Defending Americas Small Contractors Act of 2016 Introduces a number of reforms to increase transparency and the ability of small businesses to compete in the federal marketplace. NSBA supports
H.R. 4377 - American Business Competitiveness Act The bill cuts the corporate income tax to 25 percent; limits the top tax rate on non-corporate business income to 25 percent; allows businesses to deduct investment costs when they occur (full expensing); eliminates most business tax credits and many deductions;  and moves to a territorial tax system like most developed nations. NSBA is monitoring 
H.R. 4498 - Helping Angels Lead our Startups (HALOS) Act The measure is designed to make it easier for businesses to notify potential investors of their offerings as well as provide a statutory definition for angel investor group. NSBA supports 
H.R. 4612 - Midnight Rule Relief Act of 2016 Would prevent agencies from proposing or finalizing regulations from the day after elections to the day of the next presidential inauguration. NSBA supports
H.R. 4638 - Main Street Growth Act The legislation seeks to make small business offerings more attractive to investors by creating venture exchanges which will bring together buyers and sellers for of venture securities. NSBA supports 
H.R. 4783 - Commercializing on Small Business Innovation Act of 2016 Legislation would reauthorize the SBIR/STTR programs through 2022. NSBA supports
H.R. 4831 - S-Corp Bill Would amend the tax code to clarify that shareholders in an S-Corp. who acquired their shares through crowdfunding would not count against the 100 shareholder cap. NSBA supports 
H.R. 4850 - Micro Offering Safe Harbor Act Would create an exemption from registration requirements under the Securities Act for certain small securities offerings. NSBA supports
H.J. Res. 71 - Clean Power Plan - Congressional Review Act  This resolution would invoke the Congressional Review Act and roll back the Clean Power Plan regulations promulgated by the EPA to cut carbon emissions. NSBA Supports
H.J. Res. 72 - Clean Power Plan - Congressional Review Act This resolution would invoke the Congressional Review Act and roll back the Clean Power Plan regulations promulgated by the EPA to cut carbon emissions. NSBA supports
S. 155 - the Fair Tax Act To promote freedom, fairness, and economic opportunity by repealing the income tax and other taxes, abolishing the Internal Revenue Service, and enacting a national sales tax to be administered primarily by the states. NSBA supports 
S. 632 - STRONG Patent Act Introduces modest patent reforms that would afford small businesses greater protections for their patents. NSBA supports
S.698 - Marketplace Fairness Act of 2015 The bill would require eCommerce sellers who gross over $1million in remote (out-of-state) sales per year to collect sales tax from buyers in all 45 states (plus D.C.) that impose a sales tax. NSBA is monitoring
S. 1137 - PATENT Act Reforms the patent system and introduces measures that would make it more difficult for small businesses to defend their patents. NSBA opposes
S. 1140 - Federal Water Quality Protection Act The legislation would require the EPA to rewrite the waters of the U.S. rule. NSBA supports
S. 1584 - Renewable Fuel Standard Repeal Act Would remove the renewable fuel standard. NSBA is monitoring 
S. 1607 - Independent Agency Regulatory Analysis Act of 2015 Creates a procedure whereby the president can require independent regulatory agencies to comply with the same rulemaking requirements that other agencies do. NSBA supports
S. 1683 - Searching for and Cutting Regulations that are Unnecessarily Burdensome (SCRUB) Act of 2015 This bill would create a special commission to review and repeal regulatory requirements which could be removed without significant impact to the regulations overall effectiveness. NSBA supports
S. 1697 - Small Business Healthcare Relief Act This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to allow an employer with fewer than 50 employees that does not offer group health insurance coverage to establish a health reimbursement arrangement. NSBA supports 
S. 1890 - Defend Trade Secrets Act of 2015 Creates a right of action in federal court for trade secrets violations and creates mechanisms to prevent the release of trade secret information. NSBA supports
S. 2006 - Regulatory Accountability Act of 2015 Amends the APA to require that regulating agencies do more thorough examinations of the costs and benefits of promulgating regulations. NSBA supports
S. 2012 - Energy Policy Modernization Act of 2015 Would make a number of changes impacting the security and the reliability of the energy grid. NSBA supports 
S. 2582 - Midnight Rule Relief Act of 2016 Would prevent agencies from proposing or finalizing regulations from the day after elections to the day of the next presidential inauguration. NSBA supports
S. 2696 - Protect Small Business Jobs Act of 2016 Would create a six month grace period for first time regulations violations by small business which do not place anyone in imminent danger. NSBA supports
S. 2733 - Venue Equity and Non-Uniformity Elimination Act of 2016 This legislation will make changes to existing venue requirements in patent infringement litigation. NSBA opposes 
S.J. Res. 22 - WOTUS Congressional Review Act Resolution This resolution would invoke the Congressional Review Act and roll back the WOTUS rule which EPA finalized in May 2015.
NSBA supports 
S.Con. Res. 25 This expressed the sense of Congress that no deal reached during the Paris climate change conference would have force in the U.S. unless it was approved by Congress. 
NSBA is monitoring. </description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Centers For Medicare and  Medicaid Services  (CMS), Commerce - Dept of  (DOC), Energy - Dept of, Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC), Export-Import Bank of the United States (EXIM Bank), Federal Reserve System, Government Accountability Office (GAO), Health &amp; Human Services - Dept of  (HHS), Internal Revenue Service (IRS), Intl Trade Administration (ITA), Labor - Dept of (DOL), Natl Labor Relations Board (NLRB), Office of Personnel Management (OPM), Securities &amp; Exchange Commission (SEC), Small Business Adminstration (SBA), Treasury - Dept of, U.S. Citizenship &amp; Immigration Services (USCIS), U.S. Trade Representative (USTR), White House Office</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jody</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Milanese </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Gregory</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Yahr</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
  </alis>
  <updates>
    <clientAddress>1156 15TH STREET, NW, Suite 502</clientAddress>
    <clientCity>Washington</clientCity>
    <clientState>DC</clientState>
    <clientZip>20005</clientZip>
    <clientZipext>
    </clientZipext>
    <clientCountry>USA</clientCountry>
    <prinClientCity>
    </prinClientCity>
    <prinClientState>
    </prinClientState>
    <prinClientZip>
    </prinClientZip>
    <prinClientZipext>
    </prinClientZipext>
    <prinClientCountry>
    </prinClientCountry>
    <generalDescription>
    </generalDescription>
    <inactive_lobbyists>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
    </inactive_lobbyists>
    <inactive_ALIs>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
    </inactive_ALIs>
    <affiliatedUrl>
    </affiliatedUrl>
    <affiliatedOrgs>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
    </affiliatedOrgs>
    <inactiveOrgs>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
    </inactiveOrgs>
    <foreignEntities>
      <foreignEntity>
        <name>
        </name>
        <address>
        </address>
        <city>
        </city>
        <state>
        </state>
        <country>
        </country>
        <prinCity>
        </prinCity>
        <prinState>
        </prinState>
        <prinCountry>
        </prinCountry>
        <contribution>
        </contribution>
        <ownership_Percentage>
        </ownership_Percentage>
      </foreignEntity>
    </foreignEntities>
    <inactive_ForeignEntities>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
    </inactive_ForeignEntities>
  </updates>
</LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>