<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='../../ld2webpage.xsl'?>
<LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>
  <imported>Y</imported>
  <pages>3</pages>
  <submitURL>
  </submitURL>
  <organizationName>American Civil Liberties Union</organizationName>
  <prefix>
  </prefix>
  <firstName>
  </firstName>
  <lastName>
  </lastName>
  <registrantDifferentAddress>N</registrantDifferentAddress>
  <address1>915 15TH STREET, NW, 9TH FL</address1>
  <address2>
  </address2>
  <city>WASHINGTON</city>
  <state>DC</state>
  <zip>20005</zip>
  <zipext>
  </zipext>
  <country>USA</country>
  <principal_city>
  </principal_city>
  <principal_state>
  </principal_state>
  <principal_zip>
  </principal_zip>
  <principal_zipext>
  </principal_zipext>
  <principal_country>
  </principal_country>
  <contactIntlPhone>
  </contactIntlPhone>
  <selfSelect>Y</selfSelect>
  <clientName>American Civil Liberties Union</clientName>
  <clientGovtEntity>N</clientGovtEntity>
  <senateID>1901-12</senateID>
  <houseID>321890000</houseID>
  <reportYear>2016</reportYear>
  <reportType>Q1</reportType>
  <terminationDate>
  </terminationDate>
  <noLobbying>
  </noLobbying>
  <income>
  </income>
  <expenses>300871.00</expenses>
  <expensesMethod>A</expensesMethod>
  <printedName>MICHAEL W. MACLEOD-BALL</printedName>
  <signedDate>4/20/2016 4:16:22 PM</signedDate>
  <alis>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>CIV</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Legislation:
SRes104, Operation Streamline-Issue Lobbied: Border Prosecutions. S50, Abortion Non-Discrimination Act-Issue Lobbied: Reproductive Rights. S247, Expatriate Terrorists Act-Issue Lobbied: National Security. S255, Fifth Amendment Integrity Restoration Act-Issue Lobbied: Civil Asset Forfeiture. S356, ECPA Amendments Act of 2015-Issue Lobbied: Privacy. S439, Student Non-Discrimination Act of 2015-Issue Lobbied: LGBT Rights. S467, Corrections Act-Issue Lobbied: Detainers. S524, Comprehensive Addiction and Recovery Act of 2016-Issue Lobbied: Drug Policy Reform. S877, Police CAMERA Act-Issue Lobbied: Body Worn Cameras. S1056, End Racial Profiling Act-Issue Lobbied: Civil Rights, Criminal Justice, Racial Justice, Police Practices. S1169, The Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Reauthorization Act-Issue Lobbied: Civil Rights, Criminal Justice, Racial Justice, Juvenile Justice. S1177, Every Student Succeeds Act of 2015-Issue Lobbied: ESEA reauthorization; Education; School discipline; School climate, LGBT Rights. S1382, Every Child Deserves a Family Act-Issue Lobbied: LGBT Rights. S1512, Pregnant Workers Fairness Act-Issue Lobbied: Womens Rights. S1513, Second Chance Reauthorization Act of 2015-Issue Lobbied: Re-Entry Reform. S1553, Pain-Capable Unborn Child Protection Act-Issue Lobbied: Reproductive Rights- abortion restriction. S1590, Pregnancy Discrimination Amendment Act-Issue Lobbied: Women's Rights. S1598, First Amendment Defense Act-Issue Lobbied: LGBT Rights. S1659, Voting Rights Advancement Act-Issue Lobbied: Voting Rights. S1695, Womens Health Protection Act-Issue Lobbied: Reproductive Rights-  abortion access. S1770, Youth PROMISE Act-Issue Lobbied: Civil Rights, Criminal Justice, Racial Justice, Juvenile Justice. S1808, Northern Border Security Review Act-Issue Lobbied: Border Security. S1858, Equality Act-Issue Lobbied: LGBT Rights, Womens Rights, Reproductive Freedom, Racial Justice. S1864, Department of Homeland Security Border Security Metrics Act-Issue Lobbied: Border Security. S1945, Mental Health Reform Act of 2015-Issue Lobbied: Disability Rights, Access to Justice, Privacy Rights. S2123, Sentencing Reform and Corrections Act-Issue Lobbied: Sentencing Reform, Re-Entry. S2168, Law Enforcement Trust and Integrity Act-Issue Lobbied: Law Enforcement Reform. S2171, The SOAR Reauthorization Act-Issue Lobbied: Religious Liberty/Religion and Public Schools. S2200, Workplace Advancement Act-Issue Lobbied: Womens rights. S2298, Mens Rea Reform Act of 2015-Issue Lobbied: Sentencing Reform. S2337, Visa Waiver Program Security Enhancement Act-Issue Lobbied: Privacy. S2340, MEGABYTE Act of 2015-Issue Lobbied: Free Speech. S2362, Visa Waiver Program Improvement and Terrorist Travel Prevention Act of 2015-Issue Lobbied: Discrimination based on nationality, national origin; National security; Visa waivers. S2369, Community Partnership Act of 2015-Issue Lobbied: Racial Profiling, Countering Violent Extremism, National Security. S2390, FBI Whistleblower Protection Enhancement Act-Issue Lobbied: Whistleblowers, Free Expression. S2418, Countering Online Recruitment of Violent Extremists Act of 2015-Issue Lobbied: Free Speech, Racial Profiling. S2449, Equal Protection in Travel Act of 2016-Issue Lobbied: Discrimination based on nationality, national origin; National security; Visa waivers. S2506, Restoring Statutory Rights and Interests-Issue Lobbied: Arbitration/Womens rights. S2531, Combating BDS Act of 2016-Issue Lobbied: Free Speech. S2540, Fair Day in Court for Kids Act-Issue Lobbied: Counsel. S2576, Support Our Brave Law Enforcement Act-Issue Lobbied: Civil Asset Forfeiture. S2577, Justice for All Act-Issue Lobbied: Criminal Justice. S2658, FAA Reauthorization Act of 2016-Issue Lobbied: Privacy. S2680, Mental Health Reform Act of 2016-Issue Lobbied: Religious Liberty, LGBT Rights, Reproductive Freedom. HRes290, Calling for the global repeal of blasphemy laws-Issue Lobbied: Free Expression. HR5, Student Success Act-Issue Lobbied: Religious Liberty, Religion and Public Schools. HR10, The SOAR Reauthorization Act-Issue Lobbied: Religious Liberty /  Religion and Public Schools. HR36, Pain-Capable Unborn Child Protection Act-Issue Lobbied: Reproductive Rights- abortion restriction. HR158, Visa Waiver Program Improvement and Terrorist Travel Prevention Act of 2015-Issue Lobbied: Discrimination based on nationality, national origin; National security; Visa waivers. HR491, Geolocation Privacy Act-Issue Lobbied: Privacy. HR540, FAIR Act-Issue Lobbied: Civil Asset Forfeiture. HR699, Email Privacy Act-Issue Lobbied: Privacy. HR759, Recidivism Risk Reduction Act-Issue Lobbied: Criminal Justice. HR846, Student Non-Discrimination Act of 2015-Issue Lobbied: LGBT Rights. HR1232, Stop Militarizing Law Enforcement Act-Issue Lobbied: Law Enforcement Militarization. HR1680, Police CAMERA Act-Issue Lobbied: Body Worn Cameras. HR1933, End Racial Profiling Act-Issue Lobbied: Civil Rights, Criminal Justice, Racial Justice, Police Practices. HR2029, Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016-Issue Lobbied: Discrimination based on nationality, national origin; National security; Visa waivers; Cybersecurity. HR2197, Youth PROMISE Act-Issue Lobbied: Civil Rights, Criminal Justice, Racial Justice, Juvenile Justice. HR2449, Every Child Deserves a Family Act-Issue Lobbied: LGBT Rights. HR2646, Helping Families in Mental Health Crisis Act-Issue Lobbied: Disability Rights, Access to Justice, Privacy Rights, LGBT Rights. HR2654, Pregnant Workers Fairness Act-Issue Lobbied: Women's Rights. HR2800, Pregnancy Discrimination Amendment Act-Issue Lobbied: Women's Rights. HR2802, First Amendment Defense Act-Issue Lobbied: LGBT Rights. HR2867, Voting Rights Advancement Act-Issue Lobbied: Voting Rights. HR2875, Law Enforcement Trust and Integrity Act-Issue Lobbied: Law  Enforcement Reform. HR2899, Countering Violent Extremism Act of 2015-Issue Lobbied: Racial Profiling, Countering Violent Extremism, National Security. HR2972, Equal Access to Abortion Coverage in Health Insurance (EACH) Woman Act-Issue Lobbied: Reproductive Rights- abortion coverage restrictions. HR3185, Equality Act-Issue Lobbied: LGBT Rights, Womens Rights, Reproductive Freedom, Racial Justice. HR3406, Second Chance Reauthorization Act of 2015-Issue Lobbied: Re-Entry Reform. HR3504, Born-Alive Abortion Survivors Protection Act-Issue Lobbied: Reproductive Rights- abortion restrictions. HR3516, Social Security Beneficiary 2nd Amendment Rights Protection Act-Issue Lobbied: Disability Rights. HR3576, Border Enforcement Accountability, Oversight and Community Engagement Act of 2015-Issue Lobbied: CBP oversight and accountability. HR3586, Border and Maritime Coordination Improvement Act-Issue Lobbied: Border security. HR3654, Combat Terrorist Use of Social Media Act of 2015-Issue Lobbied: Privacy, First Amendment. HR3713, Sentencing Reform Act-Issue Lobbied: Sentencing Reform. HR3841, Security and Financial Empowerment Act of 2015-Issue Lobbied: Paid leave. HR4002, The Criminal Code Improvement Act-Issue Lobbied: Criminal Justice. HR4303, Border Security and Accountability Act of 2015-Issue Lobbied: Border security. HR4380, Equal Protection in Travel Act of 2016-Issue Lobbied: Discrimination based on nationality, national origin; National security; Visa waivers. HR4441, Aviation Innovation, Reform and Reauthorization Act of 2016-Issue Lobbied: Drones. HR4514, Combating BDS Act of 2016-Issue Lobbied: Free Speech. HR4532, Safe Harbor for Reporting Violent Behavior Act of 2016-Issue Lobbied: Free Expression. HR4602, Justice for All Act-Issue Lobbied: Criminal Justice. HR4611, No More Money Bail Act-Issue Lobbied: Right to Counsel. HR4646, Fair Day in Court for Kids Act-Issue Lobbied: Counsel. HR4651, Digital Security Commission Act of 2016-Issue Lobbied: Privacy, Surveillance. HR4889, Kelsey Smith Act-Issue Lobbied: Privacy.

Congressional Issues, No Bill Number:
Select Panel on Infant Lives - Fetal Tissue Research-Issue Lobbied: Reproductive Rights, Abortion Access. Zubik v. Burwell-ACA contraception coverage-Issue Lobbied: Reproductive rights- contraception. DUE PROCESS Act-Issue Lobbied: Civil Asset Forfeiture. National Right to Counsel Act-Issue Lobbied: Right to Counsel. Compliance with Courts Orders Act of 2016-Issue Lobbied: Privacy, Surveillance. Healthy Families Act-Issue Lobbied: Womens Rights. Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Reauthorization Act of 2015-Issue Lobbied: Juvenile Justice. Federal RFRA fix legislation-Issue Lobbied: Religious Liberty/Refusals. Inspector General Empowerment Act-Issue Lobbied: Subpoena Authority. FY 17 Appropriations-Issue Lobbied: Immigration, Juvenile Justice, Abortion, Hyde Amendment. FY17 National Defense Authorization Act-Issue Lobbied: National Security; Guantanamo Bay; Indefinite Detention; Military Commissions Act; Torture, Abortion ban. December 2014 Guidance for Federal Law Enforcement Agencies  Regarding the Use of Race, Ethnicity, Gender, National Origin, Religion, Sexual Orientation, or Gender Identity-Issue Lobbied: Racial Profiling, Civil Rights, Criminal Justice, Racial Justice, Police Practices, Countering Violent Extremism, National Security. Title I Portability in the Reauthorization of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act-Issue Lobbied: Religious Liberty /  Religion and Public Schools. Drone Reform-Issue Lobbied: National Security; Targeted Killing. Plan to Close Guantanamo-Issue Lobbied: National Security; Guantanamo; Indefinite Detention; Torture; Military Commissions Act. CBP oversight and excessive use of force-Issue Lobbied: Immigration. Deportation and detention practices-Issue Lobbied: Immigration. Interior and Border enforcement-Issue Lobbied: Immigration. Women in Combat-Issue Lobbied: Womens Rights. Pay equity/data collection-Issue Lobbied: Womens Rights. Nuisance ordinances-Issue Lobbied: Womens rights. Immigration enforcement, Central American families, Sensitive Locations-Issue Lobbied: Immigration. Syrian refugees; Discrimination based on nationality, national origin, religion; National security-Issue Lobbied: Immigration. DHS immigration enforcement: Secure Communities; Priority Enforcement Program (PEP); detainers; sanctuary cities-Issue Lobbied: Immigration. Family/Immigration detention, Treatment of refugee women and children/victims of violence-Issue Lobbied: Immigration. Unaccompanied children: Due process, Expedited removals, Access to counsel-Issue Lobbied: Immigration. Bond hearings, Prolonged detention-Issue Lobbied: Immigration. Voting rights-Issue Lobbied: Voting rights. Health care-Issue Lobbied: Religious refusals. Privacy Shield-Issue Lobbied: Privacy. Office of Legal Counsel transparency-Issue Lobbied: Government transparency. Late Term abortion-Issue Lobbied: Abortion rights. Material Witness-Issue Lobbied: National security, criminal justice. Housing discrimination-Issue Lobbied: Discrimination. Broadband privacy-Issue Lobbied: Broadband access. Flint water crisis-Issue Lobbied: Government transparency. Encryption-Issue Lobbied: Privacy. Academic freedom-Issue Lobbied: Free Expression. Forced arbitration-Issue Lobbied: Workplace rights. Access to counsel-Issue Lobbied: Criminal justice. Anti-trafficking legislation-Issue Lobbied: Religious refusals. Countering Violent Extremism-Issue Lobbied: Racial Profiling, National Security. Refugee restrictions and visa waivers-Issue Lobbied: National origin discrimination, immigration, privacy, social media. Lifeline expansion-Issue Lobbied: Broadband access. Border and Privacy Issues-Issue Lobbied: Immigration, Privacy. Political Speech and C3 institutions-Issue Lobbied: First Amendment. Sentencing Reform-Issue Lobbied: Criminal justice reform. Bail Reform-Issue Lobbied: Criminal justice reform. FOIA reform-Issue Lobbied: Government transparency. Cybersecurity-Issue Lobbied: Privacy. ECPA reform-Issue Lobbied: Privacy. Social Media Monitoring and Restrictions-Issue Lobbied: Privacy, Free expression. School vouchers/DC vouchers-Issue Lobbied: Religious freedom. FISA Section 702-Issue Lobbied: Surveillance. Marijuana reform/New Jersey-Issue Lobbied: Criminal justice reform. Indefinite detention-Issue Lobbied: National security. Body-worn cameras-Issue Lobbied: Law enforcement reform. Telecommunications. Disability Rights.

Agencies:
Bureau of Justice Statistics-Issue Lobbied: Provision 115.42(g) of the National Standards to Prevent, Detect, and Respond to Prison Rape &amp; Tran-specific Pods/Units. Bureau of Prisons-Issue Lobbied: Sentencing Reform, Prison Reform, Solitary Confinement, Re-entry. Corporation for National and Community Service-Issue Lobbied: AmeriCorps Volunteer directions re: abortion counseling and referrals. Department of Agriculture-Issue Lobbied: Reforms to the Faith-Based Initiative and to the Notice of Proposed Rulemaking (NPRM) Amendment to Participation by Religious Organizations in USAID Programs to Implement Executive Order 13559". Department of Defense-Issue Lobbied: EO 12333 and Section 702 surveillance; Proposed Rule, RIN 0720-AB65; Guantanamo Bay; Trans healthcare. Department of Education-Issue Lobbied: Every Student Succeeds Act of 2015; Immigration enforcement, Sensitive locations; Reforms to the Faith-Based Initiative and to the Notice of Proposed Rulemaking (NPRM) Amendment to Participation by Religious Organizations in USAID Programs to Implement Executive Order 13559"; Juvenile Justice, Racial Justice. Department of Health and Human Services-Issue Lobbied: Preventing HHS from excluding quality womens health providers from essential public health programs; Access to contraception and abortion care in ORR; Interior and Border enforcement, Unaccompanied Minors, Immigration enforcement, Sensitive locations; 1557 Proposed Rule of the Affordable Care Act (ACA) and the Notice of Proposed Rulemaking; Reforms to the Faith-Based Initiative and to the Notice of Proposed Rulemaking (NPRM) Amendment to Participation by Religious Organizations in USAID Programs to Implement Executive Order 13559". Department of Homeland Security-Issue Lobbied: Law Enforcement Reform; Interior and Border enforcement; Unaccompanied Minors; End Racial Profiling Act (ERPA); Countering Violent Extremism Act of 2015 / Community Partnership Act of 2015; December 2014 Guidance for Federal Law Enforcement Agencies  Regarding the Use of Race, Ethnicity, Gender, National Origin, Religion, Sexual Orientation, or Gender Identity; Visa Waiver Program Improvement and Terrorist Travel Prevention Act of 2015; Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016; Equal Protection in Travel Act of 2016;  Central American families; Syrian refugees; DHS immigration enforcement (Secure Communities); Priority Enforcement Program; Family detention; Due process; Immigration enforcement, sensitive locations; 'Sanctuary' cities; Detainers; Raids; Discrimination based on nationality, national origin, religion; Bond hearings, Prolonged detention; Treatment of refugee women and children/ victims of violence; Reforms to the Faith-Based Initiative and to the Notice of Proposed Rulemaking (NPRM) Amendment to Participation by Religious Organizations in USAID Programs to Implement Executive Order 13559"; 287g.. Department of Housing and Urban Development-Issue Lobbied: Fair Housing, AFFH; Reforms to the Faith-Based Initiative and to the Notice of Proposed Rulemaking (NPRM) Amendment to Participation by Religious Organizations in USAID Programs to Implement Executive Order 13559"; Proposed Rule, RIN 2506-AC40 (Equal Access in Accordance with an Individuals Gender Identity in Community Planning and Development Programs). Department of Justice-Issue Lobbied: Sentencing Reform, Prison Reform, Solitary Confinement, Law Enforcement Reform, Re-entry Reform; DICRA data collection; Interior and Border enforcement, Unaccompanied Minors; EO 12333 and Section 702 surveillance, Location Tracking Devices, "Stingrays"; Gender biased policing; 2007 OLC Memo on RFRA; End Racial Profiling Act (ERPA); Countering Violent Extremism Act of 2015 / Community Partnership Act of 2015; December 2014 Guidance for Federal Law Enforcement Agencies Regarding the Use of Race, Ethnicity, Gender, National Origin, Religion, Sexual Orientation, or Gender Identity; Fair Day in Court for Kids Act of 2016; Central American families; Due process/Access to counsel; Immigration enforcement; Family/immigration detention; Treatment of refugee women and children/victims of violence; Expedited removals; 1557 Proposed Rule of the Affordable Care Act (ACA) and the Notice of Proposed Rulemaking; Reforms to the Faith-Based Initiative and to the Notice of Proposed Rulemaking (NPRM) Amendment to Participation by Religious Organizations in USAID Programs to Implement Executive Order 13559". Department of Labor-Issue Lobbied: Proposed rule re: nondiscrimination and equal opportunity provision of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act; Proposed Rule re: establishing paid sick leave for federal contractors; Reforms to the Faith-Based Initiative and to the Notice of Proposed Rulemaking (NPRM) Amendment to Participation by Religious Organizations in USAID Programs to Implement Executive Order 13559"; Proposed Rule, RIN 1205-AB59 (Apprenticeship Programs; Equal Employment Opportunity Regulations). Department of Veterans Affairs-Issue Lobbied: Reforms to the Faith-Based Initiative and to the Notice of Proposed Rulemaking (NPRM) Amendment to Participation by Religious Organizations in USAID Programs to Implement Executive Order 13559". Director of National Intelligence-Issue Lobbied: EO 12333 and Section 702 surveillance; Transparency. EEOC-Issue Lobbied: Pay equity/data collection; Sex discrimination. Election Assistance Commission-Issue Lobbied: Voting restrictions. EOIR-Issue Lobbied: Fair Day in Court for Kids Act of 2016; Unaccompanied children; Due process; Expedited removals; Access to counsel. Executive Office of the President-Issue Lobbied: Immigration (temporary protected status, enforcement, raids); Data sharing; Torture accountability; Trans military service; Budget; Cross-border data flow; Drug laws; Visa Waiver Program; Flint water issue; ACA non-discrimination; Re-entry; UNGASS; FOIA reform; North Carolina anti-LGBT law; Encryption. Federal Aviation Administration-Issue Lobbied: Domestic Drones. Federal Bureau of Investigation-Issue Lobbied: Location Tracking Devices, Stingrays," encryption, government "back doors," Countering Violent Extremism. Federal Communications Commission-Issue Lobbied: Prison phone rates, Broadband privacy, Set-top box proposal, Lifeline expansion, Zero rating. Federal Trade Commission-Issue Lobbied: Privacy. Food and Drug Administration-Issue Lobbied: Abortion regulations. National Security Agency-Issue Lobbied: EO 12333 and Section 702 surveillance. Office of Refugee Resettlement (ACF)-Issue Lobbied: Access to contraception and abortion care in ORR. Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board-Issue Lobbied: EO 12333 and Section 702 surveillance. Transportation Security Administration-Issue Lobbied: December 2014 Guidance for Federal Law Enforcement Agencies  Regarding the Use of Race, Ethnicity, Gender, National Origin, Religion, Sexual Orientation, or Gender Identity. U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services-Issue Lobbied: Family detention, Immigration detention, Treatment of refugee women and children/ victims of violence. U.S. Commission on Civil Rights-Issue Lobbied: Debtor prisons. U.S. Customs and Border Protection-Issue Lobbied: Border enforcement/ CBP oversight and excessive use of force; December 2014 Guidance for Federal Law Enforcement Agencies  Regarding the Use of Race, Ethnicity, Gender, National Origin, Religion, Sexual Orientation, or Gender Identity. U.S. Department of State-Issue Lobbied: Equal Protection in Travel Act of 2016. U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement-Issue Lobbied: Deportation and detention practices, Central American families, Syrian refugees, DHS immigration enforcement (Secure Communities), Priority Enforcement Program, Family detention, Treatment of refugee women and children/victims of violence, Due process, Sensitive locations, 'Sanctuary' cities, Detainers; Discrimination based on nationality, national origin, religion. USAID-Issue Lobbied: Reforms to the Faith-Based Initiative and to the Notice of Proposed Rulemaking (NPRM) Amendment to Participation by Religious Organizations in USAID Programs to Implement Executive Order 13559". U.S. Sentencing Commission-Issue Lobbied: Sentencing Reform, Compassionate Release, Illegal entry crimes. White House-Issue Lobbied: Zubik v. Burwell; Access to contraception and abortion care in ORR; Sentencing Reform, Private Prisons, Solitary Confinement, Drug Policy, Clemency, Re-entry reform; Law Enforcement Reform; FY17 National Defense Authorization Act; Drone Reform; Plan to Close Guantanamo, National Security; Indefinite Detention; Torture; Military Commissions Act; Targeted Killing; Interior and Border enforcement, Unaccompanied Minors; Gender biased policing; End Racial Profiling Act (ERPA); Countering Violent Extremism Act of 2015/Community Partnership Act of 2015; December 2014 Guidance for Federal Law Enforcement Agencies  Regarding the Use of Race, Ethnicity, Gender, National Origin, Religion, Sexual Orientation, or Gender Identity; Every Student Succeeds Act of 2015, Visa Waiver Program Improvement and Terrorist Travel Prevention Act of 2015; Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016; Equal Protection in Travel Act of 2016; Fair Day in Court for Kids Act of 2016; Central American families; Syrian refugees; DHS immigration enforcement (Secure Communities); Priority Enforcement Program; Family detention; Due process/Access to counsel; Expedited removals; Sensitive locations; 'Sanctuary' cities; Detainers; Discrimination based on nationality, national origin, religion; Treatment of refugee women and children/victims of violence; 2007 OLC Memo on RFRA; 1557 Proposed Rule of the Affordable Care Act (ACA) and the Notice of Proposed Rulemaking.</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Education - Dept of, White House Office, Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), Federal Bureau of Prisons (BOP), Federal Communications Commission (FCC), U.S. Citizenship &amp; Immigration Services (USCIS), Justice - Dept of  (DOJ), Homeland Security - Dept of  (DHS), Health &amp; Human Services - Dept of (HHS), Housing &amp; Urban Development - Dept of (HUD), Executive Office of the President (EOP), Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), U.S. Customs &amp; Border Protection, U.S. Immigration &amp; Customs Enforcement (ICE), Bureau of Justice Statistics, Food &amp; Drug Administration (FDA), Transportation Security Administration (TSA), Agriculture - Dept of (USDA), Defense - Dept of (DOD), Labor - Dept of (DOL), Veterans Affairs - Dept of (VA), Director of National Intelligence (ODNI), U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), Corporation for Natl &amp; Community Service, Election Assistance Commission (EAC), Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC), Federal Trade Commission (FTC), Natl Security Agency (NSA), U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, State - Dept of (DOS), Administration for Children &amp; Families (ACF)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Michael </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Macleod-Ball</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Christopher </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Anders</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jennifer </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Bellamy</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kanya </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Bennett</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Neema</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Guliani</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Vania </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Leveille</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Joanne </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Lin</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jesselyn</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>McCurdy</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Chris</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Rickerd</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Ian</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Thompson</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Georgeanne</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Usova</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Michael</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Garvey</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Heejin</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Hwang</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Rachel </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Marshall</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Tyler</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Ray</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Nathaniel</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Turner</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Justin </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Roberts</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
  </alis>
  <updates>
    <clientAddress>
    </clientAddress>
    <clientCity>
    </clientCity>
    <clientState>
    </clientState>
    <clientZip>
    </clientZip>
    <clientZipext>
    </clientZipext>
    <clientCountry>
    </clientCountry>
    <prinClientCity>
    </prinClientCity>
    <prinClientState>
    </prinClientState>
    <prinClientZip>
    </prinClientZip>
    <prinClientZipext>
    </prinClientZipext>
    <prinClientCountry>
    </prinClientCountry>
    <generalDescription>
    </generalDescription>
    <inactive_lobbyists>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>Gabriel </firstName>
        <lastName>Rottman</lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>Carla Ruth</firstName>
        <lastName>Epstein</lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
    </inactive_lobbyists>
    <inactive_ALIs>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
    </inactive_ALIs>
    <affiliatedUrl>
    </affiliatedUrl>
    <affiliatedOrgs>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>ACLU Foundation</affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>125 Broad St</affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>New York</affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>NY</affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>10004</affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>USA</affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
    </affiliatedOrgs>
    <inactiveOrgs>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
    </inactiveOrgs>
    <foreignEntities>
      <foreignEntity>
        <name>
        </name>
        <address>
        </address>
        <city>
        </city>
        <state>
        </state>
        <country>
        </country>
        <prinCity>
        </prinCity>
        <prinState>
        </prinState>
        <prinCountry>
        </prinCountry>
        <contribution>
        </contribution>
        <ownership_Percentage>
        </ownership_Percentage>
      </foreignEntity>
    </foreignEntities>
    <inactive_ForeignEntities>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
    </inactive_ForeignEntities>
  </updates>
</LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>