<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='../../ld2webpage.xsl'?>
<LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>
  <imported>Y</imported>
  <pages>8</pages>
  <submitURL>
  </submitURL>
  <organizationName>National Active and Retired Federal Employees Association</organizationName>
  <prefix>
  </prefix>
  <firstName>
  </firstName>
  <lastName>
  </lastName>
  <registrantDifferentAddress>N</registrantDifferentAddress>
  <address1>606 NORTH WASHINGTON STREET</address1>
  <address2>
  </address2>
  <city>ALEXANDRIA</city>
  <state>VA</state>
  <zip>22314</zip>
  <zipext>7760</zipext>
  <country>USA</country>
  <principal_city>
  </principal_city>
  <principal_state>
  </principal_state>
  <principal_zip>
  </principal_zip>
  <principal_zipext>
  </principal_zipext>
  <principal_country>
  </principal_country>
  <contactIntlPhone>
  </contactIntlPhone>
  <selfSelect>Y</selfSelect>
  <clientName>National Active and Retired Federal Employees Association</clientName>
  <clientGovtEntity>N</clientGovtEntity>
  <senateID>27081-12</senateID>
  <houseID>302690000</houseID>
  <reportYear>2016</reportYear>
  <reportType>Q1</reportType>
  <terminationDate>
  </terminationDate>
  <noLobbying>
  </noLobbying>
  <income>
  </income>
  <expenses>70000.00</expenses>
  <expensesMethod>A</expensesMethod>
  <printedName>John Hatton</printedName>
  <signedDate>5/6/2016 3:59:50 PM</signedDate>
  <alis>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>GOV</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Support H.R. 4585, The Federal Adjustment of Income Rates (FAIR) Act, which provides for a 3.98 percent pay raise for federal employees, along with a 1.4 percent average locality pay increase.

Support S. 2699, The Federal Adjustment of Income Rates (FAIR) Act, which provides for a 5.3 percent pay raise for federal employees.

Support H.R. 485, the Wage Grade Employee Parity Act, which provides the President with the authority to provide a pay raise for wage grade (or hourly) employees, whose raises must be authorized by Congress currently. The President currently has the authority with regard to pay raises for federal employees on the General Schedule.

Support H.R. 785, the Federal Employee Pension Fairness Act, which would repeal laws passed in 2012 and 2013 that increased the Federal Employees Retirement System contributions for newly-hired federal employees.

Support H.R. 313, the Wounded Warriors Federal Leave Act which entitles any federal employee who is a veteran with a service-connected disability rated at 30 percent or more, during the 12-month period beginning on the first day of employment, up to 104 hours of leave, without loss or reduction in pay, for purposes of undergoing medical treatment for the disability for which sick leave could regularly be used.

Support S. 164, the Wounded Warriors Federal Leave Act which entitles any federal employee who is a veteran with a service-connected disability rated at 30 percent or more, during the 12-month period beginning on the first day of employment, up to 104 hours of leave, without loss or reduction in pay, for purposes of undergoing medical treatment for the disability for which sick leave could regularly be used.

H.R. 138, the Access to Insurance for All Americans Act, which repeals the Affordable Care Act and establishes a national health program administered by the Office of Personnel Management to offer Federal Employees Health Benefits Program plans to individuals who are not federal employees or retirees. It creates separate risk pools for federal and non-federal participants.

Support H.R. 532, the Federal Employees Paid Parental Leave Act of 2015, providing paid parental leave for federal employees.

Support S. 2033, the Federal Employees Paid Parental Leave Act of 2015, providing paid parental leave for federal employees.

Support H.R. 20, the Government By the People Act, which reforms campaign finance laws to put small donors to political campaigns on par with wealthier donors. It provides tax credits for campaign contributions and government matching contributions.

Support H.R. 2175, the FEHBP Prescription Drug Oversight Act, which provides the Office of Personnel Management greater oversight authority over the prescription drug contracting and pricing methods of the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program.

Support H.R. 2827, the Competitive Service Act, and S. 1580, the Competitive Service Act, which both would allow federal agencies to review and select job candidates from other federal agencies' "best qualified list" of applicants.

Support H.R. 3029, the RECOVER Act, which requires the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to provide each individual whose personally identifiable information was compromised during data breaches of personnel records of federal employees in a network maintained by the Department of the Interior or in OPM systems containing federal employee background investigations with comprehensive identity protection coverage that is effective for the life of the individual and that includes not less than $5 million in identity theft insurance.

Support S. 1746, the RECOVER Act, which requires the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to provide each individual whose personally identifiable information was compromised during data breaches of personnel records of federal employees in a network maintained by the Department of the Interior or in OPM systems containing federal employee background investigations with comprehensive identity protection coverage that is effective for the life of the individual and that includes not less than $5 million in identity theft insurance.

Support S. 2035, the Federal Employee Fair Treatment Act, which would require federal employees furloughed or required to work due to a lapse in appropriations beginning on or after October 1, 2015, to be compensated after the lapse in appropriations ends. Employees required to work during the lapse in appropriations are permitted to use leave. The bill addresses a lapse in appropriations scheduled to occur if FY2016 appropriations legislation is not enacted prior to the beginning of the fiscal year on October 1, 2015.

Oppose including a provision to reduce the rate of return on the Thrift Savings Plan G Fund in unrelated legislation, notably surface transportation spending authorization legislation.

Support an extension to 10 years of identity restoration services and theft insurance provided to federal employees, retirees, spouses, and applicants effected by OPM security breaches. Support inclusion in appropriations bill.

Support H.R. 3850, the Annuity Safety and Security Under Reasonable Enforcement (ASSURE) Act, which requires appropriate disclosures regarding "pension advance" schemes and caps the interest rates on these advances. Also creates a private right of action to allow individuals to enforce these laws in court.

Support H.R. 1314, the Bipartisan Budget Act of 2015, for its provisions to offset sequestration caps for annual discretionary spending / government funding, without including mandatory spending cuts affecting federal employees and retirees. Also support Medicare Part B premium provision (detailed in that issue area description).   </description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Office of Personnel Management (OPM)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jessica</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Klement</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>John</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Hatton</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Richard</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Thissen</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>POS</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Support H. Res. 12, in support of six-day delivery.

Support H. Res. 28, in support of to-the-door delivery.

Support H. Res. 54, in support of maintaining service standards.

Support H.R. 784, the Protect Overnight Delivery Act.

Support S. 1742, the Rural Postal Act of 2015. The bill would return service standards to July 2012 standards, preserves six-day delivery, and would put a two-year moratorium on plant closures.

Oppose provisions of S. 2051, The Improving Postal Operations, Service and Transparency Act (iPost) of 2015, (i) to require postal employees to enroll in Medicare in order to continue to receive their current federal health insurance coverage and (ii) to cut workers' compensation benefits for injured federal employees. </description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, U.S. Postal Service (USPS), Office of Personnel Management (OPM)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jessica</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Klement</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>John</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Hatton</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Richard </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Thissen</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>BUD</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Oppose H. Con. Res. 27, which assumed a total of $318 billion in budget "savings" from the federal workforce.

Oppose S. Con Res. 11, which assumed $170 billion in budget "savings" from the federal workforce.

Support H.R. 1314, the Bipartisan Budget Act of 2015, for its provisions to offset sequestration caps for annual discretionary spending / government funding, without including mandatory spending cuts affecting federal employees and retirees. Also support Medicare Part B premium provision (detailed in that issue area description).

Oppose H. Con. Res. 125, which assumes massive budget cuts from the federal workforce. 
</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jessica </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Klement</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>John</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Hatton</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Richard </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Thissen</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>RET</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Support H.R. 973, the Social Security Fairness Act of 2015, which repeals both the Government Pension Offset (GPO) and the Windfall Elimination Provision (WEP).

Support S. 1651, the Social Security Fairness Act of 2015, which repeals both the Government Pension Offset (GPO) and the Windfall Elimination Provision (WEP).

Support H.R. 711, the Equal Treatment of Public Servants Act, which would reform the WEP, reducing its penalty for current benficiaries, and on average and for most future beneficiaries.

Support S. 2251, the Seniors and Veterans Emergency (SAVE) Benefits Act, which would provide a $581 payment for Social Security beneficiaries and veterans or tax credit for government retirees in lieu of a cost-of-living adjustment for 2016. Also support H.R. 4144 and H.R. 4012, essentially identical bills in the House.

Support H.R. 3351, the CPI-E Act of 2015, which would base cost-of-living adjustments for federal retirement benefits on the CPI-E (price index for the elderly) instead of the CPI-W.
</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, U.S. SENATE</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>John</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Hatton</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jessica </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Klement</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Richard</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Thissen</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>DOC</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Support H.R. 317, the New Columbia Admissions Act, which would make the District of Columbia a state.</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, U.S. SENATE</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>John</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Hatton</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jessica </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Klement</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Richard</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Thissen</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>MMM</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Support administrative action or legislation to prevent a disproportionate increase in Medicare Part B premiums for about 30 percent of beneficiaries, including hundreds of thousands of federal retirees.

Support H.R. 3696, the Medicare Premium Fairness Act of 2015 &amp; S. 2148, the Protecting Medicare Beneficiaries Act of 2015. Both bills would keep Medicare Part B premiums and deductibles at 2015 levels for all beneficiaries in 2016.

Support H.R. 1314 for its provisions to lower 2016 Medicare Part B premiums for those individuals not held harmless from an increase.</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, U.S. SENATE, Centers For Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS), Health &amp; Human Services - Dept of (HHS)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>John</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Hatton</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jessica </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Klement</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Richard </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Thissen</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
  </alis>
  <updates>
    <clientAddress>
    </clientAddress>
    <clientCity>
    </clientCity>
    <clientState>
    </clientState>
    <clientZip>
    </clientZip>
    <clientZipext>
    </clientZipext>
    <clientCountry>
    </clientCountry>
    <prinClientCity>
    </prinClientCity>
    <prinClientState>
    </prinClientState>
    <prinClientZip>
    </prinClientZip>
    <prinClientZipext>
    </prinClientZipext>
    <prinClientCountry>
    </prinClientCountry>
    <generalDescription>
    </generalDescription>
    <inactive_lobbyists>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
    </inactive_lobbyists>
    <inactive_ALIs>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
    </inactive_ALIs>
    <affiliatedUrl>
    </affiliatedUrl>
    <affiliatedOrgs>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
    </affiliatedOrgs>
    <inactiveOrgs>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
    </inactiveOrgs>
    <foreignEntities>
      <foreignEntity>
        <name>
        </name>
        <address>
        </address>
        <city>
        </city>
        <state>
        </state>
        <country>
        </country>
        <prinCity>
        </prinCity>
        <prinState>
        </prinState>
        <prinCountry>
        </prinCountry>
        <contribution>
        </contribution>
        <ownership_Percentage>
        </ownership_Percentage>
      </foreignEntity>
    </foreignEntities>
    <inactive_ForeignEntities>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
    </inactive_ForeignEntities>
  </updates>
</LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>