<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='../../ld2webpage.xsl'?>
<LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>
  <imported>Y</imported>
  <pages>3</pages>
  <submitURL>
  </submitURL>
  <organizationName>Competitive Carriers Association</organizationName>
  <prefix>
  </prefix>
  <firstName>
  </firstName>
  <lastName>
  </lastName>
  <registrantDifferentAddress>N</registrantDifferentAddress>
  <address1>805 15th Street N.W.</address1>
  <address2>Suite 401</address2>
  <city>Washington</city>
  <state>DC</state>
  <zip>20005</zip>
  <zipext>
  </zipext>
  <country>USA</country>
  <principal_city>
  </principal_city>
  <principal_state>
  </principal_state>
  <principal_zip>
  </principal_zip>
  <principal_zipext>
  </principal_zipext>
  <principal_country>
  </principal_country>
  <contactIntlPhone>
  </contactIntlPhone>
  <selfSelect>Y</selfSelect>
  <clientName>Competitive Carriers Association</clientName>
  <clientGovtEntity>N</clientGovtEntity>
  <senateID>400569709-12</senateID>
  <houseID>412300000</houseID>
  <reportYear>2016</reportYear>
  <reportType>Q1</reportType>
  <terminationDate>
  </terminationDate>
  <noLobbying>
  </noLobbying>
  <income>
  </income>
  <expenses>150000.00</expenses>
  <expensesMethod>A</expensesMethod>
  <printedName>Timothy Donovan</printedName>
  <signedDate>4/20/2016 3:54:10 PM</signedDate>
  <alis>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>TEC</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>Issues relating to the Universal Service Fund, including High Cost Fund, Connect America Fund, Mobility Fund, and the Lifeline Program 
Issues relating to Spectrum, including Federal Spectrum and Unlicensed Spectrum
Issues relating to Copyright Reform and Mobile Device Unlocking
Issues relating to Spectrum Auctions, including the incentive Auction, and Implementation of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012
Issues relating to the IP Transition and Interconnection
Issues relating to Device Exclusivity
Issues relating to Data Roaming
Issues relating to E911, NG911, and Location Accuracy 
Issues relating to Federal Communications Commission Authority and Process
Issues relating to Truth-in-Billing
Issues relating to Special Access (Business Data Services) 
Issues relating to Privacy
Issues relating to Cybersecurity
Issues relating to Patent Litigation Reform
Issues relating to Rural Broadband
Issues relating to Updates to the Communications Act of 1934 
Issues relating to Internet Tax Reform 
Issues relating to FCC Appropriations and FY17 Budget and Funding Requests 
Issues relating to Number Portability 
Issues relating to FirstNet 
Issues relating to siting on Federal lands. 
Issues relating to LTE-U
Issues relating to Net Neutrality Small Business Exemption 
Issues relating to FCC Reauthorization 
Issues relating to Encryption 
Issues relating to Section 106 of the National Historic Preservation Act 


Discussion Draft Targeting Rogue and Opaque Letters Act of 2015 issues relating to patent assertion demand letters (PATENT REFORM) 
S. 2644, FCC Reauthorization Act of 2016  (FCC REAUTHORIZATION) 
Discussion Draft, To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to ensure Internet openness, to prohibit blocking lawful content and non-harmful devices, to prohibit throttling data, to prohibit paid prioritization, to require transparency of network management practices, to provide that broadband shall be considered to be an information service, and to prohibit the Commission or a State commission from relying on section 706 of the Telecommunications Act of 1996 as a grant of authority. (Issues relating to regulatory treatment of mobile broadband.)  
H.R. 9, The Innovation Act, issues relating to patent assertion
S, 632, the STRONG Patents Act, issues relating to patent assertion
H.R. 1770, the Data Security and Breach Notification Act, issues relating to breach notification standards for mobile carriers 
H.R. 1587, the Unlocking Technology Act, issues relating to unlocking mobile devices 
S. 734, the USF Fair and Equitable Distribution Act, issues relating to USF support for mobile broadband
H.R. 1641, the Federal Spectrum Incentive Auction Act, issues relating to reallocating spectrum for commercial mobile broadband use. 
S. 887, the Federal Spectrum Incentive Auction Act, issues relating to reallocating spectrum for commercial mobile broadband use. 
H.R. 1506, the Small Business Access to Spectrum Act, issues relating to bidding credits and the designated entity program. 
S. 417, the Rural Spectrum Accessibility Act, issues relating to making spectrum available in rural areas for commercial mobile broadband use. 
H.R 821, the Wi-Fi Innovation Act, issues relating to unlicensed spectrum for broadband use. 
S. 424, the Wi-Fi Innovation Act, issues relating to unlicensed spectrum for broadband use
S. 421, the Federal Communications Commission Process Reform Act, issues relating to FCC authority and process 
H.R. 1396, the Federal Communication Commission Collaboration Act, issues relating to FCC authority and process 
S. 760, The Federal Communications Commission Collaboration Act, issues relating to FCC authority and process 
S. 253, the Federal Communications Commission Consolidated Reporting Act, issues relating to the Mobile Broadband Competition Report
H.R. 1409, the Open Internet Act, issues relating to regulatory treatment of mobile broadband
H.R. 1212, The Internet Freedom Act, issues relating to regulatory treatment of mobile broadband 
S. 56, the Ending Mobile Phone Welfare Act, issues relating to the Lifeline program
H.R. 266, the End Taxpayer Funded Cell Phones Act, issues relating to the Lifeline program
H.R. 279, To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to limit the authority of the Federal Communications Commission over providers of broadband Internet access service. Issues relating to regulatory treatment of mobile broadband 
H.R. 196, the Online Competition and Consumer Choice Act, issues relating to regulatory treatment of mobile broadband
S. 40, The Online Competition and Consumer Choice Act, issues relating to regulatory treatment of mobile broadband
H.R. 2048, The USA Freedom Act, issues relating to cybersecurity 
H.R. 2583, The FCC Process Reform Act, issues relating to FCC authority and process 
H.R. 1731, the National Cybersecurity Protection Advancement Act, issues relating to cybersecurity
H.R. 2045, the Targeting Rogue and Opaque Letters Act, issues relating to patent assertion demand letters 
H.R. 2205, the Data Security Act of 2015, issues relating to cybersecurity 
S. 1606, the Digital Learning Equity Act of 2015, issues relating to mobile broadband access 
S. 1618, the Wireless Innovation Act, issues relating to mobile broadband access 
S. 1137, the PATENT Act, issues relating to patent assertion demand letters 
Discussion Draft, to provide quarterly reports on pending requests for action by the Federal Communications Commission and pending Congressional investigations, issues relating to FCC authority and process 
Discussion Draft, to Amend the Communications Act of 1934 to provide for publication on the internet website of the Federal Communications Commission of certain policies and procedures established by the Chairman of the commission. Issues relating to FCC authority and process 
S. 2555, the MOBILE NOW ACT Issues relating to spectrum, mobile infrastructure 
H.R. 2029, Consolidated Appropriations Act of 2016. Issues relating to Universal Service Fund support
S.2283/H.R. 4596, The Small Business Broadband Deployment Act of 2015 Issues relating to net neutrality enhanced transparency reporting requirements for small businesses
H.R. 2666, The No Rate Regulation of Broadband Internet Act. Issues relating to FCC authority
S. 2607, The DIGIT Act of 2016. Issues relating to the Internet of Things 
H.R. 4889, the Kelsey Smith Act of 2016. Issues relating to device location in emergency situations
H.R. 4884, Controlling the Unchecked and Reckless Ballooning of the Lifeline Fund Act (CURB Lifeline) Issues relating to the Lifeline program 
H.R. 4111, Rural Health Care Connectivity Act of 2015. Issues relating to tele-health, connectivity and rural healthcare 
H.R. 4190, Spectrum Challenge Prize Act of 2015. Issues relating to spectrum efficiency
H.R. 3998, Securing Access to Networks in Disasters (SANDy) Act. Issues relating to carrier obligations in emergency situations
S. 2733, Venue Equity and Non-Uniformity Elimination Act of 2016 (VENUE ACT). Issues relating to venue selection for patent litigation  
H.R. 4829, Trade Protection Not Troll Protection Act. Issues relating to venue selection for patent litigation 
</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Timothy</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Donovan</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Steven</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Berry</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>Chief Counsel, Senate Committee on Foreign Relations</coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Maribeth</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Collins</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>Rep. Patrick Meehan, Legislative Director '11
Rep. Bill Shuster, LA, LC, Staff Asst. '05-'11</coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>
          </lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>
          </lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
  </alis>
  <updates>
    <clientAddress>
    </clientAddress>
    <clientCity>
    </clientCity>
    <clientState>
    </clientState>
    <clientZip>
    </clientZip>
    <clientZipext>
    </clientZipext>
    <clientCountry>
    </clientCountry>
    <prinClientCity>
    </prinClientCity>
    <prinClientState>
    </prinClientState>
    <prinClientZip>
    </prinClientZip>
    <prinClientZipext>
    </prinClientZipext>
    <prinClientCountry>
    </prinClientCountry>
    <generalDescription>
    </generalDescription>
    <inactive_lobbyists>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
    </inactive_lobbyists>
    <inactive_ALIs>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
    </inactive_ALIs>
    <affiliatedUrl>
    </affiliatedUrl>
    <affiliatedOrgs>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
    </affiliatedOrgs>
    <inactiveOrgs>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
    </inactiveOrgs>
    <foreignEntities>
      <foreignEntity>
        <name>
        </name>
        <address>
        </address>
        <city>
        </city>
        <state>
        </state>
        <country>
        </country>
        <prinCity>
        </prinCity>
        <prinState>
        </prinState>
        <prinCountry>
        </prinCountry>
        <contribution>
        </contribution>
        <ownership_Percentage>
        </ownership_Percentage>
      </foreignEntity>
    </foreignEntities>
    <inactive_ForeignEntities>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
    </inactive_ForeignEntities>
  </updates>
</LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>