<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='../../ld2webpage.xsl'?>
<LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>
  <imported>Y</imported>
  <pages>7</pages>
  <submitURL>
  </submitURL>
  <organizationName>AMERICA'S HEALTH INSURANCE PLANS, INC. (AHIP)</organizationName>
  <prefix>
  </prefix>
  <firstName>
  </firstName>
  <lastName>
  </lastName>
  <registrantDifferentAddress>N</registrantDifferentAddress>
  <address1>601 PENNSYLVANIA AVENUE, NW, SOUTH BUILDING</address1>
  <address2>
  </address2>
  <city>WASHINGTON</city>
  <state>DC</state>
  <zip>20004</zip>
  <zipext>
  </zipext>
  <country>USA</country>
  <principal_city>
  </principal_city>
  <principal_state>
  </principal_state>
  <principal_zip>
  </principal_zip>
  <principal_zipext>
  </principal_zipext>
  <principal_country>
  </principal_country>
  <contactIntlPhone>
  </contactIntlPhone>
  <selfSelect>Y</selfSelect>
  <clientName>AMERICA'S HEALTH INSURANCE PLANS, INC. (AHIP)</clientName>
  <clientGovtEntity>N</clientGovtEntity>
  <senateID>1581-12</senateID>
  <houseID>306290000</houseID>
  <reportYear>2016</reportYear>
  <reportType>Q1</reportType>
  <terminationDate>
  </terminationDate>
  <noLobbying>
  </noLobbying>
  <income>
  </income>
  <expenses>2210000.00</expenses>
  <expensesMethod>A</expensesMethod>
  <printedName>Aryana Khalid</printedName>
  <signedDate>4/20/2016 4:28:31 PM</signedDate>
  <alis>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>HCR</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>H.R. 6, 21st Century Cures Act (Upton) - new cures and treatments 
H.R. 691, Telehealth Modernization Act (Matsui-Johnson) - telemedicine 
H.R. 1189, Preserving Employee Wellness Programs Act (Kline) - employee wellness programs
H.R. 2646, Helping Families in Mental Health Crisis Act (Murphy) - mental health reforms 
H.R. 2712, Commonsense Reporting and Verification Act (Black) - employer reporting and eligibility verification for ACA subsidies 
H.R. 2745, Standard Merger and Acquisition Reviews Through Equal Rules Act (Farenthold) - FTC-DOJ rules for reviewing mergers 
H.R. 3099, RAISE Family Caregivers Act (Harper) - national strategy to support family caregivers 
H.R. 3463, Aligning Childrens Dental Coverage Act (Griffith-DeGette) - rules for stand-alone dental plans 
H.R. 4771, HEALTH Act (Franks) - medical liability reforms 
S. 185, Promise for Antibiotics and Therapeutics for Health Act (Hatch) - FDA drug approval process 
S. 466, Quality Care for Moms and Babies Act (Stabenow) - pediatric quality measures 
S. 524, Comprehensive Addiction and Recovery Act (Whitehouse) - prescription opioid abuse 
S. 620, Preserving Employee Wellness Programs Act (Alexander) - employee wellness programs 
S. 961, Data Security Act (Carper) - data security 
S. 1077, Advancing Breakthrough Devices for Patients Act (Burr) - priority review of breakthrough medical devices 
S. 1427, Quality Measure Alignment Act (Stabenow) - facilitating coordination and alignment between public and private sectors on quality and efficiency measures
S. 1719, RAISE Family Caregivers Act (Collins) - national strategy to support family caregivers 
S. 1996, Commonsense Reporting Act (Warner) - employer reporting and eligibility verification for ACA subsidies 
S. 2141, TRUST IT Act, (Cassidy) - health IT rating system
S. 2646, Veterans Choice Improvement Act (Burr) - veterans health care 
S. 2680, Mental Health Reform Act (Alexander) - parity requirements, mental health services 

Regulatory Issues:
HIPAA administrative simplification issues, including standards for privacy, security, and electronic transactions and code sets (including ICD-10), identifiers including the health plan identifier, enforcement; cybersecurity; FEHBP enrollment data clearinghouse initiative, the enrollment reconciliation process, and a related OPM reimbursement factor for records that cannot be reconciled; issues relating to health insurance plan participation in FEHBP, including contract requirements; issues relating to similarly sized subscriber group (SSSG) and MLR requirements under the FEHBP;. implementation of the health savings account provisions of the Medicare Act; issues related to Medicare Secondary Payer requirements; issues related to implementation of the National Health Information Infrastructure; electronic health records, personal health records, and similar technologies; issues relating to market consolidation; issues related to hospital consolidation; issues relating to quality improvement; issues related to potential priority research topics for the effective health care program; issues relating to the national health data stewardship; issues relating to hospital outpatient measurement and reporting; prescription drug pricing; issues relating to "meaningful use" requirements for health information technology; issues related to the collection of race and ethnicity data; issues related to medical loss ratios; reference pricing; review of rates for reasonableness; preexisting condition insurance plans; issues relating to antitrust; accountable care organizations; provider non-discrimination; coverage of preventive services; contraceptive coverage; pre-existing condition exclusions; lifetime and annual dollar limits on benefits; patient protections; grandfathered health plan provisions; issues relating to the annual fee on health insurance providers; health plan automatic enrollment requirements; issues related to qualified health plans including certification and rate filing templates; health insurance market rules; reinsurance, risk corridors, and risk adjustment (commonly referred to as the 3 Rs); dependent coverage; summary of benefits and coverage disclosures; benefit and payment parameters for 2014; essential health benefits, actuarial value, and accreditation; issues related to fraud, waste, abuse, Stark/Anti-Kickback laws and regulations; issues related to supplemental products; issues related to HIPAA excepted benefits; issues related to the federally-facilitated marketplaces (i.e., Exchanges/formerly referred to as the web portal); issues related to business continuity in relation to pandemics or natural events (e.g., hurricane, tornado, etc.); issues related to small employer group size; issues related to Certificate of Public Advantage; and other issues relating to health care reform implementation.


</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Executive Office of the President (EOP), Centers For Disease Control &amp; Prevention (CDC), Centers For Medicare and  Medicaid Services  (CMS), Government Accountability Office (GAO), Health &amp; Human Services - Dept of  (HHS), Labor - Dept of (DOL), Treasury - Dept of, Office of Personnel Management (OPM), Agency for Health Care Policy &amp; Research, Internal Revenue Service (IRS), Health Resources &amp; Services Administration (HRSA), Pension &amp; Welfare Benefits Administration, White House Office, Justice - Dept of  (DOJ), Office of Management &amp; Budget (OMB)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jeremy</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Allen</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Liza</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Assatourians</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Carmella</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Bocchino</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kathleen</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Callanan</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Randy</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Desonia</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Paul</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Eiting</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Matthew</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Eyles</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Gregory</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Gierer</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Mark</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Hamelburg</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Erik</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Komendant</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Courtney</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Lawrence</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Amber</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Manko</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Julie</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Miller</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Dana</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Mott-Bronson</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jeanette</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Thornton</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Howard</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Weiss</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Thomas</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Wilder</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jay</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Perron</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Thomas</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Meyers</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Marilyn</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Tavenner</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Aryana</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Khalid</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Gregory</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Berger</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kathryn</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Gallagher</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>MMM</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>H.R. 588, Medicare Beneficiary Preservation of Choice Act (Rothfus-Schrader) - MA enrollment opportunities 
H.R. 818, Preventing and Reducing Improper Medicare and Medicaid Expenditures Act (Roskam-Carney) - reducing fraud 
H.R. 1021, Protecting the Integrity of Medicare Act (Brady) - reducing fraud 
H.R. 2488, Medicare Beneficiary Preservation of Choice Act (Rothfus-Schrader) - MA open enrollment period 
H.R. 2505, Increasing Access to Data in Medicare Advantage Act (Kelly) - annual reporting of MA enrollment data 
H.R. 2506, Preventing Unnecessary Plan Terminations Act (Buchanan) - preventing certain MA plan terminations 
H.R. 2507, Increasing Regulatory Fairness Act (Brady) - schedule for MA rates 
H.R. 2570, Strengthening Medicare Advantage through Innovation and Transparency for Seniors Act (Black) - Value-Based Insurance Design demonstration
H.R. 2579, Securing Care for Seniors Act (Black) - MA risk adjustment model 
H.R. 2581, Preservation of Access for Seniors in Medicare Advantage Act (Brady) - Value-Based Insurance Design demonstration and  MA open enrollment period
H.R. 2582, Seniors Health Care Plan Protection Act (Buchanan) - preventing certain MA plan terminations, MA risk adjustment model 
H.R. 3718, Preventing and Reducing Improper Medicare and Medicaid Expenditures Act (Roskam-Carney) - reducing fraud 
H.R. 3716, Ensuring Access to Quality Medicaid Providers Act (Bucshon) - oversight of terminated Medicaid providers 
H.R. 4275, Medicare Advantage Quality Payment Relief Act (Kelly) - calculation of MA benchmark cap
H.R. 4442, CONNECT for Health Act (Black-Welch) - telehealth, remote patient monitoring services 
H.R. 4589, Excellence in Medicare Act (MacArthur) - MA payment cap 
H.Con.Res. 125, Budget Resolution (Price) - Medicare, Medicaid issues 
S. 524, Comprehensive Addiction and Recovery Act (Whitehouse) - Medicare Part D lock-in programs  
S. 861, Preventing and Reducing Improper Medicare and Medicaid Expenditures Act (Carper-Enzi) - reducing fraud 
S. 1347, Electronic Health Fairness Act - preventing certain MA plan terminations, annual reporting of MA enrollment data 
S. 1396, Value-Based Insurance Design Seniors Copayment Reduction Act (Thune-Stabenow) - VBID demonstration 
S. 1549, Care Planning Act (Warner) - advanced illness care coordination for Medicare beneficiaries 
S. 1913, Stopping Medication Abuse and Protecting Seniors Act (Toomey) - Medicare Part D lock-in programs 
S. 2104, Preserving Medicare Advantage for all Medicare Beneficiaries Act (Portman-Casey) - preventing certain MA plan terminations, MA demonstration program  
S. 2349, Medicare Advantage Coverage Transparency Act (Heller) - MA enrollment data 
S. 2484, CONNECT for Health Act (Schatz-Wicker) - telehealth, remote patient monitoring services


Regulatory Issues:
Ongoing implementation issues for the Medicare Advantage (MA) and Medicare Part D prescription drug programs, including risk adjustment methodology, encounter data and other data-related issues, and audit issues; bidding and payment issues (including MA rate assumptions, MA coding intensity, MA Secondary Payer issues, Part D reinsurance, Part D low income subsidies, and audits); in-home health risk assessments; Medicare Medical Loss Ratio issues; implementation of sequestration under the Medicare Advantage and Part D programs; implications of the health insurer fee for MA and Part D plans; application process, audits to evaluate compliance with MA and Part D program rules, benefit design rules, , enrollment rules, marketing materials review and approval, marketing activities, including conduct and compensation of brokers and agents and plan sponsor marketing staff; measurement and oversight of plan performance including Special Needs Plans (SNPs); quality measures, grievance and appeals processes, fraud and abuse compliance including training; contracting issues for Dual Eligible SNPs; Federal preemption of State authority under MA and Part D programs, Part D prescription drug event data reporting, Part D formulary rules, Part D pharmacy access standards, Part D coverage gap discount program, including employer group waiver plan (EGWP) issues, and other operational issues; issues raised by Part D coverage of new specialty drugs, the Part D non-interference policy and related issues (e.g., preferred pharmacy and any willing pharmacy requirements, standards for network pharmacy reimbursement, and policies regarding sponsor negotiation of pharmacy price concessions); CMS's proposed Part B drug demonstration program; Medication Therapy Management Program requirements and the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation (CMMI) Demonstration; MA EGWP issues; CMMI's value-based insurance design (VBID) demonstration; Part D requirements for offering basic and enhanced alternative plans; MA and Part D systems issues affecting enrollment and disenrollment processing and payment and other operational issues; issues relating to MA and Part D Star Rating system including measures, the methodology for calculating ratings, and the role of the ratings for payment purposes; implementation of the Affordable Care Act (ACA) changes to the Part D coverage gap; functionality of the Medicare Personal Plan Finder and Drug Plan Finder; National Medicare Education Program; Medicare demonstration program on performance-based payments for physician groups; physician quality reporting initiative; issues relating to Medicare coverage policy and national coverage decisions; new payment system for physicians under MACRA, including implications for MA and Part D plans; Medicare clinical trials; Medicare/Medicaid integration for dual eligibles, including the Capitated Financial Alignment Demonstration; Medicaid managed care regulations and policies, including CMS' proposed substantial revisions to the managed care regulations, new mental health parity rules, the Medicaid managed care actuarial soundness standard, quality oversight, Medicaid and CHIP Payment and Access Commission (MACPAC), grievance and appeals processes, fraud and abuse compliance, beneficiary information requirements, treatment of Medicaid health plan member hospital days in the upper payment limit calculation; policies affecting State Medicaid funding, including block grants, the calculation of the federal medical assistance (federal matching) percentage (FMAP), and intergovernmental transfers (IGTs); coordination of benefits with state Medicaid programs; Medicaid prescription drug cost issues affecting Medicaid health plans including issues raised by Medicaid coverage of new specialty drugs; health plan-related Childrens Health Insurance Program (CHIP) issues, including eligibility and outreach issues and CHIP reauthorization; implementation of Medicaid changes made in Deficit Reduction Act of 2005, including Medicaid managed care organization provider tax issues; standards for electronic prescribing; implementation of Medicaid changes of interest to Medicaid health plans made in the ACA including Medicaid expansion, the managed care organization (MCO) prescription drug rebate provisions, minimum payments to primary care providers (PCPs), interactions between the Medicaid program and health insurance exchanges, and Medicaid and CHIP maintenance of effort (MOE) requirements; implications of the health insurer fee for Medicaid health plans; issues related to Medigap coverage; issues related to business continuity in relation to pandemics or natural events (e.g., hurricane, tornado, etc.); cybersecurity; provider directories; value-based insurance design models; Part D prescriber enrollment requirements; Part D recovery audit contractor programs; socioeconomic status impacts on star ratings related to MA and Part D programs; and other issues relating to health care reform implementation. 
</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Centers For Medicare and  Medicaid Services  (CMS), Health &amp; Human Services - Dept of  (HHS), Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (MedPAC), Executive Office of the President (EOP), Office of Personnel Management (OPM), White House Office</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jeremy</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Allen</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Liza</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Assatourians</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Carmella</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Bocchino</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kathleen</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Callanan</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Randy</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Desonia</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Paul</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Eiting</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Matthew</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Eyles</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Mark</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Hamelburg</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Erik</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Komendant</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Courtney</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Lawrence</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Amber</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Manko</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Dana</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Mott-Bronson</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jeanette</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Thornton</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Howard</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Weiss</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jay</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Perron</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Marilyn</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Tavenner</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Aryana</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Khalid</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Gregory</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Berger</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kathryn</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Gallagher</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>INS</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>H.R. 30, Save American Workers Act (Young) - definition of full-time employee 
H.R. 117, Reclaiming Individual Liberty Act (Garrett) - ACA individual mandate 
H.R. 221, ACA Taxpayer Bailout Prevention Act (Harris) - risk corridors program 
H.R. 371, Care for All Act (Fortenberry) - catastrophic plans 
H.R. 494, Competitive Health Insurance Reform Act (Gosar) - antitrust policy 
H.R. 543, Health Care Choice Act (Blackburn) - national marketplace for individual health insurance
H.R. 724, Taxpayer Bailout Protection Act (Lance) - risk corridors program 
H.R. 815, Access to Independent Health Insurance Advisors Act (Long-Schrader) - treatment of broker compensation in MLR calculation 
H.R. 1624, Protecting Affordable Coverage for Employees Act (Guthrie-Cardenas) - ACA definition of small employer 
H.R. 1770, Data Security and Breach Notification Act (Blackburn-Welch) - data security 
H.R. 2205, Data Security Act (Neugebauer) - data security 
H.R. 2739, Cancer Drug Coverage Parity Act (Lance) - coverage of oral anti-cancer drugs 
H.R. 2868, Small Business Health Fairness Act (Johnson) - association health plans 
H.R. 3323, Dental and Optometric Care Access Act (Carter) - dental and vision benefits 
H.R. 3727, Health Insurance Rate Review Act (Schakowsky) - rate review 
H.R. 3762, Restoring Americans' Healthcare Freedom Reconciliation Act (Price) - ACA premium stabilization programs, individual mandate  
H.R. 4299, Patient Opportunity Protection Act (Blum) - HIPAA excepted benefits 
S. 30, Forty Hours Is Full Time Act (Collins) - definition of full-time employee 
S. 123, ACA Taxpayer Bailout Prevention Act (Rubio) - risk corridors program 
S. 158, Employee Health Care Protection Act (Cassidy) - grandfathering of health coverage 
S. 359, Taxpayer Bailout Protection Act (Cassidy) - risk corridors program 
S. 1099, Protecting Affordable Coverage for Employees Act (Scott-Shaheen) - ACA definition of small employer 
S. 1532, Affordability is Access Act (Murray) - coverage of OTC birth control 
S. 1566, Cancer Drug Coverage Parity Act (Kirk) - coverage of oral anti-cancer drugs 
S. 1661, Access to Independent Health Insurance Advisors Act (Isakson-Coons) - treatment of broker compensation in MLR calculation 
S. 2172, Health Insurance Rate Review Act (Feinstein) - rate review 

Regulatory Issues:
Insurance regulatory reform; issues related to the coordination of private and public disability income benefits; disability risk management; disability income insurance enrollment and awareness; issues related to encouraging impaired workers to stay in/return to the workforce; issues relating to the coordination of benefits between private health insurance plans and Medicaid; Medigap claims processing and crossover fees; Medigap cross-over claim issues, Medigap coverage, implementation of Medigap standardized plan offerings; Medigap carrier recoveries related to CMS fraud and abuse enforcement activities, and issues related to Medigap educational materials, and other Medigap issues; fraud and abuse issues affecting public and private insurance coverage; issues relating to antitrust; implementation of the Mental Health Parity Act requirements; summary of benefits and coverage disclosures; pre-existing condition insurance plans; accountable care organizations; coverage of preventive services; preexisting condition exclusions; lifetime and annual dollar limits on benefits; patient protections; grandfathered health plan provisions; dependent coverage; treatment of expatriate plans; compliance with the transitional reinsurance program; issues related to fraud, waste, abuse, Stark/Anti-Kickback laws and regulations, non-discriminatory wellness programs; issues related to supplemental products; issues related to implementation of the Telephone Consumer Protection Act; and other issues relating to health care reform implementation.</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Executive Office of the President (EOP), Health &amp; Human Services - Dept of  (HHS), Labor - Dept of (DOL), Treasury - Dept of, White House Office, Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (MedPAC), Centers For Medicare and  Medicaid Services  (CMS), Internal Revenue Service (IRS), Office of Management &amp; Budget (OMB)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jeremy</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Allen</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Liza</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Assatourians</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Carmella</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Bocchino</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kathleen</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Callanan</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Paul</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Eiting</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Matthew</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Eyles</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Gregory</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Gierer</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Mark</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Hamelburg</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Erik</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Komendant</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Courtney</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Lawrence</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Amber</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Manko</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Julie</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Miller</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Dana</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Mott-Bronson</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jeanette</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Thornton</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Thomas</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Wilder</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jay</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Perron</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Marilyn</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Tavenner</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Aryana</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Khalid</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kathryn</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Gallagher</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Thomas</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Meyers</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>PHA</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>H.R. 9, Innovation Act (Goodlatte) - changes to inter partes review process 
H.R. 1600, Patients' Access to Treatments Act (McKinley-Capps) - specialty drug tiers 
H.R. 4599, Reducing Unused Medications Act (Clark) - partial fillings of prescriptions
H.R. 4784, Lower Drug Costs Through Competition Act (Schrader-Bilirakis) - prescription drug issues
S. 1137, PATENT Act (Grassley) - changes to inter partes review process 
S. 2019, Preserve Access to Affordable Generics Act (Klobuchar-Grassley) - pay-for-delay settlements 
S. 2023, Prescription Drug Affordability Act (Sanders) - pharmaceutical issues 
S. 2578, Reducing Unused Medications Act (Warren) - partial fillings of prescriptions
S. 2615, Increasing Competition in Pharmaceuticals Act (Collins-McCaskill) - prescription drug issues 

Regulatory Issues:
Issues relating to long term safety and effectiveness of medical devices and drugs, including registries; issues relating to post-market surveillance of drugs and medical devices; issues relating to access for investigational drugs; and other issues relating to health care reform implementation.</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Food &amp; Drug Administration (FDA), Health &amp; Human Services - Dept of  (HHS), White House Office, Centers For Medicare and  Medicaid Services  (CMS), Health Resources &amp; Services Administration (HRSA)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jeremy</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Allen</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Liza</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Assatourians</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Carmella</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Bocchino</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kathleen</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Callanan</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Randy</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Desonia</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Paul</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Eiting</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Matthew</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Eyles</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Mark</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Hamelburg</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Erik</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Komendant</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Courtney</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Lawrence</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Amber</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Manko</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Dana</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Mott-Bronson</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Howard</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Weiss</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jay</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Perron</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jeanette</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Thornton</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Marilyn</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Tavenner</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Aryana</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Khalid</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Gregory</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Berger</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kathryn</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Gallagher</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
    <ali_info>
      <issueAreaCode>TAX</issueAreaCode>
      <specific_issues>
        <description>H.R. 879, Ax the Tax on Middle Class Americans Health Plans Act (Guinta) - repeal of ACA excise tax on high cost employer-sponsored coverage 
H.R. 928 (Boustany-Sinema) - full repeal of ACA health insurance tax 
H.R. 1270, Restoring Access to Medication Act (Jenkins) - HSA and FSA issues 
H.R. 2050, Middle Class Health Benefits Tax Repeal Act (Courtney) - repeal of ACA excise tax on high-cost coverage 
H.R. 3762, Restoring Americans' Healthcare Freedom Reconciliation Act (Price) - ACA health insurance tax, excise tax on high-cost coverage, HSA and FSA provisions  
H.R. 4469, Health Savings Act (Paulsen) - HSA and FSA issues
H.R. 4723, Recovering Improper Subsidy Overpayments Act (Jenkins) - full recovery of overpayments of ACA premium tax credits 
S. 183, Jobs and Premium Protection Act (Barrasso) - full repeal of ACA health insurance tax 
S. 254, Small Business Health Relief Act (Portman) - full repeal of ACA health insurance tax, HSA and FSA issues  
S. 709, Restoring Access to Medication Act (Roberts) - HSA and FSA issues 
S. 879, Americans Giving Care to Elders Act (Klobuchar) - tax credits for family caregivers  
S. 2045, Middle Class Health Benefits Tax Repeal Act (Heller-Heinrich) - repeal of ACA excise tax on high-cost coverage
S. 2075, American Worker Health Care Tax Relief Act (Brown) - repeal of ACA excise tax on high-cost coverage 
S. 2432, Obamacare Tax Transparency Act (Scott) - disclosure of premium attributable to health insurance tax 
S. 2499, Health Savings Act (Hatch) - HSA and FSA issues


Regulatory Issues:
Annual insurer provider fees; issues concerning the patient-centered outcomes research fee; employer and individual coverage mandate; W-2 reporting requirements; health reimbursement accounts; deductibility limits for insurer compensation; health insurer and employer reporting of health coverage; issues related to implementation of the excise tax on high cost employer-sponsored health coverage; and other issues relating to health care reform implementation.</description>
      </specific_issues>
      <federal_agencies>U.S. SENATE, U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Internal Revenue Service (IRS), Treasury - Dept of, Labor - Dept of (DOL)</federal_agencies>
      <lobbyists>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jeremy</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Allen</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Carmella</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Bocchino</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kathleen</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Callanan</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Paul</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Eiting</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Matthew</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Eyles</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Gregory</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Gierer</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Erik</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Komendant</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Courtney</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Lawrence</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Amber</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Manko</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jeanette</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Thornton</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Thomas</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Wilder</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Jay</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Perron</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Marilyn</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Tavenner</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Aryana</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Khalid</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
        <lobbyist>
          <lobbyistFirstName>Kathryn</lobbyistFirstName>
          <lobbyistLastName>Gallagher</lobbyistLastName>
          <lobbyistSuffix>
          </lobbyistSuffix>
          <coveredPosition>
          </coveredPosition>
          <lobbyistNew>N</lobbyistNew>
        </lobbyist>
      </lobbyists>
      <foreign_entity_issues>
      </foreign_entity_issues>
    </ali_info>
  </alis>
  <updates>
    <clientAddress>
    </clientAddress>
    <clientCity>
    </clientCity>
    <clientState>
    </clientState>
    <clientZip>
    </clientZip>
    <clientZipext>
    </clientZipext>
    <clientCountry>
    </clientCountry>
    <prinClientCity>
    </prinClientCity>
    <prinClientState>
    </prinClientState>
    <prinClientZip>
    </prinClientZip>
    <prinClientZipext>
    </prinClientZipext>
    <prinClientCountry>
    </prinClientCountry>
    <generalDescription>
    </generalDescription>
    <inactive_lobbyists>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>Tom</firstName>
        <lastName>Wilder</lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
      <inactive_lobbyist>
        <firstName>
        </firstName>
        <lastName>
        </lastName>
        <suffix>
        </suffix>
      </inactive_lobbyist>
    </inactive_lobbyists>
    <inactive_ALIs>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
      <ali_Code>
      </ali_Code>
    </inactive_ALIs>
    <affiliatedUrl>https://www.ahip.org/about-us/board-of-directors/</affiliatedUrl>
    <affiliatedOrgs>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
      <affiliatedOrg>
        <affiliatedOrgName>
        </affiliatedOrgName>
        <affiliatedOrgAddress>
        </affiliatedOrgAddress>
        <affiliatedOrgCity>
        </affiliatedOrgCity>
        <affiliatedOrgState>
        </affiliatedOrgState>
        <affiliatedOrgZip>
        </affiliatedOrgZip>
        <affiliatedOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedOrgCountry>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCity>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgState>
        <affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
        </affiliatedPrinOrgCountry>
      </affiliatedOrg>
    </affiliatedOrgs>
    <inactiveOrgs>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
      <inactiveOrgName>
      </inactiveOrgName>
    </inactiveOrgs>
    <foreignEntities>
      <foreignEntity>
        <name>
        </name>
        <address>
        </address>
        <city>
        </city>
        <state>
        </state>
        <country>
        </country>
        <prinCity>
        </prinCity>
        <prinState>
        </prinState>
        <prinCountry>
        </prinCountry>
        <contribution>
        </contribution>
        <ownership_Percentage>
        </ownership_Percentage>
      </foreignEntity>
    </foreignEntities>
    <inactive_ForeignEntities>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
      <inactive_ForeignEntity>
      </inactive_ForeignEntity>
    </inactive_ForeignEntities>
  </updates>
</LOBBYINGDISCLOSURE2>